<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><recipes><recipe><name>Eye of Newt and Toe Of Frog</name><contributor>Jason Parent</contributor><category>Spell or Enchantment</category><description>This recipe is somewhat of an acquired taste but is a traditional favourite amongst some demographics
in certain areas of Scotland. While some may find the concoction to be rather foul, others may find it
to be rather fair; it's all in how you suggest it's value to yourself.</description><spices>Wool of Bat</spices><source>Scottish Recipe</source><rating>Foul, yet Fair</rating><ingredients>1 fillet of fenny snake
2 eyes of newt
1 foot of frog
1/2 ball of wool of bat
1 tongue of dog
2 forks of adder
7 stings of blind worm
4 legs of lizard
1 wing of howlet
1 gallon of swamp water</ingredients><directions>Bring a large cauldron of swamp water to a full boil. Slowly add ingredients while cackling incessantly and
stirring with a large wooden stick. Loudly state the name of each ingredient in pig latin
before dropping it into the cauldron. Once all ingredients have been added, let cauldron sit for 30 minutes.
Do the hokey-pokey, turn yourself around and then enjoy! One gallon of swamp water feeds four adults.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Stuffed Mushrooms</name><contributor>Iva Nedeleva</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Fast and delicious recipe. Main course or addition to steak. I myself came up with it and since then my family and friends loved it!</description><spices>Salt, Savory, Thyme, Marjoram, Vegeta</spices><source>Own recipes</source><rating>Delicious</rating><ingredients>1/2 kg white mushrooms
1/2 cup rice
1 pack of bacon
1/4 pack of butter
3 carrots
1/2 kg cheese
3 cups whater
spices
1 teaspoon salt
1 potato</ingredients><directions>Wash the mushrooms and the carrots. Separate the stemps of the mushrooms and cut them into small pieces. Cut the carrots and the potato on small cubes. Mix them with chopped bacon, rice, salt and spices. Put the butter in a pan and fry the mixture for 5 minutes. Arrange the rest of the mushrooms in a baking dish and stuff them with the mixture you just fried. Pour the water and add the cheese on top. Bake for 25 - 30 minutes in oven on 250 degrees.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Blended Japanese Curry and Rice</name><contributor>Michael Yagi</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This has been my favorite dish since my childhood. This is a modified version of a typical way of making Japanese curry.
The curry sauce is mostly sold in the form of packaged roux blocks. Brands such as Glico, House and S&amp;B are popular
and can be easily found in Asian food markets. This recipe uses a large sized package which are usually about 220g.
It is very easy to make.</description><spices>Japanese curry</spices><source>Japanese</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>Big box (220g) of Japanese curry sauce
3 carrots, chopped
2 medium sized onions, chopped
2 stalks of celery, finely chopped
4 cloves of garlic, minced
2 tablespoons of powdered soup stock
2 chicken breasts, diced
4 cups water</ingredients><directions>In a large pot, combine carrots, onions, celery and garlic; cook with a bit of oil for 10 to 15 minutes on medium heat
until vegetables are half tender. Add water and soup stock and bring to a boil; reduce heat to medium and cook for an
addition 10 minutes until completely tender. While letting it simmer until it is warm, cook diced chicken in a seperate
pan with oil. Split half of the vegetables and water from the pot into a blender to blend into a soup. Put blended
vegetables back into pot along with the remaining vegetables; add cooked chicken. Put on low heat; add curry blocks
and mix until it dissolves. Serve with cooked rice. Makes 10 servings.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Jan's Spaghetti and Meatballs</name><contributor>Thomas Goldsmith</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a recipe for a delicious version of spaghetti and meatballs. It is
relatively simple to make, and well worth it!</description><spices>None.</spices><source>Family.</source><rating>Not spicy.</rating><ingredients>500 grams ground beef
1 chopped onion
1 egg
1/4 cup bread crumbs
Montreal steak spice to taste (about 1 teaspoon)
1 tsp cooking oil
2 cans spaghetti sauce (or 1 can spaghetti and 1 can tomato sauce)
1 can chopped tomatoes
1/2 cup red wine
1 chopped onion
2 chopped celery stalks
2 minced garlic cloves
1 Tblsp. cooking oil</ingredients><directions>Mix beef, onion, egg, bread crumbs and steak spice.  Form into small balls and
cook in oil in frying pan on medium-low heat until brown. Saut? onion, celery
and garlic in cooking oil in large saucepan.  Add sauce, tomatoes, wine and
meatballs.  Let simmer on low heat for an hour. Serve over spaghetti pasta.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Indian Butter Chicken</name><contributor>Murray Christopherson</contributor><category>Main Course</category><description>null</description><spices>Dried red chili</spices><source>India/UK Recipe</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>* 1 tablespoon peanut oil
* 1 shallot, finely chopped
* 1/4 white onion, chopped
* 2 tablespoons butter
* 2 teaspoons lemon juice
* 1 tablespoon ginger garlic paste
* 1 teaspoon garam masala
* 1 teaspoon chili powder
* 1 teaspoon ground cumin
* 1 bay leaf
* 1/4 cup plain yogurt
* 1 cup half-and-half
* 1 cup tomato puree
* 1/4 teaspoon cayenne pepper, or to taste
* 1 pinch salt
* 1 pinch black pepper
*
* 1 tablespoon peanut oil
* 1 pound boneless, skinless chicken thighs, cut into bite-size         	pieces
* 1 teaspoon garam masala
* 1 pinch cayenne pepper
* 1 tablespoon cornstarch
* 1/4 cup water</ingredients><directions>1.   Heat 1 tablespoon oil in a large saucepan over medium high heat. Saute shallot and onion until soft and translucent. Stir in butter, lemon juice, ginger-garlic paste, 1 teaspoon garam masala, chili powder, cumin and bay leaf. Cook, stirring, for 1 minute. Add tomato sauce, and cook for 2 minutes, stirring frequently. Stir in half-and-half and yogurt. Reduce heat to low, and simmer for 10 minutes, stirring frequently. Season with salt pepper. Remove from heat and set aside.
2. Heat 1 tablespoon oil in a large heavy skillet over medium heat. Cook chicken until lightly browned, about 10 minutes. Reduce heat, and season with 1 teaspoon garam masala and cayenne. Stir in a few spoonfuls of sauce, and simmer until liquid has reduced, and chicken is no longer pink. Stir cooked chicken into sauce.
3. Mix together cornstarch and water, then stir into the sauce. Cook for 5 to 10 minutes, or until thickened.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Salsa Chicken</name><contributor>Devon Johnston</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a modern North American meal. I came upon it at my girlfriends house and have made it my own</description><spices>none</spices><source>Homemade Recipe</source><rating>Hot</rating><ingredients>2 Thinly cut Chicken Breasts
1 cup of Louisiana Style Hot Sauce
512ml Bottle of Mild Salsa
Shredded Cheese
1 Green Pepper
1 Onion
Noodles of any kind (Penne recommended)</ingredients><directions>Boil water and cook the noodles to concistency your looking for. Cook the chicken in a pan with cooking oil until the
chicken is no longer pink. While this is cooking chop the green pepper and onion into sizes of your desire. Once the
chicken is no longer pink put in the vegetables and throw in the cup of hot sauce and the bottle of salsa. Let this
cook for approx 4-5 min or until the veggies are no longer crunchy.  Now it is ready to serve, serve the pasta then
put as much of the chicken mixture on the pasta as is desired and then take some of the shredded cheese and add it on
top of the pasta! Bon Appetite!!!</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Chocolate Honey Cake</name><contributor>Robert Wolfe</contributor><category>Dessert</category><description>This is a delicious dessert to serve your family. It is my Grandma's
special recipe. It is already sweet because of the honey, but the chocolate
makes it all the tastier.</description><spices>Cinnamon</spices><source>Grandma</source><rating>Mild? Sweet?</rating><ingredients>2 eggs
1 tsp. baking powder
3/4 cup honey-liquid
cinnamon
1 cup sugar
4 tsp. cocoa (heaping)
1/2 cup oil
1 cup coffee (cool)
1 tsp. soda
2 cups flour</ingredients><directions>Stir ingredients well in big bowl.
Bake 325 oven 1 hour approx.
Add raisins + nuts (optional).
Line pan with wax paper.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Crepes</name><contributor>Julia Schulze</contributor><category>Desert</category><description>This is a a special french recipe that tastes delicious.</description><spices>red chilies</spices><source>my french mother</source><rating>mild</rating><ingredients>1 cup all-purpose flour
2 eggs
1 cup milk
1/4 teaspoon salt
2 teaspoons vegetable oil
4 red chilies
2 cups of fluid chocolate</ingredients><directions>Put all ingredients together and mix them well until they form a fluid dough
Then heat a lightly oiled griddle or frying pan over medium high heat
Pour or scoop the batter onto the griddle, using approximately 1/4 cup for each crepe
Tilt the pan with a circular motion so that the batter coats the surface evenly
Cook the crepe for about 2 minutes, until the bottom is light brown. Loosen with a spatula, turn and cook the other side
At the end put the chocolate and the red chilies on the crepe
Serve hot.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Baked Chicken Paprika</name><contributor>Trevor Burn</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a simple recipe for baked chicken with a simple paprika flavouring and a sour cream sauce.</description><spices>Paprika</spices><source>CDKithen.com</source><rating>I enjoyed it</rating><ingredients>5 pounds chicken pieces
3 tablespoons butter
3 tablespoons oil
1 1/2 cup finely chopped onion
1 teaspoon sweet Hungarian paprika
4 teaspoons chicken bouillon granules
Water -- Enough To Cover
2 tablespoons Flour
2 cups Sour Cream</ingredients><directions>Add butter, oil, onion, paprika, bouillon and water to a Dutch Oven, heat
to boiling. Add chicken. Simmer covered until tender. Remove chicken, then bone
and skin the chicken pieces. Add flour to sour cream. Add mixture to chicken.
Heat until sour cream is just hot, do not boil. Serves four.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Baked Chicken Paprika</name><contributor>Trevor Burn</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a simple recipe for baked chicken with a simple paprika flavouring and a sour cream sauce.</description><spices>Paprika</spices><source>CDKithen.com</source><rating>I enjoyed it</rating><ingredients>5 pounds chicken pieces
3 tablespoons butter
3 tablespoons oil
1 1/2 cup finely chopped onion
1 teaspoon sweet Hungarian paprika
4 teaspoons chicken bouillon granules
Water -- Enough To Cover
2 tablespoons Flour
2 cups Sour Cream</ingredients><directions>Add butter, oil, onion, paprika, bouillon and water to a Dutch Oven, heat
to boiling. Add chicken. Simmer covered until tender. Remove chicken, then bone
and skin the chicken pieces. Add flour to sour cream. Add mixture to chicken.
Heat until sour cream is just hot, do not boil. Serves four.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Spicy Mexican Rice</name><contributor>Adam</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This will make a spicy, stew-like dish. Rice mixed with tomato, onion, corn, peppers, and spice.</description><spices>Oregano, Cayenne Pepper, Chili Powder</spices><source>Family Recipe</source><rating>Spicy - moderate</rating><ingredients>3 cups parboiled rice
6 cups water (see step 2 below)
1 large can diced tomatoes (see step 2 below)
1 tsp salt
1 tsp oregano
1 tsp chili powder
1/2 tsp cayenne pepper (adjust acording to your taste)
1 can corn, drained
1/4 cup diced onion
1/2 of a green pepper, diced
3 green onion stalks chopped</ingredients><directions>1.  Saute onion and green pepper, until tender.
2.  Drain the juice from the canned tomatoes into a measuring cup.  Add enough water to the juice to make a total
of 6 cups of liquid.
3.  Place liquid, onions and green peppers and all other ingredients, including the rice, into a pot.
4.  Cover and bring to a boil.  After the water boils, turn the burner down to the lowest setting, and let simmer until
all water has been absorbed.  Takes 25 to 30 minutes.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Chocolate-Mocha Parfait</name><contributor>Kyle Lunau</contributor><category>Dessert</category><description>This is a delicious dessert recipe. Set aside several parfait or 	regular glasses before beginning.</description><spices>None</spices><source>Unknown</source><rating>Cool</rating><ingredients>1 cup of strong hot coffee
1/2 pkg of chocolate wafers
1/2 pkg. marshmallows
1 cup whipping cream</ingredients><directions>Dissolve marshmallows in hot coffee. Let the mixture cool until syrupy. Whip whipping cream and blend into coffee mixture. Layer mixture into parfait glasses, alternating with crushed chocolate cookie crumbs. Chill, then serve.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Green Thai Curry</name><contributor>Leah Pearson</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>A rich and spicy Thai green curry with shrimp, cubed tofu and a selection of vegetables including green beans, broccoli and green pepper served with fragrant Jasmine rice.</description><spices/><source>Meditarrasian.com</source><rating>Spicy</rating><ingredients>2 tablespoons canola or peanut oil
1 onion ? finely chopped
1 kaffir lime leaf ? finely chopped (or ? teaspoon lime zest)
2 teaspoons Thai green curry paste (or 3 teaspoons for a hotter curry)
2 cloves garlic ? finely chopped
1 cup coconut milk
1 cup fish, chicken or vegetable stock
2 tablespoons fish sauce
1 tablespoon brown sugar
? teaspoon salt
1 cup small broccoli florets
? green pepper (capsicum) ? julienned
1 cup green beans ? ends trimmed and cut in half
3? oz (100g) firm tofu ? cubed
1 cup Jasmine rice
12 large uncooked shrimp (prawns) ? peeled, deveined and bottom of tail left intact
2 tablespoons cornstarch (corn flour) mixed to a paste with 2 tablespoons water
2 tablespoons lime juice
2 tablespoons finely chopped fresh cilantro</ingredients><directions>Heat the oil in a large saucepan over a medium heat and cook the onion for 5 minutes, stirring occasionally. Add the chopped kaffir lime leaf (or lime zest), curry paste and garlic and cook, stirring, for a minute. Add the coconut milk, stock, fish sauce, sugar and salt, and then bring to a boil. Add the broccoli, green pepper, green beans and tofu, cover with a lid, then reduce the heat to medium and simmer for 12 minutes. While the curry simmers, cook the rice. Add the shrimp and cabbage to the curry and simmer, covered, for a further 5 minutes. Add the cornstarch paste and stir continuously until the curry thickens, then stir in the lime juice and cilantro.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Tomato Soup Cake</name><contributor>Robert Wilson</contributor><category>Dessert</category><description>Grandma Wilson kept the name of this affordable treat
a secret until we asked for seconds. She lived through the Great Depression, and
so she had all kinds of tasty budget recipes. I was unable to find
her original but I am sure she would have approved of this one.
It comes from a book by MFK Fisher entitled "How to Cook a Wolf".</description><spices>Cinnamon, Nutmeg, Cloves</spices><source>adapted from MFK Fisher - "How to Cook a Wolf"</source><rating>Comfort Food</rating><ingredients>3 tablespoons butter or shortening
1 cup sugar
1 teaspoon baking soda
1 can tomato soup ( about 15 ounces?)
2 cups flour
1 teaspoon cinnamon
1 teaspoon nutmeg, ginger, cloves mixed
1 1/2 cup raisins, nuts, chopped figs, what you will</ingredients><directions>Cream butter, add the sugar, and blend thoroughly, Add the baking
soda to the soup, stirring well, and add this alternately to the
first mixture with the flour and spices sifted together. Stir well,
and bake in a pan or loaf tin at 325 (F). (RJPW - optional - Once cooked,
brush with melted butter and dust with sugar and allow to cool. Leave the
main ingredient as a mystery until people ask.)</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Linzer Torte</name><contributor>Addison Dunbrook</contributor><category>Dessert</category><description>This is a family favorite, usually served around christmas time, its also the oldest known cake in the world.</description><spices>cinnamon</spices><source>Austrian/German recipe</source><rating>heavy and sweet</rating><ingredients>1/2cup whole almonds, toasted
1-1/2cups all-purpose flour
1teaspoon ground cinnamon
1/4teaspoon salt
3/4cup granulated sugar
1/2cup butter, softened
1/2teaspoon grated lemon peel
1egg
3/4cup raspberry or apricot jam
Sifted powdered sugar</ingredients><directions>1.Process almonds in food processor until ground, but not pasty. Preheat oven to 375?F. Combine flour, almonds, cinnamon and salt in medium bowl; set aside. Beat granulated sugar, butter and lemon peel in large bowl with electric mixer at medium speed about 5 minutes or until light and fluffy, scraping down side of bowl once. Beat in egg until well blended. Beat in flour mixture at low speed until well blended.

2.Spoon 2/3 of dough onto bottom of 10-inch tart pan with removable bottom. Pat dough evenly over bottom and up side of pan. Spread jam over bottom of dough. Roll remaining 1/3 of dough on lightly floured surface into 10X5-inch rectangle. Cut dough into ten 1/2-inch-wide strips using pizza wheel or sharp knife.

3.Arrange 4 or 5 strips of dough lengthwise across jam. Arrange another 4 or 5 strips of dough crosswise across top. Trim and press ends of dough strips into edge of crust. Bake 25 to 35 minutes or until crust is golden brown. Cool completely in pan on wire rack. Remove torte from pan. Sprinkle with powdered sugar. Cut into wedges. Store, tightly covered, at room temperature 1 to 2 days.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Chocolate Crinkles</name><contributor>Paul Haussler</contributor><category>Dessert</category><description>These tantalizingly decadent cookies are a chocolate lover's fantasy. Eat them quickly,
as these delicious treats won't last long in any house.</description><spices>None</spices><source>School Cookbook</source><rating>Null</rating><ingredients>1/2 cup vegetable oil
4 squares unsweetened chocolate (4 oz.) melted
2 cups granulated sugar
4 eggs
2 tsp. vanilla
2 cups all-purpose flour
2 tsp. baking powder
1/2 tsp. salt
1 cup confectioners sugar</ingredients><directions>Mix oil, chocolate and granulated sugar. Blend in one egg at a time until well mixed.
Add vanilla. Stir flour, baking powder and salt into oil mixture. Chill several hours or overnight.
Heat oven tp 350 F. Drop tsp. of dough into confectioners sugar. Roll in sugar, and shape into balls.
Place about 2" apart on greased baking sheet. Bake 10-12 minutes. Do not overbake.
Makes 6 dozen.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Nonna's Potatoes</name><contributor>Nicholas Young</contributor><category>Side Dish</category><description>This simple, but delicious recipe is something my Italian grandmother created when I was a kid. To this day, it is still one of my favourite things to eat.</description><spices>Montreal Steak Spice/The Keg Steak Spice</spices><source>Homemade/Italian</source><rating>Small kick</rating><ingredients>2 cups of potatoes, 4 cups of water, table spoon of salt, a few tablespoons of oil, healthy serving of Montreal/The Keg steak spice</ingredients><directions>First, bring 4 cups of water to a boil in a pot. While the pot is boiling, pre-heat the oven to 375F. Once the water is finished boiling, throw in the salt and potatoes. Reduce heat. After simmering          potatoes for about 15-20 minutes, remove from heat and strain the water. Next, place the potatoes on a well oiled cooking sheet. Load the potatoes (and I mean LOAD) them with your steak spice of              choice. Place the spiced potatoes into the oven and let them roast until golden brown. For the best results, reduce the heat of the oven and let them cook for an hour or two. This will get them nice          and crispy on the outside but soft on the inside. DELICIOUS!</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Nonna's Potatoes</name><contributor>Nicholas Young</contributor><category>Side Dish</category><description>This simple, but delicious recipe is something my Italian grandmother created when I was a kid. To this day, it is still one of my favourite things to eat.</description><spices>Montreal Steak Spice/The Keg Steak Spice</spices><source>Homemade/Italian</source><rating>Small kick</rating><ingredients>2 cups of potatoes, 4 cups of water, table spoon of salt, a few tablespoons of oil, healthy serving of Montreal/The Keg steak spice</ingredients><directions>First, bring 4 cups of water to a boil in a pot. While the pot is boiling, pre-heat the oven to 375F. Once the water is finished boiling, throw in the salt and potatoes. Reduce heat. After simmering          potatoes for about 15-20 minutes, remove from heat and strain the water. Next, place the potatoes on a well oiled cooking sheet. Load the potatoes (and I mean LOAD) them with your steak spice of              choice. Place the spiced potatoes into the oven and let them roast until golden brown. For the best results, reduce the heat of the oven and let them cook for an hour or two. This will get them nice          and crispy on the outside but soft on the inside. DELICIOUS!</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Corn Latkes</name><contributor>Dina Tsirlin</contributor><category>Snack</category><description>null</description><spices>Salt</spices><source>null</source><rating>Bland\par</rating><ingredients>225 gr corn
2 eggs
2 spoons flour
2 spoons milk
salt
canola oil</ingredients><directions>Put in a bowl the eggs, flour and milk and mix with a fork. Add canola oil to frying pan and heat.
Put small chuncks of mixture on the frying pan and fry until golden from both sides.
Make 2 servings.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Pickled Chanterelle Mushroom Salad</name><contributor>Drew Martin</contributor><category>Appetizer</category><description>This is a delicious salad I've made at a restaurant I worked at. Though the duck prosciutto
and marinated mushrooms must be started long in advance, they can be made and eaten on their
own.</description><spices>Mustard seed
Dill seed
Black peppercorn</spices><source>Inn On The Twenty</source><rating>Not spicy</rating><ingredients>500ml cleaned chanterelle mushrooms
1 small white onion
200ml water
100ml white vinegar
200ml white sugar
3 cloves of garlic
3 bay leaves
1tsp mustard seed
1tsp dill seed
1tsp whole black peppercorns

2 Boneless duck breasts
500ml kosher or sea salt
150ml raw sugar
Cheesecloth

100ml Baco Noir balsamic vinegar
300ml soybean oil
1tsp grainy mustard
1tsp thyme

Mache lettuce
Oka or Niagara Gold cheese</ingredients><directions>Pickled Chanterelle mushrooms:
Cut or pull apart any large mushrooms. Heat a large sauce pan on medium-high heat and cook the
mushrooms, stirring frequently, for 5-10 minutes, until the liquid they have released is dried.
Combine the onion, water, vinegar, white sugar, garlic, bay leaves, mustard seed, dill seed and
peppercorns in a pot and bring to a boil. Pour the mixture over top of the mushrooms.
Boil a large mason jar, with its lid, for a few minutes to sterilize it, then pour the mushrooms
and pickling liquid in, and seal. Refrigerate them for at least two weeks.

Duck Prosciutto:
Mix the sea salt and raw sugar together. Place about an inch of salt on the bottom of a plastic
container, and then lay the breasts side by side on top, leaving some room between them. Pour the
rest of the salt and sugar mixture over top, making sure there is some around the edges of the
breasts. Refrigerate them for a day.
Rinse them off and dry them, and then wrap them individually in two or three layers of cheesecloth,
tie it securely and hang them in a cool, dry place. A walk in fridge is ideal, but a cool cellar
will work. Leave them to dry for 10-20 days.  Remove them from the cheesecloth and carve off any
grayness or overly dried areas.

Dressing:
Combine balsamic vinegar and grainy mustard and thyme. Whisk vigorously while slowly pouring in the
soybean oil. This can be done in a food processor. Ideally it should take a few minutes to pour in
all the oil. If done correctly, the dressing will not split. Season as needed.

Combine a quantity of mache lettuce with a quarter as much of pickled chanterelle mushrooms. Toss
with the balsamic dressing, and serve with thinly sliced pieces of duck prosciutto and cheese.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Jollof Rice</name><contributor>Elom</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional Ghanaian recipe. It is usually spicy and served with chicken or fried plantain and salad</description><spices>Chilli
Oregana</spices><source>Ghanaian recipe</source><rating>MILD</rating><ingredients>2 ripe tomatoes
half a packet of rice
1 onion, chopped
1 garlic cloves, finely chopped
3 hot peppers (or powdered chilli)
3 teaspoons vegetable oil
1 can chicken broth
5 chicken drumsticks
1 tablespoon salt
1/2 teaspoon grated lemon peel
1 glass water</ingredients><directions>In a medium saucepan, heat up the teaspoons of oil and fry onions till goldreb brown. Pour blended tomatoes into pan and let it simmer for 20 mins. Add chopped garlic, pepper, spices and can of broth. Allow to simmer for extra 5 mins. Pour packet of rice till theres enough sauce just to cook it. Boil under low heat for extra 20 mins. Serve for four with grilled or fried chicken.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Crazy Spice Cake</name><contributor>Chaman Chahal</contributor><category>Dessert</category><description>This is a simple yet flavourful cake my family makes for birthdays. For those who like it hot, the original recipe actually calls for twice the amount of the spices listed here.</description><spices>cinnamon
ginger
nutmeg
cloves</spices><source>a Friend of a Friend</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>1 1/2 cup flour
1/2 cup wh. sugar
1/2 cup br sugar
1/2 tsp. cinnamon
1/4 tsp. ginger
1/4 tsp. nutmeg
1/8 tsp. cloves
1 tsp. baking soda
1/2 tsp. salt
5 Tbsp. vegetable oil
1 Tbsp. vinegar
1 tsp. vanilla
1 cup cold water</ingredients><directions>Sift together flour, sugars, spices, soda &amp; salt. make 3 holes in the mixture, fill one with vanilla, one with vinegar, and one with oil. Pour water over all; stir gently until just mixed. Pour into a greased 8-inch baking pan. Bake in a preheated 350 degree oven for 25 to 30 minutes, or until it tests done with a toothpick. Frost or serve with whipped topping.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Tarator Soup</name><contributor>Anna Galerkin</contributor><category>Soup</category><description>This is a traditional bulgarian cucumber soup. I found the recipe on-line and changed slightely to my taste.
It's cold, sharp, tart and refreshing. It's easy and fast to make and very low calorie.</description><spices>Garlic
Salt</spices><source>Internet</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>2 cucumbers, peeled and chopped
1 garlic clove, minced
4 cups plain yoghurt
1/2 cup water
1/4 teaspoon salt
2 Tablespoons dill, chopped
toasted almond slices</ingredients><directions>In a saucepan, combine yoghurt, water, cucumbers, garlic, dill, salt and mix well. Refrigerate at least 2 hours.
When ready to serve, ladle into bowls and sprinkle with toasted almonds.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>HASH BROWN POTATO CASSEROLE</name><contributor>Matthew Steckly</contributor><category>Side Dish</category><description>A Simple Hash Brown Casserole thats quick and easy to make, cream of mushroom soup
can be used instead of cream of chicken</description><spices>Salt
Pepper</spices><source>Savour Perth's Flavours Cook Book</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>2 lb. bag of hashbrowns thawed
1 onion, chopped
2 cups grated cheese
1 small carton sour cream
1 can (10 oz.) cream of chicken soup
salt and pepper to taste
1 cup Corn Flake Crumbs
1/3 cup butter, melted</ingredients><directions>Mix together all of the ingredients except the corn flakes and butter.
Put in a 9"x13" pan. Mix together Corn Flakes and butter.
Spread on top of potato mixture.
Bake at 350 degrees F. for 1 hour.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Pho Bo</name><contributor>Kyle Tanaka</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Popular Vietnamese noodle based soup which has become extremely popular throughout North America due to its low cost and taste.</description><spices>Cinnamon
Star Anise</spices><source>Vietnamese recipe</source><rating>Normal</rating><ingredients>2 cups grated fresh or packaged unsweetened coconut
4 cups beef broth (1 box per cup)
1 (1/4-inch thick) slice ginger
4 whole star anise
1 cinnamon stick
1/2 pound piece boneless beef sirloin, trimmed of any fat
3 ounces dried flat rice noodles*
1/4 cup Asian fish sauce*
1/8 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper
1 cup fresh bean sprouts, rinsed and drained
1/8 cup minced scallions
1/4 cup fresh cilantro sprigs, washed and finely chopped
1 small thin fresh red or green Asian chilie, sliced very thin
1/2 cup fresh basil leaves
Lime wedges for garnish</ingredients><directions>In a 2 quart saucepan bring broth, ginger, star anise, and cinnamon to a boil. Reduce heat and simmer for 15 minutes.
With a very sharp knife cut sirloin across the grain into very thin slices.
In a large bowl soak noodles in hot water to cover 15 minutes, or until softened and pliable.
While noodles are soaking, bring a kettle of salted water to a boil for noodles. Drain noodles in a colander and cook in boiling water, stirring 45 seconds, or until tender. Drain noodles in a colander. Set aside.
Strain broth into saucepan and bring to a boil. Stir in fish sauce, salt and pepper. Add sirloin and sprouts and cook 30 to 45 seconds, or until sirloin changes color. Skim any froth from soup.
To serve, divide noodles into 4 bowls. Ladle soup over noodles. Sprinkle scallion greens, cilantro, chilies and basil over soup and serve with lime wedges</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Kommstborscht (Summer Borscht)</name><contributor>Kaylene FUnk</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional German soup. It is very hardy and tasts great with a little sour cream add before you eat.</description><spices>Bay Leaf
Parsely</spices><source>Family recipe</source><rating>MILD</rating><ingredients>2-3 lbs. ham bone
4 qt. water
1 bay leaf and parsley or beet leaves(chopped finely)
1 stalk rhubarb (optional)
3-4 medium potatoes, diced
small red pepper (optional)</ingredients><directions>Simmer ham bones, water and onion for 2 hours or until the ham falls off the bone.
Add remaining ingredients and let simmer for at least 2 hours.
Add salt and pepper to taste. Serve with sour cream, if desired.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Cherry Cheese Cake</name><contributor>Julie Powers</contributor><category>Dessert</category><description>This is my favourite recipe for cheesecake.
It comes from my grandmother and has been popular among friends and family.</description><spices>None</spices><source/><rating>null</rating><ingredients>Bottom layer:
2 cups of graham cracker crumbs,
1/2 cup of butter
1/2 cup of brown sugar
Filling:
1 package of Philly Cream Cheese
1 cup of icing sugar
1 package of Dream Whip
Topping:
1 can of cherry filling</ingredients><directions>Mix together the ingredients for the bottom layer and put in 10 by 12 inch panand chill for approx. 15 minutes
Filling - Beat Philly cream cheese with icing sugar.
Mix 1 package of Dream Whip and fold into cheese mixture.
Spread filling over cracker crumbs.
Topping - Spread one can of cherry filling over cheese mixture and chill in fridge for 24 hours.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Chocolate Muffins</name><contributor>Daoud, Rani</contributor><category>Desert</category><description>This is great desert for chocolate lovers and people who are avoiding spicy deserts.
This particular recipe will make a dozen muffins.</description><spices>Cayenne pepper</spices><source>A pamphlet handed out in a supermarket a long time ago.</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>-2 eggs -1 cup or 250 mL milk -2 cups or 500 mL all-purpose flour -1 1/2 cup or 350 mL chocolate chips -1/2 cup or 125 mL cocoa powder -1/2 cup or 125 mL sugar -1/8 tsp of salt -1/8 tsp of cayenne pepper -1 tbsp or 15 mL baking powder -1/4 cup or 50 mL vegetable oil</ingredients><directions>Preheat oven to 375F or 190C. In a small bowl, whisk together the flour, chocolate powder, sugar, baking powder, chocolate chips and salt. In a seperate large bowl, whisk the eggs, milk, oil and cayenne pepper. Slowly add the dry ingredients from the small bowl into the wet ingredients in the large bowl while whisking. Keep whisking thoroughly until all the ingredients are completely blended. Lightly grease the muffin pan and sprinkle it with cocoa. Using an ice cream scoop, place a ball of the mixture into every slot in the pan. Slide the pan into the oven and let the muffins bake for 20 minutes or until an inserted toothpick comes out clean with a few crumbs. Let the muffins cool for at least 10 minutes before serving.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Kimchi Pancakes</name><contributor>Jimin Park</contributor><category>Side dish</category><description>Kimchi is a traditional spicy Korean salad made of cabbage.
Kimchi can be bought from any local Korean market.</description><spices>Garlic
Green onion</spices><source>Korean family recipe</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>1 cup flour
1/2 cup water
1/2 teaspoon salt
1 cup cabbage kimchi, minced
2 tablespoons green onions, minced
1 teaspoon garlic clove, minced
2 teaspoons sesame oil</ingredients><directions>Mix flour, water and salt together and combine with the rest of the ingredients to create a thick "pancake" batter.
Heat 2 Tablespoons oil. Place 1/4 of the batter in the pan to form a pancake. Fry until both sides are golden. Reduce heat to low and cook all the way through.
Repeat with remaining portions.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Barbecued Short Ribs</name><contributor>Adebimpe Adegbembo</contributor><category>Food</category><description>This recipe for short ribs is very popular in our area. The meat is fork-tender, and the sauce is wonderfully tangy. We're retired now but raised beef for many years. We still put this recipe to good use.
Prep Time:1hr 15min
Cook Time:1hr 15min
Ready in:2hrs 30min</description><spices>pepper</spices><source>www.allrecipes.com</source><rating>Hard</rating><ingredients>3 1/2 pounds beef short ribs
1 1/2 cups water
1 medium onion, sliced
1 tablespoon vinegar
SAUCE:
1/2 cup ketchup
1/4 cup chopped onion
2 tablespoons lemon juice
2 garlic cloves, minced
1 teaspoon sugar
1/2 teaspoon salt
1/8 teaspoon pepper</ingredients><directions>1.  In a Dutch oven, combine ribs, water, onion and vinegar; bring to a boil. Reduce hat; cover and simmer for 1 hour, turning ribs occasionally. Drain. Place ribs in a single layer in an ungreased 13-in. x 9-in. x 2-in. baking dish. Combine sauce ingredients; spoon over ribs. Cover and bake at 325 degrees F for 1-1/4 hours or until meat is tender.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Fried Wonton</name><contributor>Angela</contributor><category>Appetizer</category><description>It is a type of dumpling commonly found in a number of Chinese cuisines. Wonton is made with a thin ten     centimeter square lye-water pastry wrapper made of wheat flour, water, salt and lye. It is often filled with minced        meat, but vegetarian fillings can be substituted.</description><spices>dark soy sauce</spices><source>Chinese cuisines</source><rating>Wonderful and authentic tasting!</rating><ingredients>4 dried black mushrooms, 1 leaf bok choy, 1 green onion, 1/2 pound ground pork, 1 tablespoon dark soy sauce, 1 teaspoon sesame oil, 1 teaspoon granulated sugar, pinch of salt, 1 egg, lightly beaten, 3 cups oil for deep-frying, 48 wonton wrappers and water</ingredients><directions>Wipe any dirt off the mushrooms. Soak in warm water until softened(20 to 30 minutes). Squeeze out the excess water and chop. Wash and shred the bok choy leaf. Wash and dice the green onion. Mince the ginger until you have 1/2 teaspoons.

In a medium bowl, combine the ground with the dark soy sauce, sesame oil, sugar and salt. Add the lightly beaten egg and the vegetables. This is wonton filling.

Heat the oil to 375 degrees Fahrenheit. While the oil is heating, prepare the wontons. Lay a wonton wrapper in front of you. Place a teaspoon of the filling in the middle. Fold up the wonton so that it resembles a nurse's cap, wetting the edges to seal .

Add the won tons to the hot oil, a few at a time, sliding them in carefully. Deep-fry the wontons in batches until they are golden brown, turning to make sure they brown evenly. Drain on paper towels or a tempura rack if you have one. As with egg rolls, wontons should be served as soon as possible, to ensure they remain crispy. Serve with Sweet and Sour Sauce or red rice wine vinegar.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Plain Paratha</name><contributor>Zhang Lan</contributor><category>main course</category><description>A paratha can be eaten simply with a blob of butter spread on top but it is best served with pickles and yoghurt, or thick spicy curries of meat and vegetables. Some people prefer to roll up the paratha into a tube and eat it with tea, often dipping the paratha into the tea.</description><spices>None</spices><source>friend</source><rating>normal</rating><ingredients>For Dough:
2 Cups Wheat Flour
1/2 tsp salt
oil
1/2 cup  Ghee/butter/Margarine
water</ingredients><directions>If using Butter/Margarine bring it room temparature.
Mix flour salt &amp; Required water to make a dough consistency. Rub oil over &amp; knead it soft .Let it rest for an hour.

With a help of a rolling pin take a lemon sized dough .
Roll it to a a small round &amp; apply some butter/ghee to it. Fold into two again fold the same.Start rolling to form a triangle.

Heat a flat pan ,when it gets hot add the paratha &amp; let it cook for a minute. When it starts to get small bubbles turn around &amp; add a small tsp of oil around the paratha. when the brown spots appear take it out &amp; keep it in an in a covered box.

Serve hot or warm with any accompaniment.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>White Chicken Chili</name><contributor>Kendra Hicks</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This recipe is "white" version of traditional chili - great northern beans replace the kidney beans and chicken takes the place of ground beef. Lime juice and pepper sauce make this chili tangy, a little spicy and very delicious!</description><spices>Ground cumin
Dried oregano
Chopped fresh cilantro</spices><source>Mother</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>6 skinless, boneless chicken breasts
1 cup chopped white onion
4 cloves garlic, finely chopped
4 cups chicken broth
2 tsp ground cumin
2 tsp dried oregano
1 tsp salt
1/2 tsp red pepper sauce
2 cans (each 15 oz) great northern beans, rinsed and drained
1 can (11 oz) corn, drained
6 tbsp lime juice
4 tbsp chopped fresh cilantro</ingredients><directions>1. In a 3.5 to 4 qt slow cooker, mix onion, garlic, broth, cumin, oregano, salt, and pepper sauce. Add Chicken.
2. Cover; cook on LOW heat setting for 4 to 5 hours.
3. Remove chicken from slow cooker. Use two forks to shred the chicken into pieces. Return the chicken to the slow cooker.
4. Stir in the beans, corn, lime juice, and cilantro. Cover and cook on LOW heat setting 15 to 20 minutes or until beans and corn are hot.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Apple Rhubarb Crumble</name><contributor>Andrew Tubman</contributor><category>Desert</category><description>This is a recipe my mom cooks all the time.She says she got it off the internet.It's
a pretty standard apple cruble with the addition of rhubarb and maple syrup.
Its yummy.</description><spices>Nutmeg
Cinnimon</spices><source>allrecipes.com</source><rating>Not Spicy</rating><ingredients>3 cups chopped fresh or frozen rhubarb
2 medium tart apples, peeled and chopped
1 egg
3/4 cup sugar
1/4 cup maple syrup
1/4 teaspoon ground nutmeg
1/4 teaspoon ground cinnamon
1 cup all-purpose flour
1/2 cup packed brown sugar
Pinch of salt
1/2 cup cold butter or margarine</ingredients><directions>In a bowl, combine the rhubarb, apples, egg, sugar, syrup, nutmeg and cinnamon.
Pour into a greased 2-qt. baking dish. In another bowl, combine the flour, brown sugar and salt.
Cut in butter until the mixture resembles coarse crumbs; sprinkle over fruit mixture.
Bake at 350 degrees F for 45-55 minutes or until bubbly.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Cannelloni</name><contributor>Armando Taucer</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Pasta wrapped around a filling, mostly cheese. An old family recipe, we generally serve it at Christmas,though that is
because it takes a long time to make and serves a whole load of people rather then for any traditional reason. It should be noted
that some people (including myself) prefer the taste without the sauce described.</description><spices>None</spices><source>Italy</source><rating>coold</rating><ingredients>Filling
4-6 sausages (mild Italian)
300 grams mozzarella cheese grated
425 grams ricotta cheese
2 eggs
1/2 cup grated parmesan cheese

Sauce

1 tbsp. olive oil
1 large finely diced onion
1 stalk finely diced celery
1 finely diced medium carrot (optional)
water
1 large can of diced tomatoes
fresh or dried basil (1 tbsp fresh or 1 tsp dried)
salt and pepper to taste
chicken broth cube
tomato paste

Pasta
5 cups flour
9 eggs
1/2 tsp. salt</ingredients><directions>Filling

Put the sausages in a frying pan and prick them with a fork.  Brown on all sides over medium heat.  Continue to cook on medium-low
heat  adding water as necessary to keep sausages from sticking and burning.  When cooked all the way through, put them in a food
processor with ricotta and mozzarella - you may have to do this in two batches.  Pulse until well blended.  Put in a mixing bowl
and add parmesan, eggs, salt and pepper.  The number of eggs can be adjusted to get the right consistency of filling.

Sauce

Heat oil in a heavy saucepan.  Saute onion, celery and carrot until soft adding water as needed to keep vegetables moist and not
sticking to pan.  Add tomatoes, basil, salt and pepper, chicken broth cube and half a can of tomato paste and boil gently for
20-30 minutes.  Blend in a food processor.  Add more tomato paste if the mixture is too runny or some broth if too thick.

Pasta

Put the flour on counter in a pile.  Make a hole in the middle and fill it with eggs and salt.  Mix with a fork and clean hands
until well mixed.  Divide dough into three or four balls and cover to keep moist.  Run dough balls through pasta machine gradually
thinning.  Divide the long strips into 4 or 5 cm. rectangles.  Cook in boiling, salted water with 1 tbsp of oil for 4 or 5
minutes.  Drain and run under cold water or keep immersed in cold water to keep pasta from sticking together.

Assembling

Spread the cooked, cooled pasta rectangles on a table covered with a clean cloth.  Pipe or spoon filling across short end of each
rectangle.  Roll up and place in a buttered baking dish.  Add a little broth to keep them moist.  Cover with sauce.  A single
layer of cannelloni works best but if you are going to have multiple layers in your dish, put sauce between each layer.

Bake in a 350 degree oven until the cannelloni are hot and the sauce is bubbly.  Serve with grated parmesan cheese.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Vietnamese caramel custard</name><contributor>Hung Vuong</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is my favorite food. I eat it as a dessert.</description><spices>Sweet</spices><source>Vietnamese recipe</source><rating>Too Sweet</rating><ingredients>4 Large eggs
500ml fresh milk
300g sugar
120ml water
Shaved ice
coffee(optional)</ingredients><directions>In a large mixing bowl, beat eggs well with 100 g sugar, fresh milk and vanilla powder. Set aside.
Into a pan, add half the water and the remaining sugar and bring to the boil.
Stir well until sugar melts and syrup is a caramel color.
Add remaining water and stir well. Remove from heat.
Pour 1 tablespoon of syrup each into 12 plastic or stainless steel moulds.
Fill moulds up with beaten egg mixture. Arrange moulds in a steamer and steam for 30 minutes.
To test if custard is cooked, simply insert a bamboo skewer into custard.
If the skewer comes out clean, the custard is cooked.
Remove from heat and leave to cool. Refrigerate until firm.
To serve, use the tip of a small knife to go around inside edge of each mould.
Then turn custard out onto dessert plates.
Top with a shaved ice.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Tex-Mex Style Dinner Loaf</name><contributor>100781662</contributor><category>Main COurse</category><description>The flavour of this loaf is even better the next day.
Leftovers make terrific sandwiches.</description><spices>Cilantro
Cumin</spices><source>Joy of Cooking</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>1 ancho pepper
1 cup textured vegatable protein
One 15-ounce can Italian or Mexican-style tomato sauce
3/4 cup water
1 large egg, beaten
1/4 cup raisins
1 small onion, chopped
1 small fresh jalapeno pepper, seeded and minced, or
2 canned chile peppers, drained and chopped
3/4 cup dry bread crumbs
1/3 cup all-purpose flour
1/4 cup finely chopped cilantro
2 teaspoons salt
1 teaspoon ground cumin</ingredients><directions>Soak ancho chile pepper in 1/2 cup boiling water till
softened, for 15-20 minutes. Preheat oven to 350'F.
Grease a 9x5" loaf pan. Drain the chile, and squeeze
out the excess water. Chop the chile, discarding the
seeds and membranes. Combine with rest of ingredients.
Pack the loaf mixture into the pan. Cover loosely with
aluminum foil and bake for 45 minutes. Uncover and bake
until set, ~30 minutes. Let stand in the pan on a rack
for 5 minutes, then invert onto a serving platter.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Lasagna Roll-Ups</name><contributor>Gregory Bint</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>All the fun of regular lasagna, but all rolled up into a lasagna noodle
instead of laid out in a pan.  Uses sausage meat instead of regular beef and
takes less time to prepare and bake.</description><spices>Fresh Parsley
Marinara Sauce</spices><source>Dear Mom</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>12 Lasagna noodles
2 cups ricotta cheese
1 egg
1/4 cup chopped parsley
2 cups shredded mozzarella cheese
8 ounces Italian sausage
1 28oz jar marinara sauce</ingredients><directions>Preheat oven to 350F.  Cook lasagna noodles according to package directions.  Drain
noodles and rinse under cold water.  Mix ricotta, egg, parsley and 1 cup of mozzarella in
a large bowl and set aside.  Remove sausage meat from casings and cook in a skillet over
medium heat until browned and crumbly; drain fat.  Spread 1/2 cup of the marinara sauce
in a 9 x 13 inch baking dish.  Spread 3 tablespoons of the ricotta mixture onto each
noodle and top with some sausage meat.  Roll up each noodle and place in baking dish so
that the seam of the roll is down.  Top the roll-ups with the remaining sauce and
mozzarella.  Cover loosely with foil and bake for 15 minutes; remove foil and bake for
another 10 minutes until brown and bubbly.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Korean Pork Cutlet</name><contributor>My mom</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is my mom's homemade Pork Cutlet, known as Donkatsu. This recipe is
usaually known in the asian continents, usually thick, fried, eaten with ketchup.
The specialty of this homemade pork cutlet is that it is very thin, and crunchy</description><spices>soy sauce</spices><source>fusion recipe</source><rating>mild not even hot</rating><ingredients>2 kg porks
1/2 cup milk
1 bag of crumbled bread powder(either korean or japan)
1 pack of olive oil
8~10 eggs
10 teaspoon of soy sauce or ketchup (for sauce-dipping purpose only)
2 teaspoon salt
1 teaspoon sugar
2 lb flour
6 tablespoons water</ingredients><directions>In a medium bowl, combine egg and milk; stir it until complete mix. chop off
porks into hand-sized pieces. Merge them into this egg and milk mixture for 5 minutes.
Take out porks, take and spread out crumbled bread powder into large plate. Coat up the merged-porks with crumbled powder.
Make sure you coat every porks completely. Take olive oil into big pan, pour oils down to merge those porks into oil.
Take them, and get them into oil. You will be frying them for 15~20 minutes.After that, take them out, they are ready.
Take your sauce whatever you want, cut them with scissors, eat them!!</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Grandma's Chicken Noodle Soup</name><contributor>Haiyan Zhou</contributor><category>Soups and Stews</category><description>This is a recipe that was given to me by my grandmother. It is a very savory and tasty soup and I believe that all will like it. If you would like to add even more flavor, try using smoked chicken!!</description><spices>salt
balk paper</spices><source>some book</source><rating>null</rating><ingredients>2 1/2 cups wide egg noodles
1 teaspoon vegetable oil
12 cups chicken broth
1 1/2 tablespoons salt
1 teaspoon poultry seasoning
1 cup chopped celery
1 cup chopped onion
1/3 cup cornstarch
1/4 cup water
3 cups diced, cooked chicken meat</ingredients><directions>1. Bring a large pot of lightly salted water to a boil. Add egg noodles and oil, and boil for 8 minutes, or until tender. Drain, and rinse under cool running water.
2. In a large saucepan or Dutch oven, combine broth, salt, and poultry seasoning. Bring to a boil. Stir in celery and onion. Reduce heat, cover, and simmer 15 minutes.
3. In a small bowl, mix cornstarch and water together until cornstarch is completely dissolved. Gradually add to soup, stirring constantly. Stir in noodles and chicken, and heat through.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Taiwanese Kaoliang Pork Ribs Soup Noodles</name><contributor>Shoou-Sheng Row</contributor><category>Cuisine</category><description>My family's modification to the well known Taiwanese cuisine - Pork Ribs Soup Noodles. The major difference is the large alcohol contents in this version compared to the original one. One shall be fairly wasted after eating this unless you're an Engineer or Taiwanese.</description><spices>"Aged Ginger",
"Southern Chinese Ginger",
"Black Pepper",
"Garlic",
"Chinese Wild Pepper",
"White Pepper",
"Bay Laurel Leaf",
"Star Anise",
"Coriander Leaf",
"Red Hot Chilli Pepper",
"Japenol",
"Szchan Red Pepper",
"Seven Spices Powder"</spices><source>Father side family recipe</source><rating>GODLIKE</rating><ingredients>Pork thigh and large leg bones, Pork ribs, Ramen or Chinese noodles, Your choice of steamed vegetables, Small dried sardiens, Eggs, Sliced dried Bonito, Sliced dried flying fish, Konbu, Black mushrooms, Onions, Green onions, Leek, Aged ginger, Southern Chinese ginger, Bay Laurel Leaf, Star Anise, Apple, Kinmen Kaoiang (sorghum wine, has to be Kinmen made and has a minimum 58% of alcohol or else it just wouldn't do the job), Rice wine, Mirin, Soy Sauce (Taiwanese Kimlan soy sause is most preferred, or any Japanese brand soy sauce, but don't use Chinese or Hong Kong brands or else you'll ruin the taste), Table salt, Black Pepper, Chinese Wild Pepper, White Pepper, Potato starch, Garlic, Sunflower oil, Sesame oil. Prepare a good amount of them because we'll be using a lot.</ingredients><directions>The directions are quite simple once you break them down as different components to deal with, there are 5 different components, and all you have to do is mix them together in the end with the final directions. The components can be made on different days as long as they're well preserved; it takes more than a day to complete all the steps anyways so no point in rushing.

Component 1 - Soy Sauce Extract:
Put large amount of Konbu (the more the stronger your extract would be) with sufficient amount of water inside a large bowl and leave it for one day, cut up black mushrooms in slices and put them in a huge bowl full of water and leave them for a night, fast cook the sliced up dry flying fish and sardines along with sliced dry Bonito, Put everything inside a big pot and boil it until the taste is fully trasfered to the soup (remember to take out the Konbu right after the water starts boiling), get rid of all the stuff inside the pot except the soup, pour it into another large pot and add large amount of soy sauce, salt and rice wine in a 3:1:3 ratio, add just a bit of Mirin for the unique sweetness, boil until it tastes really strong but not unbareble. Collect and store the soup well preserved for future use.

Component 2 - Pork Bone Soup:
Use a hammer and smash the pork leg and thigh bones until you can see cracks with blood gushing out of them, chop/saw them into managable size, cook the bones in a pot with boiling water for 40-50 min. and throw all the soup and floating goo away, now put the bones, apple, onion, green onion, garlic, aged ginger, a bit of salt and soy sauce, black pepper, bay laurel leaf, Kinmen Kaolian (pour according to the amount you can handle), rice wine, and star anise into the pot and boil (leave the apple and onions with their skins). Boil about 8 hours on stove with medium to low heat, making sure you don't burn your soup. Check often and take out the floating fat and blood, make sure the lid is shut tight so you don't lose all your alcohol.

Component 3 - Fried Pork Ribs:
Spray salt and pepper all over fresh spare ribs, marinate them in diced green onions, garlic, southern Chinese ginger, aged ginger, along with soy sauce and of course the most important out of all - Kinmen Kaoliang. Marinate them for about 30 - 60 minutes depending on how strong would you like your ribs. While you're wating for the marinating, mix diced garlic and aged ginger with pepper, salt, egg, and just a tiny bit of soy sauce to make the base coating for the fired ribs, take the marinated ribs out and mix them well with the coating, coat one at a time again inside a plastic bag filled with potato powder. Fry the coated ribs in 180 degree boiling sunflower oil, do this ASAP before the oil goes deadly and cause you cancer. Fry the ribs until they turn totally GOLDEN and buzzing with hot oil.

Component 4 - Hot Spring Egg:
Heat water till 68 degrees, turn off the stove, carefully put the eggs in and close the lid steam for 20 minutes.

Component 5 - Noodles and Vegetables:
Steam your choice of vegetable and cook noodles.

FINALIZATION -
1. steam and heat your bowl with hot water, get rid of the water once you've make sure that the bowl is hot.
2. Pour heated Soy sauce extract into the bowl according to your taste, just remember that you can always pour more in if you feel like the taste isn't strong enough, so start light.
3. Pour boiling hot pork soup into the bowl making sure that none of the bones and those random stuff went in too.
4. put your cooked noodles and vegetables in, break the prepared hot spring egg into the soup noodles.
5. Place the fried ribs on top of the noodles and season with sesame oil and a small amount of coriander leaf if you like.
6. Prepare a dipping dish of grined up Chinese wild peppers with salt and white peppers for extra ribs to dip in and serve as a side dish.
7. And never forget that bottle of Kinmen Kaoliang; afterall, nothing tastes good without some alcohol!</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Chili</name><contributor>Corey Faibish</contributor><category>chili</category><description>basic chili whose spice level can be modified by the increase/decrease of chili power and such spicy ingredients.</description><spices>1 tbsp chili powder (+for spicier)
1/2 tsp oregano
1/4 tsp crushed chillies</spices><source>I got this recipe from my mom, she got it fro her cookbook(s).</source><rating>mild</rating><ingredients>3/4 lb ground beef
1 28oz can of tomatoes, drained
1 19oz can red kidney beans, drained
3 tbsp tomato paste</ingredients><directions>Saute onion &amp; green pepper in oil for 10 min, over medium heat.
Add meat + brown. Add tomatoes, beans, tomato &amp; paste, spices &amp; mix thoroughly.
Add salt to taste + simmer for 2 hours.
Serve with french bread.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Clam Sycee</name><contributor>Chang Wu</contributor><category>Dim Sum</category><description>Clam sycee originated in Shanghai, on the coast of eastern China. A popular New Year's dish, it symbolizes good fortune and prosperity, as the stuffed clams resemble the gold or silver bouillion originally used as money in China. Traditionally, the clams would be steamed before stir-frying or deep-frying, but I've cooked them in wine instead and combined the wine with the sauce for a bit of extra flavor.</description><spices>Sesamum indicum</spices><source>Chinese recipe</source><rating>GOOD</rating><ingredients>2 dozen clams, such as littleneck or cherrystone
2 teaspoons olive oil
1/2 cup dry white wine
2 tablespoons Chinese rice wine or dry sherry, divided
1 slice ginger
1 green onion, cut on the diagonal into thirds
1 tablespoon cornstarch dissolved in 2 tablespoons water
3/4 cup chicken broth or stock
1 tablespoon oyster sauce
2 tablespoons soy sauce, divided
1 teaspoon granulated sugar
3/4 pound ground pork
1 tablespoon cornstarch
Salt, to taste</ingredients><directions>Use a stiff brush to scrub the outside of the clams under cold running water. Drain.Heat a wok or large frying pan over medium high heat. Add the olive oil, wine, 1 tablespoon Chinese rice wine or sherry, ginger, and green onion and the clams. Cover and cook just until the clams open (about 10 minutes). Use a slotted spoon to remove the clams from the pan. Do not clean out the pan.While the clams are steaming, mix the cornstarch and water into a paste. Combine the chicken broth, oyster sauce, 1 tablespoon soy sauce and sugar.Shuck the clams, setting aside the shells for later. Mince the clam meat and combine with the ground pork. Stir in 1 tablespoon sherry, 1 tablespoon soy sauce, 1 tablespoon cornstarch, and salt to taste.Stuff this mixture into the clam half shells. Rub the cornstarch/water mixture paste over top. Reserve any extra cornstarch paste to add to the sauce later.At this point you can either deep-fry or stir-fry the clams. If deep-frying, be careful to deep-fry only a few clams at a time, meat side up, sliding them carefully into the wok so that the oil doesn't splatter. Deep-fry until golden in color and drain on paper towels or a tempura rack if you have one. If stir-frying, place the clams in the wok with the meat side down. Stir-fry in 2 tablespoons heated oil until golden.Add the sauce ingredients into the pan with the wine. Add the clams back to the wok and simmer, covered, for about 20 minutes. Add any remaining cornstarch/water paste, stirring quickly to thicken. Serve hot.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Onion Soup Gratinee</name><contributor>Sylvain Blais</contributor><category>Entree</category><description>This is authentic Bistro style Potage D'Oignon. Enjoy! It takes a while to make, but
is easy enough for anyone to make.</description><spices>Thyme
Bay leaf
White pepper</spices><source>Occidental recipe</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>6 tablespoons olive oil
4 medium yellow onions, sliced 1/4 inch thick
1 tablespoon unsalted butter
1 clove garlic, thinly sliced
4 sprigs fresh thyme
1 bay leaf
salt to taste
1/4 teaspoon ground white pepper
3/4 cup dry white wine
2 quarts chicken stock
1/2 cup port wine
6 slices French bread
2 cups shredded Gruyere cheese</ingredients><directions>1. Heat the olive oil in a heavy pot over medium heat. Add the onions;
cook and stir until golden brown, about 30 minutes.
2. Add butter, garlic, thyme, bay leaf, salt, and white pepper. Cook and stir for about 10 minutes. Increase the heat to high, and stir in the white wine.
Bring to a boil, and cook until wine has reduced by half, 3 to 5 minutes. Pour in the chicken stock, and simmer over medium heat for 45 minutes.
3. Preheat the oven's broiler. Remove the thyme sprigs and bay leaf from the soup and stir in the port wine. Ladle soup into 6 crocks or heat proof bowls,
top each with a slice of bread, and a generous helping of Gruyere cheese. Place the bowls on a baking sheet for ease in handling.
4. Place under the broiler for 2 to 3 minutes, until the bread and cheese are toasted and bubbly. Serve immediately.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Spaghetti alla Carbonara</name><contributor>Nicolas Porter</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional italian recipe. Due to the name of the dish, carbonara ( or italian for charcoal), legend has it that it was a meal originally cooked for italian charcoal miners. This dish is very unhealthy, so don't make it too often!</description><spices>black pepper</spices><source>Internet</source><rating>very mild</rating><ingredients>1 pound of spaghetti (also works well with spaghettini or linguini)
1/2 pound of bacon or pancetta
1/2 cup of grated parmesan cheese
3-4 eggs
1/4 cup of finely chopped italian parsley</ingredients><directions>Cook the spaghetti until they are cooked but firm (al dente). While the spaghetti is cooking, fry in a big pan (important) the bacon (or pancetta) until crispy. When the bacon is ready, drain some of the fat out of the pan, but make you sure you keep some in. Cut the bacon in small pieces. Mix eggs, cheese and parsley togheter. Add the mix and the spaghetti to the pan, and stir until the spaghetti is evenly coated with sauce and bacon bits. Serve immediately.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Peanut Butter Rice Krispie Squares</name><contributor>527803</contributor><category>Dessert</category><description>This recipe is a idea developed from the classic
Rice Krispie squares. They have the same feel except
the Rice Krispies are coated in peanut butter. It has
less sugar and is healthier than the classic squares.</description><spices>N/A</spices><source>My Grandmother</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>1/4 cup of butter or margerine
2 - 3 cups of marshmallows
3 - 4 cups of peanut butter
6 cups of Rice Krispies Cereal</ingredients><directions>Melt butter/margerine, marshmallows, and peanut butter in a pan on low heat.
Put Rice Krispies into bowl then add melted mixture.
Stir until the Rice Krispie are covered to your pleasure.
Place in pan and leave to cool.
Enjoy.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Beef Noodle Soup</name><contributor>Chris Duong</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Beef Noodle Soup is served as a bowl of white rice noodles in clear beef broth, with thin cuts of beef (steak, fatty flank, lean flank, brisket). Variations featuring tendon, tripe, meatballs, chicken leg, chicken breast, or other chicken organs (heart, liver, tongue, etc.) can also be used.</description><spices>Star anise
Hot chili sauce
black pepper
red chili peppers</spices><source>The Motherland</source><rating>Look at the spices, wtf do you think?</rating><ingredients>11/2 pound Beef sirloin (Sliced thin)
4 qtz Beef broth (or chicken broth)
3 large Onions, (2 unpeeled - halved, 1 peeled - sliced thin)
3 Shallots (unpeeled)
7 Star anise
2 teaspoons Salt
2 Scallions  (sliced thin)
1 tablespoon Shredded coriander
1/4 cup Hot chili sauce
1 package of Vietnamese Pho rice noodle
1/2 cup Vietnamese fish sauce
Freshly ground black pepper
2 cups Fresh bean sprouts
2 Fresh red chili peppers (sliced thin)
2 Limes (cut into wedges)
1 bn Of fresh mint</ingredients><directions>1. In a large pot, combine the beef broth with 2 qtz of water.  Bring to boil.    Add onion halve, parsnips, and salt . Simmer for 15 minutes.

2. Soak the rice sticks in warm water for 30 minutes. Drain and set aside. Meanwhile, slice beef sirloin against grain into thin slices; set aside. In a small bowl, combine the scallions, coriander and half of the slice onions.

3.When broth is ready, strain it through a strainer into a clean pot. Add the fish sauce and bring the broth to a boil. Reduce the heat and keep the broth at a bare simmer.

4. When ready to serve, put the rice noodle in a bowl and microwave for 30 seconds. Top the noodles with the sliced meats. Bring the broth to a rolling boil. Ladle the broth directly over the meat to cook the raw beef. Garnish with the scallion mixture and freshly ground black pepper.

5.Serve the onions in hot chili sauce and the accompaniments on the side. Each diner will add these ingredients as desired.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Gnocchi Noudles</name><contributor>Sebastian Schneider</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a German/Italian recipe.</description><spices>Pepper and Salt</spices><source>German/Italian Recipe</source><rating>Tasty</rating><ingredients>1 onion
1 clove of garlic
Tomato puree
Mozarella cheese
Cnocchis noudles
Oliveoil</ingredients><directions>Roast the onion and the garlic gently in a pot (don't let it get dark). Add tomato puree into the pot and bring to a broil. Add salt and pepper, additionally you can add other spices if you want. Cut some of the mozarella in cubes and put the cubes in the sauce, cook until you can not see the cheese anymore and add about 2 - 3 tablespoons oliveoil. Cook the gnocchis and serve everything hot. Additionally you can serve small slices of mozarella.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Meat Sauce</name><contributor>Spencer Winson</contributor><category>Sauce</category><description>This is a recipe I use when I make sauce for pasta. It's an easy recipe to make and does not require many ingredients.</description><spices>Montreal Steak Spice</spices><source>Homemade</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>1/2 lb. ground beef.
1 onion, chopped
1 tablespoon montreal steak spice
1 can of spaghetti sauce.</ingredients><directions>In a sauce pan, brown beef and cook onions until they are soft. Pour can of sauce onto beef. Add Steak spice and stir until sauce is heated. Pour over pasta and enjoy.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>French Toast</name><contributor>David Carson</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a very basic breakfast meal.  It is very tasty, and easy to prepare.  It is also an excellent way to use up slightly stale bread.</description><spices>None</spices><source>Cooking Handbook</source><rating>Extremely Delicious</rating><ingredients>4 slices of bread
1 egg
1/3 - 1/2 cup of milk
1/2 tsp vanilla
maple syrup, applesauce, jam</ingredients><directions>Beat egg, milk, and vanilla in a wide, shallow bowl or pan. The bowl / pan must be wide enough for you to lay the bread flat in it. Heat a skillet on medium and add butter. Dip slices of bread into the egg mixture, making sure to coat both sides.  Place in the skillet, cook both sides. Top with maple syrup, applesauce, or jam.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Quick Banana Bread</name><contributor>Justin Mutter</contributor><category>Breads</category><description>Easy to make banana bread that everyone will love.</description><spices>None</spices><source>Torn out page form a very old cook book</source><rating>Not spicy at all</rating><ingredients>1 3/4 cups flour
2 1/4 tablespoons baking powder
1/2 tablespoon salt
1/3 cup shortening
2/3 cup sugar
3/4 teaspoon grated lemon rind
1 or 2 eggs
1 1/4 cups ripe banana</ingredients><directions>Preheat oven to 350 F. Sift together the flour, baking powder and salt. Blend together the shortening, sugar, and lemon rind. Add egg(s) and banana to the shortening mixture, and beat well.  Add the flour mixture to the shortening, egg, and banana mixture 1/3 at a time, always beating the mixture until smooth before adding more.  Place the batter in a greased bread pan, roughly 8 1/2" by 4 1/2".  Bake for about an hour, or until done.  Allow to cool before slicing.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Homemade Italian Lasagne</name><contributor>RhiAnne Brown</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>A harmony of rich sauce and sharp herbs makes this Italian dish a real winner.
With alternating layers of pasta, cheese, and tomato sauce this meal will have everyone
raving! Cooking time: Approx. 1 hour;Serves 6.</description><spices>Italian Herbs, Nutmeg, Garlic</spices><source>The Brown Family</source><rating>5 Stars</rating><ingredients>9 Lasagne noodles
1 can ground tomatoes (28 oz / 800g)
1 can Tomato paste - Italian (6 oz / 170g)
10 oz (300g) ground beef
1 - 2 cloves of garlic
Tsp Italian herbs
1/4 cup red (cooking) wine
1 cup grated mozzarella cheese
1 cup white sauce
1/2 cup milk
1/2 tsp nutmeg
2 tsp cornstarch
Tbsp Parmesan cheese
1/2 cup cottage cheese
Grated parmesan cheese
Loaf of Garlic bread
Bottle of Italian Red wine (Chianti)</ingredients><directions>Pre-heat oven to 350 degrees Celsius.

Fry ground beef until cooked, mash Garlic &amp; herbs in mortar with pestle,
add to frying pan, cook for a minute.Add ground tomatoes, tomato paste &amp; wine.
Simmer for 10 - 15 minutes. Stir occasionally.
Meanwhile, make the white sauce. Pour the milk into a saucepan &amp; boil. Mix the
cornstarch with a little milk. When almost boiling, add to pan - thicken the sauce.
Add nutmeg, cottage cheese, parmesan &amp; black pepper to taste. Stir well
Ladle about 1/4 tomato sauce into bottom of lasagne pan (9 x 11),
spread to cover evenly. Place 3 noodles over sauce.
Cover noodles with 1/2 white sauce, sprinkle with 1/3 cup mozzarella.
Top with 1/3 remaining tomato sauce
Repeat.
Place last 3 noodles on top. Cover with remaining tomato sauce.
Top with remaining mozzarella &amp; sprinkle with parmesan cheese.
Cover Lasagne pan with aluminum foil. Bake for 45 mins - 1 hour.
Place Garlic bread in oven to heat during last 10 - 15 minutes
Remove foil from Lasagne, return to oven to let top brown
Serve with Garlic bread (&amp; red wine)</directions></recipe><recipe><name>The Whole Jar of Peanut Butter Cookies</name><contributor>Martin Madzio</contributor><category>Dessert</category><description>These delicious cookies get their name from the fact that it takes a whole jar of peanut butter to make them! The only way you could make them better is to enjoy them with a nice cold glass of milk. Peanut haters beware!</description><spices>Vanilla Extract</spices><source>http://www.allrecipes.com</source><rating>Bland</rating><ingredients>1 cup butter, softened
1 cup white sugar
1 cup packed brown sugar
2 egg
1 egg yolk
2 teaspoons vanilla extract
1 (18 ounce) jar peanut butter
2 cups all-purpose flour
1 teaspoon baking soda
1/2 teaspoon salt
1 cup chopped peanuts</ingredients><directions>1. In a large bowl, cream butter, white sugar, and brown sugar until smooth. Add the eggs, yolks, and vanilla; mix until fluffy. Stir in peanut butter. Sift together the flour, baking soda, and salt; stir into the peanut butter mixture. Finally, stir in the peanuts. Refrigerate the dough for at least 2 hours.
2. Preheat oven to 350 degrees F (175 degrees C). Lightly grease a cookie sheet.
3. Roll dough into walnut sized balls. Place on the prepared cookie sheet and flatten slightly with a fork. Bake for 12 to 15 minutes in the preheated oven. Cookies should look dry on top. Allow to cool for a few minutes on the cookie sheet before removing to cool completely on a rack. These cookies taste great when slightly undercooked.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Barscz</name><contributor>Bart Wernik</contributor><category>Appetizer</category><description>This recipe is traditional to Eastern Europe and Russia and is more commonly known as Borsch (beat soup).
The recipe was provided by my mother and is sweet in flavor. Depending how much pepper you add the soup can either
be mild or medium.Try adding beef or cheese tortellini to the soup when serving.</description><spices>Pepper, Salt</spices><source>My mom</source><rating>MILD - MEDIUM</rating><ingredients>1 &amp; 1/2 litres of water
1/2 Kg red beets
1/2 Kg of beef on bone
1 carrott chopped, 1 celery chopped, 1/2 leak chopped, 1 parsnip chopped, 1 onion chopped, 1 garlic diced
1/2 cup of dried mushrooms
1 bay leaf
1 tablespoon of salt
1 tablespoon of pepper
1/2 tablespoon of sugar</ingredients><directions>Soak the mushrooms in water for 30 min and then combine the mushrooms with the 1 &amp; 1/2 litres of water,
the meat on the bone and the salt. Boil slowly, stirring occasionally, for 30 min then add the carrott, celery, leak,
bay leaf, parsnip, onion and pepper. Coninue boiling (stirring occasionally) until the vegetables are tender. Filter the
solid vegetables and meat from the broth. Set aside. Boil the beets in a pot of water until tender. Take the beets out, peel
them and grind them. Put the beets into the vegetable broth and boil for another 10 min. Add the garlic and sugar.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Chocolate Muffins</name><contributor>311942</contributor><category>Desert</category><description>This is great desert for chocolate lovers and people who are avoiding spicy deserts.
This particular recipe will make a dozen muffins.</description><spices>Cayenne pepper</spices><source>A pamphlet handed out in a supermarket a long time ago.</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>-2 eggs
-1cup or 250 mL milk
-2 cups or 500 mL all-purpose flour
-1 1/2 cup or 350 mL chocolate chips
-1/2 cup or 125 mL cocoa powder
-1/2 cup or 125 mL sugar
-1/8 tsp of salt
-1/8 tsp of cayenne pepper
-1 tbsp or 15 mL baking powder
-1/4 cup or 50 mL vegetable oil</ingredients><directions>-Preheat oven to 375F or 190C.
-In a small bowl, whisk together the flour, chocolate powder, sugar, baking powder, chocolate chips and salt.
-In a seperate large bowl, whisk the eggs, milk, oil and cayenne pepper.
-Slowly add the dry ingredients from the small bowl into the wet ingredients in the large bowl while whisking.
-Keep whisking thoroughly until all the ingredients are completely blended.
-Lightly grease the muffin pan and sprinkle it with cocoa.
-Using an ice cream scoop, place a ball of the mixture into every slot in the pan.
-Slide the pan into the oven and let the muffins bake for 20 minutes or until an inserted toothpick comes out clean with a few crumbs.
-Let the muffins cool for at least 10 minutes before serving.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Tarallo</name><contributor>Anthony D'Angelo</contributor><category>Dessert/Snack</category><description>A sweet, delicious, round Italian cake with a hint of lemon and a hole in the middle. A yellow, fluffy texture on the inside with a golden-brown outside.</description><spices>Sugar (Cinnamon, etc. as desired)</spices><source>Family recipe</source><rating>Sweet and delicious!</rating><ingredients>-8 eggs
-16 tablespoons of sugar (2 per egg)
-16 tablespoons of flour (2 per egg)
-1 lemon (grated skin)
-1 cup of Canola oil
-3 espresso spoons of baking powder
-1 'fluted tube' pan</ingredients><directions>1. Preheat oven to 325 degrees Farenheit.
2. Mix all ingredients EXCEPT baking powder together in a mixing bowl.
3. Beat for 20 minutes.
4. Stir baking powder in.
5. Spray cooking spray in 'fluted tube' pan.
6. Bake for an hour.
7. Shut off oven and let sit in oven for 5-10 minutes.
--You can sprinkle powdered sugar or cinnamon on top after it's done. You can substitute orange peel instead of lemon skin and you could add some cinnamon in the mix.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Roasted Sweet Potato and Apple Soup</name><contributor>Matthew MacLeod</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is an thick and flavourful soup that is easy to make and great for a cold day.
Of course, you can easily modify the recipe; try using carrots, peppers, or squash.</description><spices>Salt
Pepper</spices><source>My Mom, who got it from a friend</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>2 med. Sweet potatoes, peeled
1 apple, peeled, cut into 1? pieces
1 med yellow onion, peeled, cut
2 cloves of garlic, peeled and chopped
2 tbs olive oil
salt and pepper
3-4 cups vegetable broth</ingredients><directions>(1)  Preheat oven to 450.  Place sweet potatoes, apple, onion and
garlic in a roasting pan. Toss with oil; season with salt and pepperto taste.
Roast, tossing once or twice, until soft and onions are starting to brown, about 20-25 minutes.
(2)  Place half of mixture in a blender, adding just enough broth to cover.
Puree, pouring in more broth until soup is smooth and not too thick.
Repeat with rest of mixture.
(3)  Heat on stove and serve.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Tibetan Momos</name><contributor>Tashi Topgyal</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional Tibetan recipe. We make it on special ocassion with usually large crowd. It is served with different designs and tastes delicious. When you take the first bite,it is usually hot and juicy and it compliments with a hot tibetan sauce.\par</description><spices>Hot Chilli Sauce</spices><source>Tibetan recipe</source><rating>MILD\par</rating><ingredients>There are no set ingredients for Momos. Meats and vegetables can all be chosen depending upon the culinary tastes of an individual. Some of the most common ingredients include,Potato,Cabbage ,Carrot,Onion,Spinach,Salt,Oil,,Water,Masalas of Choice,Meat of Choice (for meat Momos, ie: yak, chicken, Pork, etc.),Dough</ingredients><directions>Finely cut and chop the ingredients. The meat in particular should be as finely chopped as possible, however no less than half a centimeter.In a bowl, mix all of the ingredients thoroughly together with your hands. Make sure that the salt and masala are consistently mixed throughout.The dough must then be prepared with a careful balance of water and flour only. After kneading it, place the dough in a bowl. Cover it with a towel and let it sit for 10 minutes. You will know that it is ready once it has a certain spring-like resistance.Sprinkle a little flour on a very smooth surface. Take a ball of approximately 4 centimeters worth of dough, and using a rolling pin, roll it into a flat circle.Pick up the flat circle of dough in the palm of one hand and then spoon in the amount of thoroughly mixed ingredients of your choice.Gently close the palm of your hand while carefully squeezing together the top of the Momo using your thumb and index finger.After closing all of the Momos, place them on one of the specials pans with holes. Place this pan on the cooker with boiling water on the stove. The water beneath the pan causes steam to rise which will thoroughly cook your delicious Momos! They should be steamed and ready to eat in 15 minutes.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Vindaye Ourites</name><contributor>LEE SLEW, Jonathan</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional recipe from Rodrigues which is a sister island of Mauritius. Most people fish octopus as their living. They dried the octopus before cooking it.</description><spices>Saffron</spices><source>Mauritian Cuisine</source><rating>SPICY</rating><ingredients>3 lbs well clean Octopus
10 small Oignons
5 garlic cloves
4 whole chilies
2 coffee spoon of crushed mustard
2 coffee spoon saffron
2 coffee spoon vinegar
1 cup of oil</ingredients><directions>Boil the octopus for 45 minutes in a pressure cooker. Open and check if it is cooked, otherwise, add some water and leave it for 15 more minutes. Then remove from the fire and let it cool down. Cut the octopus in small pieces. Reserve. Preheat an oiled-pan. Add every ingredients but not the octopus. Let it cool down before adding the octopus. Mix the ingredients well with the octopus by shaking the pan.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Chunky Potato Soup</name><contributor>Shawn Hansen</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>A piping-hot bowl of this soup can chase away the chills on any cold day.</description><spices>Crushed red pepper flakes and Ground black pepper.</spices><source>Got the recipe from my mom.</source><rating>Hot and spicy</rating><ingredients>3 medium red potatoes, 2 cups water, 1 small onion, 3 tablespoons butter, 3 tablespoons all-purpose flour, Crushed red pepper flakes, Ground black pepper, 3 cups milk, 1/2 teaspoon sugar, 1 cup shredded cheddar cheese, and 1 cup cubed cooked ham.</ingredients><directions>1. Peel potatoes and cut into 1 inch cubes. 2. Bring water to a boil in a large saucepan.  Add potatoes and cook until tender.  Drain, reserving liquid.  Set aside potatoes.  Measure 1 cup cooking liquid, adding water, if necessary; set aside. 3. Peel and finely chop onion.  Melt butter in saucepan over medium heat.  Add onion to saucepan; cook, stirring frequently, until onion is translucent and tender, but not brown. 4. Add flour to saucepan; season with pepper flakes and black pepper to taste.  Cook 3 to 4 minutes. 5. Gradually add potatoes, reserved 1 cup cooking liquid, milk and sugar to onion mixture in saucepan; stir well.  Add cheese and ham.  Simmer over low heat 30 minutes, stirring frequently.  Store leftovers, covered, in refrigerator.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Baked Manicotti</name><contributor>Kirill Kashigin</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>great little dish</description><spices>Cayenne Pepper</spices><source>Italian recipe</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>1 package of 16 manicotti shells
8 oz grated parmesan cheese
6 cloves garlic ? minced
1 16 oz tub Ricotta cheese
8?12 oz fresh hot Italian bulk sausage
1 heaping tablespoon freshly snipped flat-leaf parsley
1 quart Bold Tomato Sauce
1/4 teaspoon cayenne pepper
16 oz mozzarella cheese ? shredded</ingredients><directions>Cook the manicotti according to package directions. Be careful not to over cook
In a large nonstick fry pan thoroughly cook the sausage, breaking it into small
bite?sized pieces ? Drain. In a mixing bowl, whisk together the sausage, Ricotta,
parmesan cheese, garlic, cayenne pepper, and parsley. Stuff each manicotti shell
with the mixture and place in a non stick baking dish. Pour the tomato sauce
over the manicotti, and top with the mozzarella cheese. Bake at 350? for 45
minutes, or until the cheese is bubbly.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Tibetan Momos</name><contributor>Tashi Topgyal</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional Tibetan recipe. We make it on special ocassion with usually large crowd. It is served with different designs and tastes delicious. When you take the first bite,it is usually hot and juicy and it compliments with a hot tibetan sauce.</description><spices>Hot Chilli Sauce</spices><source>Tibetan recipe</source><rating>MILD</rating><ingredients>There are no set ingredients for Momos. Meats and vegetables can all be chosen depending upon the culinary tastes of an individual. Some of the most common ingredients include,Potato,Cabbage ,Carrot,Onion,Spinach,Salt,Oil,,Water,Masalas of Choice,Meat of Choice (for meat Momos, ie: yak, chicken, Pork, etc.),Dough</ingredients><directions>Finely cut and chop the ingredients. The meat in particular should be as finely chopped as possible, however no less than half a centimeter.In a bowl, mix all of the ingredients thoroughly together with your hands. Make sure that the salt and masala are consistently mixed throughout.The dough must then be prepared with a careful balance of water and flour only. After kneading it, place the dough in a bowl. Cover it with a towel and let it sit for 10 minutes. You will know that it is ready once it has a certain spring-like resistance.Sprinkle a little flour on a very smooth surface. Take a ball of approximately 4 centimeters worth of dough, and using a rolling pin, roll it into a flat circle.Pick up the flat circle of dough in the palm of one hand and then spoon in the amount of thoroughly mixed ingredients of your choice.Gently close the palm of your hand while carefully squeezing together the top of the Momo using your thumb and index finger.After closing all of the Momos, place them on one of the specials pans with holes. Place this pan on the cooker with boiling water on the stove. The water beneath the pan causes steam to rise which will thoroughly cook your delicious Momos! They should be steamed and ready to eat in 15 minutes.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Rotisserie Chicken</name><contributor>Shane Panke</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a great easy recipe that our family loves. It's perfect as the main dish of a simple meal with French fries and cole slaw.</description><spices>Ground black pepper</spices><source>American recipe</source><rating>Very Mild</rating><ingredients>1 (3 pound) whole chicken
1 pinch salt
1/4 cup butter, melted
1 tablespoon salt
1 tablespoon paprika
1/4 tablespoon ground black pepper</ingredients><directions>Season the inside of the chicken with a pinch of salt. Place the chicken onto a rotisserie and set the grill on high. Cook for 10 minutes. During that time, quickly mix together the butter, 1 tablespoon of salt, paprika and pepper. Turn the grill down to medium and baste the chicken with the butter mixture. Close the lid and cook for 1 to 1 1/2 hours, basting occasionally, until the internal temperature reaches 180 degrees F (83 degrees C) when taken in the thigh with a meat thermometer. Remove from the rotisserie and let stand for 10 to 15 minutes before cutting into pieces and serving.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>DanDan Mian</name><contributor>zhiling Hu</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional southern of  Chinese noodle recipe. I found it from an international cooking book. It should taste spicy and a little bit sour.</description><spices>red pepper, garlic</spices><source>Chinese recipe</source><rating>taste good and hot</rating><ingredients>1/2 pound Chinese flat wheat noodles, or linguine
2 tablespoons tahini, or peanut butter
1 tablespoon ground Szechuan red peppercorn
1 tablespoon minced garlic
1 teaspoon brown sugar
2 teaspoons Chinese or white vinegar
2 teaspoons soy sauce
1 tablespoon dark sesame oil
1 tablespoon crushed roasted peanuts</ingredients><directions>Boil the noodles. Meanwhile, combine the tahini, Szechuan
pepper, garlic, sugar, vinegar, soy sauce, and sesame oil. When the
noodles are done, drain and toss them with the tahini
mixture. Sprinkle the peanuts on top before serving.Yield: 2 servings</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Pecan Butterball Cookies</name><contributor>Andrew Zemancik</contributor><category>Dessert</category><description>Round pecan cookies coated in icing sugar.</description><spices>None</spices><source>My Mother</source><rating>Bland</rating><ingredients>1 cup butter
? cup icing sugar
1 teaspoon vanilla extract
2 ? cups flour
1 cup finely chopped pecans</ingredients><directions>- cream butter, icing sugar and vanilla extract with electric mixer
- add sifted flour and blend well
- stir in pecans
- shape dough into 1 inch balls
- place on ungreased baking sheet
- bake at 400?F for 8-10 minutes (until lightly golden)
- remove from oven and cool on racks
- roll in sifted icing sugar when cool
- store in airtight container</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Super Swiss Potato Soup</name><contributor>Robert Theoret</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>There was no description that came along with this recipe, but it sounds pretty awesome and self explanatory.</description><spices>Cayenne Pepper
Hot Paprika</spices><source>The Red Cat Cookbook</source><rating>Un-parse-ably Hot</rating><ingredients>tablespoons butter, divided
1 small shallot, finely chopped
1 1/2 lbs idaho potatoes, peeled and quartered (about 2 medium potatoes)
3 cups low sodium chicken broth
3 cups water
1 1/2 cups milk
1 1/2 cups heavy cream
salt, to taste
fresh ground black pepper, to taste
cayenne pepper, to taste
3/4 cup grated gruyere cheese (about 6 ounces)
2 teaspoons hot paprika
2 scallions, white and green parts, finely sliced</ingredients><directions>Melt 2 tablespoons of butter in a heavy soup pot. Saute shallot in butter until translucent and soft, about 3 minutes. Add the potatoes, chicken broth and water. Bring to a boil, then reduce to a             simmer. Cook 15 minutes or until potatoes are soft when poked with a knife-tip. Strain the liquid into a bowl and set aside.

Pass potatoes through a food mill or ricer. Return to soup pot with milk, cream and 1 1/2 cups of cooking liquor. Whisk gently until combined well, but do not overwork the potatoes. Season with salt,         pepper and cayenne to taste, then add remaining 1 tablespoon of butter.

Divide Gruyere equally between four soup bowls. Ladle soup over cheese. Sprinkle with paprika and scallions to garnish.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>"Oven-Fried" Buffalo Chicken Wings</name><contributor>Wesley L. Lawrence</contributor><category>Snack/Appetizer</category><description>Crispy, delicious Buffalo chicken wings :)</description><spices>ground black pepper
anything hot you want to add</spices><source>Internet</source><rating>Mild, depends on your spices</rating><ingredients>5 pounds whole chicken wings
1 tsp salt
1 tsp fresh ground black pepper
2 tbsp hot sauce
2 tbsp vegetable oil
1 1/2 cup all-purpose flour
non-stick canola oil spray
large mixing bowl
aluminum foil
2 sheet pans
1 cup of your favorite Buffalo chicken wing sauce or glaze</ingredients><directions>It's important to cut your whole chicken wings into sections before they can become delicious Buffalo chicken wings. You want to separate each chicken wing at the joints to give you three sections per wing.

Once you've cut up all the whole chicken wings, transfer the flats and drums to a large bowl. The tips are too small to use in this Buffalo chicken wing recipe.

To the bowl of chicken wings, add the salt, pepper, hot sauce, oil, and your own spices. Toss to coat evenly.

Add the flour to a large plastic grocery bag, or clean garbage bag, and pour in the chicken wings. Twist the top of the bag closed and shake vigorously to coat the wings in the flour.

Cover the two baking sheets in foil, and spray them thoroughly with canola oil. Place the floured chicken wings evenly on the pans, and spray the tops of the wings lightly with the canola oil.

Bake the chicken wings in a preheated 400 degree F. oven for 30 minutes. Remove from oven and turn over each wing. Place back in the oven for another 30 minutes, or until the wings are golden-brown and the coating is getting crispy.

Once the Buffalo chicken wings are cooked, remove them from the oven, and transfer into a clean mixing bowl. Toss with 1 cup of the sauce, or glaze, of your choice.

Once the chicken wings are coated with the sauce, transfer to serving plates, and allow to cool for 5-10 minutes. The sauce will soak into the skin, and they will cool enough to be easily handled. Enjoy!</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Vietnamese Egg Rolls</name><contributor>Tuan Pham</contributor><category>Appetizer</category><description>This is a traditional Vietnamese appetizer made for almost all celebrations, one is
Lunar New Year. It should be crunchy and very tasty with all the variety of food
inside the roll. This is not my family's recipe because we do not have one so i found it
on http://recipes.epicurean.com/recipe/830/vietnamese-egg-rolls-(cha-gio).html</description><spices>Garlic Cloves
Red chili
Dried Chilli</spices><source>http://recipes.epicurean.com/recipe/830/vietnamese-egg-rolls-(cha-gio).html</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>1/2 lb. raw shrimp, minced
1/2 lb. lean pork, minced
1/2 lb. bean sprouts
2 medium carrots, grated
2 to 3 shallots, minced, if desired
1 oz. cellophane noodles(bean threads)
1 pkg. round rice paper(available at Oriental markets)
2 eggs, beaten
Oil for deep frying
Shredded scallions for garnish, if desired
Lettuce leaves
Dipping Sauce(Nuoc Cham)
1 fresh red chili or 2 small dried chilies
2 large garlic cloves, peeled
5 t sugar
Juice and pulp of 1/4 unpeeled lime
1/4 c fish sauce(available at Oriental markets)
1/3 c water
1 T shredded carrot
1 T minced scallion</ingredients><directions>In large bowl, combine shrimp, pork, bean sprouts, carrots and shallots; set aside.
Soak cellophane noodles in warm water about 15 minutes, until flexible; drain, cut into
one-inch pieces and add to meat mixture. Toss until combined.
Run one sheet of rice paper quickly under tepid water, handling carefully because paper is
very brittle. Place sheet on work surface and brush quickly with egg. Let stand a few
seconds, until flexible. With very sharp knife, cut into quarters(or halves, if larger
rolls are desired). Place one tablespoon filling on round edge of quarter piece; roll over
once, then tuck in sides to enclose filling and continue rolling. If using halves, place
about 1/3 cup filling on one end, roll once, tuck in sides and roll up.
Continue filling and rolling until all filling is used. The egg will hold the rolls
together. In wok or 10-inch frying pan, heat oil until a drop of water jumps on the
surface. Fry about eight rolls at a time until golden brown, about 15 minutes. Drain on
paper towels, garnish with scallions and serve with lettuce leaves and Nuoc Cham. Makes
about 50 small or 30 large egg rolls.
Dipping Sauce (Nuoc cham)
If using fresh chili, remove seeds and membrane. In food processor or blender, combine
chili, garlic, sugar, lime, fish sauce and water. Process or blend until well minced.
Pour into serving dish and sprinkle with carrot and scallion. Makes about 3/4 cup</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Kazakh Plov</name><contributor>Temirlan Kumargazhin</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional Kazakh food. This recipe contains my mother's own way of cooking this tasty dish.</description><spices>Red and black pepper</spices><source>Kazakhstan</source><rating>Not hot</rating><ingredients>600 gr. of lamb, 3 dining spoons of melted fat, 3 onions, 4 large carrots, 1 glass of rice, 1/4 glass of raisins</ingredients><directions>Cut onions into rings and put it into heated pot and fry till onions become golden-coloured. Put medium sliced pieces of lamb into the pot and fry with onions till meat becomes ruddy. Cut carrots into  straws, add to pot with pepper and salt. Fry till half done. Wash rice and put it into the pot and add water with ratio - 1.5 glass of water for 1 glass of rice. Wait till the pot starts boiling. Spread raisins inside the pot and stew on slow fire for 1 hour not mixing the mass. Turn off the fire and let plov rest for 10-15 minutes. Then mix the mass and serve the dish.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Oven Fried Chicken With Honey Butter Sauce</name><contributor>Chin Yen  Ong</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is one of my mother's specialty.
Chicken with honey and butter is the best combination.</description><spices>paprika</spices><source>my mom's recipe</source><rating>sweet</rating><ingredients>1/2 cup melted butter, 1 cup all-purpose flour, 2 teaspoons paprika, 1/2 teaspoon salt, 1/4 teaspoon pepper, 1 chicken (cut up), 1/4 cup melted butter, 1/4 cup lemon juice, 1/2 cup honey</ingredients><directions>Pour 1/2 c melted butter in a baking dish. Combine flour, paprika, salt and pepper. Dredge chicken pieces in the flour mixture. Put chicken pieces in the baking dish and turn to coat with butter. Cover and bake, meaty side down, at 400 degrees for 30 minutes. Combine 1/4 c melted butter, lemon juice and honey. After the chicken pieces have cooked for 30 minutes, turn the pieces over. Pour the sauce over the chicken. Bake uncovered for an additional 25-30 minutes or until chicken is done. 4-6 servings.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Omurice (Japanese Omelet Rice)</name><contributor>Fong Yi, Tan</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Omurice is a very popular dish in Japan.</description><spices>pepper</spices><source>http://japanesefood.about.com/od/rice/r/omurice.htm</source><rating>Bland</rating><ingredients>4 cups steamed Japanese rice
1/2 lb. chicken breast
1 green peppers, chopped
4 white mushrooms, sliced
1/2 onion, chopped
salt and pepper to season
4 Tbsp. ketchup
vegetable oil for frying
8 eggs</ingredients><directions>Cook steamed rice. Cut chicken into small pieces. Chop green pepper and onion. Slice mushrooms thinly.
Heat vegetable oil in a large skillet and saute chicken. Add onion, mushrooms, and green pepper in the
skillet and saute together until softened. Add steamed rice in the pan and stir-fry together. Sprinkle
some salt and pepper. Stop the heat and add ketchup and mix well. Set the seasoned rice aside. Heat 1 tsp
of vegetable oil in a large skillet. Beat two eggs in a small bowl and pour the egg in the skillet.
Quickly spread the egg and make a round omelet. Place 1/4 of the seasoned rice in the middle of the omelet
and fold top and bottom sides of omelet over the rice. Cover the frying pan with a plate and turn them over
to place the omerice in the plate. Repeat this process to make four omelet rice. Put some ketchup on top of
omurice just before serving.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Cake</name><contributor>Martin Kugler</contributor><category>Desert</category><description>The cake is a lie.  If you don't get the joke then you should play the game  What did you expect from someone in the game development stream?</description><spices>Rhubarb</spices><source>Portal</source><rating>Delicious</rating><ingredients>1 18.25 ounce package chocolate cake mix
1 can prepared coconut pecan frosting
3/4 cup vegetable oil
4 large eggs
1 cup semi-sweet chocolate chips
3/4 cups butter or margarine
1 2/3 cups granulated sugar
Two cups all purpose flower
Garnishes such as:
Fish shaped crackers
Fish shaped candies
Fish shaped solid waste
Fish shaped dirt
Fish shaped ethyl benzene
Pull and peel licorice
Fish shaped organic compounds
Sediment shaped sediment
Candy coated peanut butter pieces shaped like fish
1 cup lemon juice
Alpha resins
Unsaturated polyester resin
Fiberglass surface resins
Volatile malted milk impoundments
9 large egg yolks
12 medium geosynthetic membranes
1 cup granulated sugar
2 cups rhubard, sliced
2/3 cups granulated rhubarb
1 tablespoon all-purpose rhubarb
1 teaspoon grated orange rhubarb
3 tablespoons rhubarb, on fire
1 cross borehole electro-magnetic imaging rhubarb
2 tablespoons rhubarb juice
Cordless electric needle injector
Injector needle driver
Injector needle gun
Cranial caps</ingredients><directions>Mix it; Cook it; Garnish it; Let sit for 2-3 hours in a cool dry environment; Eat with mouth</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Chilli Chicken</name><contributor>Pragash Siva</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a Spicy Sri Lankan side dish, and can be used to eat it with rice or noodles.</description><spices>Green Chilies</spices><source>Sri Lankan</source><rating>Hot</rating><ingredients>500-600gms. boneless chicken (cut into1-inch cubes)
2 tbsp Soy sauce
1 egg
2 tbsp corn flour / corn starch
5-6 green chilies (finely chopped)
1 tsp garlic paste
Salt To Taste
1/2 tsp white pepper powder to taste
1 tsp sugar
A pinch of ajinomoto (optional)
2 cups chicken stock / water
1 tbsp cooking oil
Oil to fry
spring onions for garnishing</ingredients><directions>Take 1tbsp Soy sauce, 1tbsp corn flour, salt, egg in a bowl and marinate chicken pieces in the the mixture for about 10-15 minutes.
Heat oil and deep fry the marinated chicken pieces till golden brown.
Now in a separate wok heat 1 tbsp oil and add garlic paste and green chilies and saut? for few seconds.
Add 2 cups of chicken broth or water. Bring to boil and add sugar, pepper powder, salt , ajinomoto and remaining Soya sauce.
Add fried chicken pieces to it and cook for few minutes.
Dissolve the remaining corn flour in 1/2 cup water and add to the curry stirring constantly to avoid lumps. Cook for 2-3 minutes.
Serve chilli chicken hot garnished with chopped spring onions. Goes well with Naan, Chappathi, Roti and fried rice.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Banana Chocolate Chip Muffin</name><contributor>Ryan Moore</contributor><category>Snack</category><description>Banana flavoured muffins
with chocolate chips. Self explanatory!</description><spices>None</spices><source>Sister</source><rating>Sweet</rating><ingredients>Dry Ingredients:

2        cups flour
1/4     cup white sugar
2        teaspoons baking powder
1        teaspoon baking soda
1        pinch of salt
1        cup chocolate chips

Wet Ingredients:

2        cups mashed bananas (3 or 4)
1/2     cup melted butter
1/4     cup milk
2        eggs</ingredients><directions>In large bowl, mix all dry ingredients.  Add chocolate chips last.  In
small bowl, blend all wet ingredients together. Then add your banana
mixture to your flour mixture and stir just until the 2 mixtures are
blended. Don't overmix.
Grease muffin cups with small amount of oil on paper towel to prevent
sticking.  Fill cups 3/4 full.
Bake at 350 degrees for approx. 25 minutes or until muffins bounce back
when touched on top.
Enjoy!</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Best-ever brownies</name><contributor>Matthew Sean Brett</contributor><category>Dessert</category><description>Yummy brownies</description><spices>cocoa powder, salt, granulated sugar</spices><source>http://recipes.chatelaine.com/recipe2/article.jsp?recipeId=10273</source><rating>Good</rating><ingredients>1 cup(250 mL) whole hazelnuts, skin-on or blanched whole almonds (optional)
1 cup(250 mL) all-purpose flour1/4 cup(50 mL) cocoa powder
1/4 tsp(1 mL) salt6 oz(168 g) semi-sweet chocolate, about 6 squares
1/2 cup(125 mL) unsalted butter
3 eggs
1 cup(250 mL) granulated sugar
2 tsp(10 mL) vanilla</ingredients><directions>1. Preheat oven to 325F (160C). Spread nuts out on a baking ;
sheet. Toast until lightly golden and fragrant, 8 to 12 min. ;
Stir halfway through. Leave oven on. If using hazelnuts, wrap ;
in a kitchen towel and let steam for 1 min. Then rub hazelnuts;
in towel to remove skins. When nuts are completely cool, coarsely chop.;
2. Meanwhile, coat or spray an 8-in. (2-L) square baking dish with oil. ;
In a small bowl, using a fork, stir flour with cocoa and salt. Using a ;
serrated knife, coarsely chop chocolate. Place in a medium-size bowl ;
along with butter.  ;
3. Microwave chocolate and butter on medium until almost melted, ;
about 3 min. Use a rubber spatula to stir chocolate halfway through ;
microwaving. Then stir until smooth. Or place chocolate and butter ;
in a medium saucepan and set over low heat. Stir constantly until ;
melted. Set aside to cool. ;
4. In a large bowl, whisk eggs, then sugar and vanilla. Using a spatula, ;
scrape in cooled chocolate mixture, then stir until evenly mixed. ;
Gradually stir in flour mixture, just until almost mixed. ;
(Overmixing toughens brownies.) Stir in nuts until evenly distributed. ;
Spread batter in baking dish. Smooth top. ;
5. Bake until edges are firm and middle is set, 35 to 45 min. ;
Don't overbake. (A toothpick inserted in the centre may have chocolatey ;
crumbs clinging to it.) Remove pan to a rack and cool. Cut into squares. ;
Brownies will keep well, covered, at room temperature for up to 3 days or ;
in the freezer up to 1 month. ;</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Gingerbread Cookies</name><contributor>Eva Demers-Brett</contributor><category>Dessert</category><description>A very tasty gingerbread recipe great for making holiday cookies.</description><spices>Ginger
Nutmeg
Cloves
Cinnamon</spices><source>http://allrecipes.com</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>6 cups all-purpose flour
1 tablespoon baking powder
1 tablespoon ground ginger
1 teaspoon ground nutmeg
1 teaspoon ground cloves
1 teaspoon ground cinnamon
1 cup shortening, melted and cooled slightly
1 cup molasses
1 cup packed brown sugar
1/2 cup water
1 egg
1 teaspoon vanilla extract</ingredients><directions>1. Sift together the flour, baking powder, ginger, nutmeg, cloves, 	and cinnamon; set aside.

2. In a medium bowl, mix together the shortening, molasses, brown 	sugar, water, egg, and vanilla until smooth. Gradually stir in the 	dry ingredients, until they are completely absorbed. Divide dough 	into 3 pieces, pat down to 1 1/2 inch thickness, wrap in plastic 	wrap, and refrigerate for at least 3 hours.

3. Preheat oven to 350 degrees F (175 degrees C). On a lightly 	floured surface, roll the dough out to 1/4 inch thickness. Cut 	into desired shapes with cookie cutters. Place cookies 1 inch 	apart onto an ungreased cookie sheet.

4. Bake for 10 to 12 minutes in the preheated oven. When the 	cookies are done, they will look dry, but still be soft to the 	touch. Remove from the baking sheet to cool on wire racks. When 	cool, the cookies can be frosted with the icing of your choice.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Chicken Fettuccini Alfredo</name><contributor>Tomiwa Odetoyinbo</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Meal to be prepared is Chicken Fettucci Alfredo.It is a creamy cheesy Alfredo dish."
Preparation time:30mimutes."
Cook Time : 30 minutes."
Ready in: 1hour."</description><spices>white pepper</spices><source>allrecipes.com</source><rating>****</rating><ingredients>6 skinless, boneless chicken breast halves - cut into cubes"
6 tablespoons butter, divided "
4 cloves garlic, minced, divided"
1 tablespoon Italian seasoning"
1 pound fettuccini pasta"
1 onion, diced "
1 (8 ounce) package sliced mushrooms"
1/3 cup all-purpose flour"
1 tablespoon salt "
3/4 teaspoon ground white pepper"
3 cups milk "
1 cup half-and-half "
3/4 cup grated Parmesan cheese "
8 ounces shredded Colby-Monterey Jack cheese"
3 roma (plum) tomatoes, diced "
1/2 cup sour cream "
"1)In a large skillet over medium heat combine chicken, 2 tablespoons butter, garlic and Italian seasoning.
Cook until chicken is no longer pink inside. Remove from skillet and set aside.
2)Bring a large pot of lightly salted water to a boil. Add pasta and cook for 8 to 10 minutes or until al dente; drain.
3)Meanwhile, melt 4 tablespoons butter in the skillet. Saute onion, 2 tablespoons garlic and mushrooms until onions are transparent.
Stir in flour, salt and pepper; cook 2 minutes. Slowly add milk and half-and-half, stirring until smooth and creamy.
Stir in Parmesan and Colby-Monterey Jack cheeses; stir until cheese is melted. Stir in chicken mixture, tomatoes and sour cream.
After which fettuccini is ready to be served!!." );</ingredients><directions>null</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Hot 'n' Spicy Buffalo Chicken Salad</name><contributor>Michael de Grasse</contributor><category>Salad</category><description>If you like Buffalo Chicken Wings, you'll love this take on it.</description><spices>Salt and Pepper</spices><source>allrecipes.com</source><rating>Hot</rating><ingredients>1/3 cup butter, melted
1/3 cup Louisiana-style hot sauce
3 large skinless, boneless chicken breast halves - cut into 1 inch cubes
salt and pepper
1 tablespoon vegetable oil
2 heads romaine lettuce, chopped
1/3 cup blue cheese dressing
1/4 cup crumbled blue cheese
1 tablespoon salad seasoning mix</ingredients><directions>Whisk together the melted butter, hot sauce,
and salad seasoning in a small bowl. Set aside.
Season cubed chicken with salt and pepper.
Heat a large skillet over high heat, and
pour in the vegetable oil. Just before the oil starts
to smoke, add the chicken. Cook to brown evenly,
about 3 minutes. Reduce heat to low, and pour in the reserved sauce.
Simmer until chicken is cooked through and
no longer pink, about 5 minutes.
Toss together the lettuce, blue cheese
dressing, and blue cheese in a large bowl.
Top salad with chicken, and serve.
Make 4 servings.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Bacalhau (Cod Fish)</name><contributor>Matthew Cabral</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Traditional portuguese recipe.  The word bacalhau in portuguese means cod, this main dish is traditionaly found friday nights in portuguese's homes.</description><spices>Fine ground pepper</spices><source>Portuguese recipe</source><rating>Not Spicy</rating><ingredients>1 lb. of salt cod ( most times found in little wooden boxes)
5 to 6 large potatoes
2 large onions, sliced
1 green peppers, sliced into slivers
3 hard-boiled eggs, sliced
4 cloves of garlic
black olives, those sliced ones are real good
black pepper to taste
2 tablespoons of parsley, chopped fine if fresh
1 tablespoon of vinegar or the juice of one lemon</ingredients><directions>1 lb. of salt cod ( most times found in little wooden boxes) 5 to 6 large potatoes 2 large onions, sliced 1 green peppers, sliced into slivers 3 hard-boiled eggs, sliced 4 cloves of garlic black olives, those sliced ones are real good black pepper to taste 2 tablespoons of parsley, chopped fine if fresh 1 tablespoon of vinegar or the juice of one lemon Just a side note here that you might want to add either a 1/2 cup of red or white wine. Soak cod fish overnight. Boil the cod fish the next day in unsalted water for 15 min. Flake fish and set aside. Boil potatoes, slice and set aside. Slice onion, peppers, crush garlic and saut? in olive oil. In large casserole add a layer as follows, potatoes, then fish, sliced hard-eggs, onion, peppers, garlic. Sprinkle olives and parsley. Pour olive oil over the entire casserole. Cover and bake at 350 degrees for a 1/2 hour in a 3 qt. casserole dish.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Banana Caramel Toast</name><contributor>Shintaro Hagiwara</contributor><category>Breakfast</category><description>the sweet breakfast that goes well with coffee. It gives you the energy to start up the day.</description><spices>Cinnamon</spices><source>http://cookpad.com/</source><rating>sweet</rating><ingredients>1 sliced bread 1 banana 5g butter 1+2/3tbs sugar 1tbs water cinnamon</ingredients><directions>1. slice the banana, lightly toast the bread 2. put sugar and water into the pan, stir then put on medium heat until it gets thickened and until the color changes to caramel 3.put banana and butter into the pan, put on the toast and shake some cinnamon on top</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Mini Crab Bites</name><contributor>Aaron Leblanc</contributor><category>Appetizer</category><description>The crab mix itself is delicious, just crab meat with bits of corn and onion,
then presented in tiny portions in 'spoons' of slightly bitter endive leaves.</description><spices>cayenne pepper</spices><source>Home Recipe</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>1/2 cup corn
1/4 cup finely chopped red onion
1/4 cup mayonnaise
1 tablespoon frozen orange juice concentrate
1 teaspoon lemon zest
1 tablespoon lemon juice
1/2 teaspoon ground cumin
1/8 teaspoon cayenne pepper
4 teaspoons fresh tarragon, chopped
Salt &amp; pepper to taste
8 ounces fresh or canned crab</ingredients><directions>Mix all crab mix ingredients except the crab. Taste and adjust seasoning. Stir in the crab. (Stop here if making in advance, as much as 24 hours before serving.) Place a small spoonful of crab in the 'bowl' of each endive leaf. Arrange on platter and serve immediately.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Sambar</name><contributor>Sagenthar Sinnadurai</contributor><category>Spicy Indian/Thamil Foods</category><description>A tamil food called 'Sambar' in native language Tamil. It is great to have with rice. Be careful, it is spicy.</description><spices>Dhania Spicy Powder</spices><source>http://www.kuttyjapan.com/tamilrecipes/</source><rating>Hot</rating><ingredients>4-5 strips tamarind soaked for 5 minutes (paste or pulp may also be used),
1 tbsp. jaggery or sugar,
2 tbsp. sambar masala,
1/4 tsp. turmeric powder,
1 tsp. dhania powder,
1 tsp. red chilli powder,
1/2 tsp. each cumin and mustard seeds,
3 whole red chillies,
1 stalk curry leaves,
4 onions,
1/2 cup pumpkin or bottle gourd boiled and cubed,
1 large tomato,
1 tbsp. chopped coriander leaves,
2-3 brinjals,
1 drumstick,
100gms of chopped mixed vegetables, potato, peas, cauliflower, carrot,
2-3 flakes garlic,
salt to taste,
2 tbsp. oil</ingredients><directions>Add tamarind, 1/2 tomato &amp; 1 onion chopped, to the dal.;

Pressure cook till dal is done very soft. (Approx. 3 or 4 whistles);

Remove dal and beat with a whisk or churner till smooth.;

Grind to a paste, 1 onion, 1/4 tomato, jaggery, garlic, all dry masalas.;

Chop the remaining onion and tomato to medium or fine pieces.;

Heat oil, add seeds, curry leaves and allow to splutter.;

Add onion, brinjal, pumpkin, tomato, drumstick, chopped vegetables and stir fry for 2-3 minutes.;

Add paste, and cook for further 2 minutes.;

Add dal and bring to a boil on high.;

Add enough water to get sambar consistency.;

Check and adjust masalas as required.;
Simmer for 12-15 minutes on low, till the aroma exudes.;

Add chopped coriander before serving.;</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Lemon Herb Chicken</name><contributor>100767446</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a simple, quick and delicious dish. All you need are a few spices and, of course, the chicken! The amount of spices are completely up to you. You can add more or less according to your taste. Enjoy!"</description><spices>oregano
black pepper</spices><source>Family recipe</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>2 skinless, boneless chicken breast halves
1 lemon
salt and pepper to taste
1 tablespoon olive oil
1 pinch dried oregano
2 sprigs fresh parsley, for garnish</ingredients><directions>Cut lemon in half, and squeeze juice from 1/2 lemon on chicken. Season with salt to taste. Let sit while you heat oil in a small skillet over medium low heat. When oil is hot, put chicken in skillet. As you saute chicken, add juice from other 1/2 lemon, pepper to taste, and oregano. Saute for 5 to 10 minutes each side, or until juices run clear. Serve with parsley for garnish.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Kung Pao Chicken</name><contributor>Ning Chang</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional Chinese recipe. I found it from one Chinese guy's blog. It should taste spicy. You'd better eat it with rice.</description><spices>Dried red chili</spices><source>Chinese recipe</source><rating>Very Good</rating><ingredients>1 lb. boned, skinned chicken breasts - cubed
3 Tbls. soy sauce - divided
1 1/2 Tbls. cornstarch mixed with 1 1/2 Tbls. cold water
1 Tbls. dry sherry
1 Tbls. granulated sugar
1 tsp. cornstarch
1/2 tsp. salt
1 tsp. sesame oil
3 1/2 Tbls. vegetable oil - divided
1/2 cup unsalted roasted peanuts
4-8 dried red chili peppers - chopped
1 slice peeled, fresh ginger - chopped
1 clove garlic - sliced</ingredients><directions>Combine chicken, 1 Tbls. soy sauce, and cornstarch/water mixture; allow to marinate for 30 minutes.
Combine 2 Tbls. soy sauce, sherry, sugar, cornstarch, salt, and sesame oil; set aside.
In a hot wok, stir-fry the peanuts in 1 1/2 Tbls. vegetable oil until golden brown, remove peanuts from wok, and set aside.
Fill wok with vegetable oil for frying and heat to 350 degrees. Carefully slide the chicken into the wok, piece by piece, and fry for 1 minute.
Remove chicken from oil and drain on a brown paper bag. Remove oil from wok.
In hot wok, stir-fry the red peppers in 2 Tbls. vegetable oil until they turn dark. Add ginger, garlic, and chicken to the wok and fry, stirring constantly. Stir the prepared sauce and add to the wok. Stir and cook wok contents until the sauce is thickened. Stir in peanuts and serve.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Sweet Victorian Shrimp</name><contributor>Adrian Murphy</contributor><category>Side dish</category><description>This is an old recipe originally found in a 1940s cookbook, modified
after years of eating. Not spicey by any means, it's best combined with
sauce of personal preference.</description><spices>Jamaican Pepper
Vanilla</spices><source>1940s Cookbook</source><rating>Sweet</rating><ingredients>2 lb. med. shrimp peeled and deveined
1 small onion minced finely
6 tablespoon butter
3/4 lb. mushrooms
salt and fresh ground pepper to taste
1 cup sour cream
1/4 cup cream
1 tablespoon lemon juice
3 teaspoon vanilla
1 tablespoon ground jamaican pepper
1 Tbs. flour</ingredients><directions>Saut? shrimp and onions in 6 Tbs. butter until shrimp are pink. Add mushrooms
and cook 5 min. Add remaining remaining butter, flour, vanilla, salt and pepper.
Stir in sour cream. Serve hot over rice flavored with juice of 1 large lemon.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Grilled Chicken Thighs</name><contributor>Vijitharan Vivekanandarajah</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Based on a Sri Lankan recipe for chicken thighs, and canalso be made with chicken breasts.</description><spices>Pepper, Garam Masala</spices><source>Sri Lankan Recipe</source><rating>WAY TOO HOT</rating><ingredients>8 skinless, bone-in chicken thighs
1 teaspoon ground cumin
4 garlic cloves, crushed
2 tablespoons grated fresh ginger
salt
2 tablespoons fresh lemon juice
1 teaspoon finely grated lemon zest
1/2 cup plain Greek yogurt
1/2 teaspoon cayenne pepper
1/4 teaspoon Garam Masala
Melted butter for basting</ingredients><directions>With sharp knife, make several shallow slashes in each
chicken thigh; transfer to a large baking
dish. sprinkle the thighs with cumin, garlic, ginger and 1 teaspoon of salt.
Rub the seasonings into the meat. Refrigerate for 1 hour. In a small ball
combine the lemon juice and lemon zest with the yogurt, cayenne pepper and
Garam masala to make a marinade. Pour the marinade over the chicken thighs and
turn to coat them. Let the chicken in the marinade at room temperature for 1 hour.
Light a grill. Remove the chicken from the marinade. Lightly brush the chicken with
butter and transfer to the grill. Grill over moderate heat for 22 - 25 minutes, turning
and brushing occasionally, until chicken is done.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Lao Egg Pancake</name><contributor>Jeffery Luangpakham</contributor><category>Side Dish/Brunch</category><description>This is a traditional Laotian dish, a quick and easy meal to serve. Usually eaten with rice.</description><spices>Red Peppers</spices><source>My parents taught me.</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>1 pancake: 2 eggs, 2 teaspoons fish sauce, 1 dice green onion, few dashes black pepper, 1 diced red pepper</ingredients><directions>Crack the 2 eggs into a bowl. Add in the rest of the ingredients. Mix the ingredients thoroughly. Pour the mixed ingredients into a frying pan with heated cooking oil in it. Fry the egg pancake until both sides are slightly tinted brown.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Lobster Madness</name><contributor>xuyang zhu</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>this is a real cantonese styled lobster recipe. rich in flavor.</description><spices>salted black beans, garlic</spices><source>chinesefood.about.com</source><rating>a very fancy dish</rating><ingredients>tablespoon paprika
2 lobster tails (about 1 pound each)
1 teaspoon salt
2 tablespoons flour
1 clove garlic, minced
1 tablespoon salted black beans, (also called fermented black beans) pounded and soaked in 1 tablespoon water
1 tablespoon ginger, chopped fine
1 scallion, chopped fine
1/4 pound ground pork
2 tablespoons sherry
1 tablespoon light soy sauce
1 cup chicken stock
1 tablespoon cornstarch, dissolved in 2 tablespoons water
2 scallions, cut into 1-inch pieces
1 egg, beaten
2 to 4 cups oil for deep-frying and stir-frying</ingredients><directions>Cut each lobster tail in half. Wash thoroughly. Drain. Cut tails into pieces 1 1/2 inches in length, leaving shells on.

Sprinkle 1/2 teaspoon of salt and the flour on lobster.

Mix garlic with black bean mixture in a bowl. Stir well.

Heat oil for deep-frying to smoking hot. Put in lobster pieces. Deep-fry until shells are red. Drain. Remove.

Reheat 1 tablespoon of oil in wok. Stir-fry black bean mixture 30 seconds. Remove.

Reheat 2 tablespoons of oil in wok. Stir-fry ginger and scallion until there is an aroma, about 30 seconds. Add pork. Stir-fry on high heat until color changes. Add 1 tablespoon of sherry, soy sauce, black bean mixture, and stock. Bring to boil.

Add lobster to meat mixture. Add 1 tablespoon sherry. Cover. Cook 3 minutes.

Remove lid. Bring to boil. Thicken gravy with dissolved cornstarch. Season with 1/2 teaspoon salt. Add scallions. Slowly pour in beaten egg. Stir-fry about 10 seconds. Remove.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Eelam Chicken Sensation</name><contributor>Tharsan.S</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional Malaysia recipe. I found it from an international
cooking book. It should taste spicy and a little bit sour. You can also use
canned coconut milk to substitute coconut and milk.</description><spices>Garlic, Hot pepper, Dried red chili</spices><source>Sri Lankan recipe</source><rating>WAY TOO HOT</rating><ingredients>12 x Boneless-Skinless Chicken Thighs (approximately 1.50 lbs / 675g)
2 Ginger
2 Bell pepper
2 tbsp Flour (Approximately)
1 1/2 cups Basmati Rice
3 cups Water
2 tbsp Cornstarch
2/3 cups Brown Sugar
1/4 cup Soy Sauce</ingredients><directions>Take out equipment and ingredients. Pre-heat oven to 400 degree F.Unroll chicken thighs and place in a large cake or lasagna pan.
You may need to squish them together. Brush all the thighs with water and sprinkle all the thighs evenly with flour.
Place in preheated oven for 30 minutes. Meanwhile: Combine rice and water together in a microwave-safe pot with lid. Set aside until timer rings for chicken.
Combine the following in a bowl in this order; cornstarch, sugar, gradually whisk in soy sauce, and water. Add ginger,pepper and red chili.
When timer rings for chicken pour all over lifting the thighs to completely coat.Reset timer for another 20 minutes.
Microwave rice on high for 10 minutes, then on medium an additional 10 minutes. Let stand. Sliver peppers in a colander. Toss and place in a serving bowl.
When timer rings, it's ready to go. This sauce is yummy on rice and there is lots of it. Make 4 servings.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>THE COLONATOR</name><contributor>Thomas Humphreys</contributor><category>Main dish</category><description>I was bored and wanted to make a mess of the
kitchen, my colon, and the toilet. The base idea was taken
off the back of a chili mix packet bought at Wal-market.
Trail and error has built it into the chili it is today.
This dish serves three. It's suggested that this dish
consumed with a side of bread. The great thing about this
recipe is that everything used to make this dish can be
purchased in the form of a preservable.</description><spices>Cayenne Pepper, powdered
Chili Powder Mix, Bulk Barn
Banna Pepper Chucks, Bicks
Banna Pepper Chucks Brine, Bicks
Paprika, powdered</spices><source>Wal-mart + My brain (The creative side)</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>1/2 tablespoon of basil
1 teaspoon of cayenne pepper
1 teaspoon of paprika powder
1 tablespoon of chili powder mix
1 cup of banana pepper chucks, bicks
1/4 cup of banana pepper chucks brine, bicks
1/2 cup of diced mushrooms
1 cup of diced onion
1 cup of diced tomatoes
1 cup of cheese, marble
2 cups of mixed beans
3 cups of tomato pasta
1 can of Mixed Beans
12 chicken nuggets</ingredients><directions>This recipe requires you to have a large high brimmed sauce
pan. Attempting this recipe with anything else runs the risk of over
flowing or improper results. It?s also suggested you make use of an oil
splatter guard. There?s no risk of oil splatter, this device just
prevents against sauce splatter making clean up easier.

1) In a toast oven or oven, undercook chicken nuggets by 20%. The
nuggets should be cooked but not hard. They?ll appear soft or mushy. If
the nuggets ready anytime before their needed, remove them and dice them
into quarters.

2) While you're waiting for the chicken nuggets to heat up base a sauce
pan with a 1/8 a cup of oil and let the oil melt with the stove at 50% of
its maximum heat. Prepare the mixed beans, diced onions, diced tomatoes,
diced mushrooms, and diced banana pepper chunks. Turn the stove to 60%
and add the previously prepared ingredients.
3) Ready your tomato pasta, spices, and banana pepper brink. Give the
original ingredients 6 or 7 minutes to cook. Dump the tomato pasta on
first. Follow the pasta with the spices and top it off with the brine.
Stir ingredients so that the pasta sauce darkens and then cover it with
the splatter guard.

4) By now the chicken nuggets should be ready. Prepare then and the cup
of cheese. The cheese should be added in smaller portions so that it?s
easier to melt. Give the imprudence from the third stage 3 minutes at
the most before adding these ingredients.

5) Increase the temperature to 80% for 9 to 10 minutes and stir every
1 to 2 minutes. If you find build up appearing on sauce pans surface,
mix that back in. Draw the thicker chucks to the center and let the
softer bits or liquids cook around the edge. This recipe serves three.
As mentioned about, it?s suggested you give this meal a side of bread</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Microwave Caramel Popcorn</name><contributor>Thomas McMahon</contributor><category>Snack</category><description>This recipe yields 4 quarts of caramel popcorn. Along with the ingredients
all you need is a microwave oven to complete this recipe. Meant for a quick and delicious snack.</description><spices>none</spices><source>Friend's microwave cookbook</source><rating>not spicy</rating><ingredients>1/4 cup corn syrup
1/4 cup butter
1/2 cup brown sugar
1/4 teaspoon baking soda
4 quarts popcorn (16 cups)</ingredients><directions>In a small glass bowl, add the corn syrup, margarine, and brown sugar.
Cook on High for 3 minutes. Stir. Add the baking soda to mixture and stir until smooth.
Cook for another 30 seconds on High. Stir.
Put the popcorn in a large bowl. Pour over popcorn with the hot mixture and mix until well coated.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>SnowBoarder Pork Tenderloin</name><contributor>Jonathon Slonosky</contributor><category>Main Course</category><description>This recipe is a favorite in the family and among friends that have come over and were blessed by its flavour.For cooking on barbeque, heat to approximately 400F, and cook for 20 minutes, turning after 10.</description><spices>Bay Leaves
Garlic
Dried Thyme</spices><source>Newspaper</source><rating>Not hot, but flavourful</rating><ingredients>2-? 	pounds pork tenderloin (2 tenderloins)
?	cup Dijon-style mustard
1	tablespoon pressed garlic (4 large or 6 small cloves)
?	cup best-quality dry red wine
?	cup extra-virgin olive oil
1	tablespoon dried thyme, crushed
?	bay leaf
?	teaspoon freshly ground pepper
?	teaspoon granulated sugar</ingredients><directions>Trim fat and ?silver skin? from tenderloins.  Rinse, pat dry, and set aside.  Place all the other ingredients in a glass pan and whisk together well.  Place tenderloins in the pan, and turn them to cover with the marinade, cover the pan with plastic wrap, and place in the refrigerator for 6 hours, or overnight.

Thirty minutes before you plan to roast the pork, remove the tenderloins from the refrigerator to come to room temperature.

Preheat the oven to 400oF.  Use a roasting pan with a rack; line the bottom of the pan with foil and place the tenderloins on the rack.  Roast the tenderloins until an instant read thermometer inserted in the center registers 140oF ? about 20 to 25 minutes.  Do not overcook the pork; the center should still be pink when served.  Remove from the oven and slice.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Moroccan stew</name><contributor>Ahmad Darwish</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional Vegeterian Moroccan recipe. I learned it from my mother.</description><spices>salt,pepper, Cinnamon sticks, cumin.</spices><source>Mom</source><rating>5 stars</rating><ingredients>1 onion, chopped
1 garlic cloves, finely chopped
1 teaspoon cumin
2 cinnamon stick
1 teaspoon pepper
3 tablespoons olive oil
1 teaspoon salt
1 whole squash, cut cubes
2 whole potatoes cut into cubes
250g og garbanzo beans
2 tomatoes
1/4 glass of lemon juice
1 glass of chicken broth
1 3/4 glass of water</ingredients><directions>Heat olive oil in a large covered saucepan or Dutch oven over medium heat, until oil is hot but not smoking.         Drop in the onion, garlic, cumin, cinnamon stick, and salt and pepper.
Cook and stir for 5 minutes, until onion is tender and translucent.
Stir in the butternut squash and potato cubes, broth, garbanzo beans, and tomatoes, and bring the mixture to a       boil.
Reduce heat, cover the pot, and simmer about 20 minutes, stirring occasionally, until the squash and potatoes        are tender.
Remove the stew from heat, and stir in the olives and lemon zest.
In a large saucepan, bring 1 3/4 cup water to a boil. Stir in couscous. Cover and remove from the heat; let          stand for 5 minutes. Fluff with a fork; cool.
Serve stew over cooked couscous.
Garnish each serving with a dollop of yogurt and a sprinkle of cilantro leaves.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Beef Goulash</name><contributor>Corey Fee</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>A great idea for those cold nights when all you want is a warm tasty stew.</description><spices>Paprika, Pepper, Garlic Cloves</spices><source>Family CookBook</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>2 tbsp. oil
3 onions, sliced
3 tbsp. paprika
Salt and pepper
2 garlic cloves, minced
3 lb. beef stew meat
Two 16 oz. cans tomatoes, drained
1/3 cup sour cream (optional)</ingredients><directions>1.  In a heavy pot, heat the oil. Add the onions, cover the pot and cook
for 10 minutes, until the onions are lightly browned. Stir in the
paprika, garlic, salt and pepper. Cook for 1 minute, remove contents
of pot with a slotted spoon and set aside.

2.  Turn up the heat and brown the beef in the oil left in the pot.
Return the onions to the pot with the tomatoes; cover and simmer
about 2 hours, until the meat is tender. Serve as is, or remove from
the heat and stir in the sour cream. (Do not bring to a boil or the
sauce will curdle.) Makes 6 servings.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Beef Bourgon Youl</name><contributor>Kyle Zavitz</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Rice, meat, sauce and Mushrooms. Fantastic, and good for you, too.</description><spices/><source>Homemade</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>2 can white mushrooms
4 cans roast beef
1/2 onion, sauteed
2 can gravy
4 cups rice</ingredients><directions>Use a medium-sized pot, to boil water. Once boiling, drop rice in for 15 minutes. Stir frequently.
Using a turkey pot, at the same time, bake the mixture of mushrooms, onion, gravy, and beef for 25 minutes at 425 degrees.
Serve hot - with the turkey pot mix on rice. Serves 8.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Peanutbuttor Sandwich</name><contributor>MICKEY YUEN</contributor><category>Desperate Meal</category><description>A weird Sandwich that has peanut, ketcup and salt together.</description><spices>None</spices><source>General Knowledge</source><rating>Weird and not reccomanded</rating><ingredients>2 Pieces of bread
1/8 cup of ketchup
1 gram of salt</ingredients><directions>1) Get a knife and spread ketchup on one piece of bread
2) add salt to peice of bread that the ketchup is on
3) put the peices of bread together
4) eat it
5) If you get sick, barf into the a bag</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Slightly Fried Dumpling with Pork</name><contributor>Xu Guo</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional Chinese recipe. I found it from internet. It should taste  a little bit salted. And it taste good.</description><spices>soy sauce sugar salt</spices><source>Chinese recipe</source><rating>****</rating><ingredients>500 grams (1.1 lb) wheat flour ,250 grams (0.55 lb) minced pork ,5 grams (5/6 tsp) salt, 5 grams (1 tsp) sugar, 5 grams (1 1/4 tsp) MSG, 10 grams (1 1/2 tsp) soy sauce, 15 grams (1 tbsp) cooking wine, 5 grams (1/6 oz) finely cut scallions, 5 grams (1/6 oz) chopped ginger, 150 grams (12 tbsp) cooking oil.</ingredients><directions>1. Mix the minced pork well with the salt, sugar, MSG, soy sauce, cooking wine, scallions and ginger. Add 50 g (3 tbsp) of water and stir in one direction till you feel the sense of elasticity, combine coconut and milk; bring to a boil. 2. Mix the flour with 200 g (2/5 cup) of boiling water, make the dough into long and round shape and reduce to 40 pieces. Press and roll into wrappings each about 6 centimeters (2.4 inches) in diameter. Put in the filling, fold and wrap into crescent shapes, 3. Put the cooking oil into the frying pan, heat and when the oil is about 135-200oC (275-390oF), place the raw dumplings in. Heat for one minute, sprinkle 100 g (6 tbsp) of water and put on the pan cover. Use strong fire to heat five minutes. When the water disappears, the dumplings are ready. (It may take several repetitions to cook all the 40 dumplings because of the size of the pan.)</directions></recipe><recipe><name>The tomato fries the egg</name><contributor>Xu Guo</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional Chinese recipe. I found it from internet. It should taste  a little bit acid and salted. And it taste good.</description><spices>sugar salt</spices><source>Chinese recipe</source><rating>*****</rating><ingredients>Egg 3,Tomato 150 grams,Vegetable oil 4 soupspoon,Salt, monosodium glutamate respectively right amount,Sugar 1 soupspoon.</ingredients><directions>After 1st, burns the tomato cleaning with the boiling water, goes to the skin, goes to the peduncle, the slice is ready to be used. 2nd, infiltrates the egg in the bowl, adds the salt, evenly is ready to be used with the chopsticks full whipping. 3rd, the wok puts the oil 3 soupspoon to burn the heat, puts in the egg in the pot to fry is ripely abundant is ready to be used. 4th, the surplus oil will burn the heat, will get down the tomato piece to stir-fry before stewing fries, puts the salt, the sugar fries the moment, will pour into the egg to turn fries several pots namely to become. When stirs fry system this vegetable, wants the strong fire to be intensive. Although this vegetable is the ordinariest simple dish, but fries quality may know. Is called the cooking technique now at last.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Fried Bitter Melon with Eggs</name><contributor>Xu Guo</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional Chinese recipe. I found it from internet. It should taste  a little bit bitter and salted. And it taste good.</description><spices>oil, salt, gourmet powder,ginger</spices><source>Chinese recipe</source><rating>******</rating><ingredients>bitter melon, eggs, 150 grams Vegetable oil 4 soupspoon,Salt, monosodium glutamate respectively right amount,Sugar 1 soupspoon.</ingredients><directions>1) chop bitter melon into two parts, plunge into boilded water for a short while and take them out. get them sliced 2)churn up the eggs and add some flavors 3)add some veg oil and heat it . Then put the spice in ,wait till fragrant. Pour in egg and continue to stir until egg is just cooked through. Stir in the sliced bitter melon, put some flavor and toss well. then serve promptly.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Sugar Cookies</name><contributor>John Byford</contributor><category>Dessert</category><description>A very simple and sweet dessert that is especially popular over Christmas and during the Holidays (and is Pennsylvania's official cookie).</description><spices>nutmeg</spices><source>Common - family</source><rating>Sweet</rating><ingredients>3 cups flour
1 tsp baking powder
1 tsp baking soda
1/2 tsp salt
1 cup butter
2 eggs
1 1/2 cups sugar
1 tsp vanilla
1 tsp nutmeg</ingredients><directions>Mix the flour, baking powder, baking soda, nutmeg and salt well in bowl. Cut in the cup of butter then beat 2 eggs with the sugar and vanilla. Then add flour to the mixture. Knead and roll into a ball to refridgerate for 1 hour. Roll out, cut and bake at 375 F for 6-11 minutes.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Patties with potatoes</name><contributor>David Krutsko</contributor><category>Side Dish</category><description>This is a traditional Ukrainian recipe that I got by asking
my grandmother. Depending on the ingredients you use and the
temperature you eat it at, the patties should always taste
exceptionally well with a mild hint of sweetness.</description><spices>Black and Red pepper</spices><source>Ukrainian recipe</source><rating>Mild and Tender</rating><ingredients>Dough ball
1 cup hot water
1 cup mayonnaise
Potatoes with friend onion</ingredients><directions>Depending on how many you are making, you want to cut the
dough into small pieces. Flatten out the dough balls with
a roller to get it as thin as possible, try starting from
the center and rolling it out. Place stuffing in the center
with a diameter approximately five to seven centimetres.
Then fold the dough into a semicircle and squeeze it
together so the stuffing doesn?t escape. Finally, fry it
to a crisp golden brown and enjoy.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Chilli Chicken</name><contributor>Abhay Mehta</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is my best friend's specialty. As far as I know, she made it from
scratch, and it models after such dishes from Indian-Chinese (spicy Chinese)
restaurants found in Mississauga, such as Hakka Magic, Eddie's Wok &amp; Roll,
China Palace, etc. It can be made according to your preference of spice, but
spiciest is best. The sauce should be brown and thick and taste amazing.</description><spices>Green Chillies</spices><source>Best friend's specialty recipe</source><rating>Moderately Hot</rating><ingredients>2 teaspoons canola oil
2 small onions, chopped
2 teaspoons garlic paste
1 teaspoons ginger paste
3-5 green chillies, finely chopped
1 1/2 teaspoons Corn Starch
3/4 cup water
3-4 tablespoons soya sauce
1 teaspoon hot sauce
1 large green pepper, chopped in cubes
1 lb (pound) Chicken breast, chopped in cubes.
Salt to taste</ingredients><directions>In a medium pan, add 2 teaspoons of canola oil.
Add 2 teaspoons of garlic paste and 1 teaspoon of ginger paste.
Combine it with the chopped green chillies and the chopped onions, stir
until golden brown. Add the chopped Chicken breast pieces and add 2
tablespoons of soya sauce. Cover the pan until the chicken is tender.
Add the chopped green peppers and add 1 tablespoon of soya sauce. In a
bowl, combine 1 1/2 teaspoons of corn starch powder to 3/4 cup of warm
water. Add the mixture to the chicken. Add salt to taste. Let it simmer
for 3-5 minutes until the sauce thickens. Serve with cooked rice or noodles.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Irish Soda Bread</name><contributor>100780535</contributor><category>Appetiser</category><description>Traditional Irish recipe passed down through my family. Can be served as a snack or an appetiser. Taste is similar to that of a scone.</description><spices>None</spices><source>Irish recipe&gt;</source><rating>Not hot at all</rating><ingredients>4 cups of sifted, all purpose flour, 1/4 cup of granulated sugar, 1 teaspoon of salt, 1 teaspoon of baking powder, 1 teaspoon of baking soda, 2 tablespoons of caraway seeds, 1 1/3 cups of  buttermilk, 1/4 cup of butter, 1 egg (unbeaten), 1 egg yolk (beaten), and 1/2 cup of raisins or currents if desired.</ingredients><directions>In a bowl, sift together the flour, sugar, salt, and baking powder.  Stir in caraway seeds.  Cut butter into small pieces and add to mixture.  Combine buttermilk, egg, and baking soda, and stir into flour mixture.  Add raisins or currents.  Place dough on a floured board.  Knead until dough is smooth.  Form dough into one round loaf - about two inches high.  Use a knife to make a large "X" on the top of the dough.  Brush with egg yolk.  Bake on a greased cooking sheet at 375 degrees F or 191 degrees C, for 70 minutes or until done. Allow to cool. Serve with butter and jam if you wish.  Makes one loaf.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>My Fajitas</name><contributor>Mark Fortney</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is an easy, quick recipe to make that still tastes great.</description><spices>Cumin, Coriander Seed, Chili, Paprika, Cayenne</spices><source>Family</source><rating>Hot</rating><ingredients>1/4 cup olive oil
1/4 cup lemon juice
2 chicken breasts, cut into slices
1 onion
2 peppers of any colour
1 teaspoon cumin
1 teaspoon coriander seed
1/2 teaspoon chili
1/2 teaspoon paprika
1/4 teaspoon cayenne
Tortillas
Optional sides: rice, beans, shredded cheese, salsa, guacamole</ingredients><directions>1. Combine oil, lemon juice and spices in a small bowl.
(Add more or less cayenne depending on how spicy you want them to be)
2. Add chopped raw chicken, mix well, and let rest for a few hours in the fridge.
3. Chop onions and peppers
4. Pour marinated chicken and any of the spices left into a frying pan;
cook at medium heat.
5. When the chicken is fully cooked or close to it, add the onions and peppers. After
the onions are cooked to taste, remove from heat.
6. Serve with warmed tortillas and sides of your choice: rice, beans, shredded cheese, salse, guacamole.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Superbly Grilled Chicken</name><contributor>Stephanie Lodge</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This simple chicken marinade will easily become one of your
summer barbeque favorites! Serve on a bed of rice with mixed veggies.</description><spices>Dried oregano
Garlic Powder
Basil
Salt
Ground Pepper</spices><source>Family recipe</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>16 skinless ,boneless chicken thighs
12 skinless, boneless chicken breasts
1/2 cup of olive oil
4 lemons
2 TBSP garlic powder
2 TBSP dried oregano
1 TBSP basil
1 TBSP salt
1 TBSP ground pepper</ingredients><directions>1. Place chicken in very large bowl or 2 smaller ones. Pour
oil into large measuring cup or bowl. Squeeze about 1 cup of juice
from the lemons. Whisk into oil along with garlic powder, oregano,
basil, salt and pepper. Pour over Chicken. Mix until evenly coated.
Use right away or cover and refrigerate up to one day.
2. Lightly oil grill. Heat BBQ to medium. Remove chicken from
marinade. Grill with lid closed for 8 minutes, then baste chicken
remaining marinade. Turn chicken and continue to grill with lid
closed until chicken feels springy when pressed, 6 to 8 minutes.

For best results, marinate overnight.
Fresh garlic may be used instead of garlic powder but will have to
be strained from marinade before grilling.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Super Swiss Potato Soup</name><contributor>Robert Theoret</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>There was no description that came along with this recipe, but it sounds pretty awesome and self explanatory.</description><spices>Cayenne Pepper
Hot Paprika</spices><source>The Red Cat Cookbook</source><rating>Un-parse-ably Hot</rating><ingredients>tablespoons butter, divided
1 small shallot, finely chopped
1 1/2 lbs idaho potatoes, peeled and quartered (about 2 medium potatoes)
3 cups low sodium chicken broth
3 cups water
1 1/2 cups milk
1 1/2 cups heavy cream
salt, to taste
fresh ground black pepper, to taste
cayenne pepper, to taste
3/4 cup grated gruyere cheese (about 6 ounces)
2 teaspoons hot paprika
2 scallions, white and green parts, finely sliced</ingredients><directions>Melt 2 tablespoons of butter in a heavy soup pot. Saute shallot in butter until translucent and soft, about 3 minutes. Add the potatoes, chicken broth and water. Bring to a boil, then reduce to a             simmer. Cook 15 minutes or until potatoes are soft when poked with a knife-tip. Strain the liquid into a bowl and set aside.

Pass potatoes through a food mill or ricer. Return to soup pot with milk, cream and 1 1/2 cups of cooking liquor. Whisk gently until combined well, but do not overwork the potatoes. Season with salt,         pepper and cayenne to taste, then add remaining 1 tablespoon of butter.

Divide Gruyere equally between four soup bowls. Ladle soup over cheese. Sprinkle with paprika and scallions to garnish.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>A slightly more interesting tuna salad.</name><contributor>Andrew Morris</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is ordinary tuna salad, but spiced up a little.</description><spices>Honey Mustard
Hot Sauce</spices><source>A friend made this for me a few months back.</source><rating>Varies</rating><ingredients>1 can of tuna
Mayonnaise
Relish
Bread</ingredients><directions>Drain the tuna and put it in a bowl.  Add lots of mayonnaise and a couple tablespoons of relish.
Add honey mustard and hot sauce as desired.  Serve on bread as a sandwhich.  Serves 1-2 people.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Fried Wonton</name><contributor>Angela</contributor><category>Appetizer</category><description>It is a type of dumpling commonly found in a number of Chinese cuisines. Wonton is made with a thin ten     centimeter square lye-water pastry wrapper made of wheat flour, water, salt and lye. It is often filled with minced        meat, but vegetarian fillings can be substituted.</description><spices>dark soy sauce</spices><source>Chinese cuisines</source><rating>Wonderful and authentic tasting!</rating><ingredients>4 dried black mushrooms, 1 leaf bok choy, 1 green onion, 1/2 pound ground pork, 1 tablespoon dark soy sauce, 1 teaspoon sesame oil, 1 teaspoon granulated sugar, pinch of salt, 1 egg, lightly beaten, 3 cups oil for deep-frying, 48 wonton wrappers and water</ingredients><directions>Wipe any dirt off the mushrooms. Soak in warm water until softened(20 to 30 minutes). Squeeze out the excess water and chop. Wash and shred the bok choy leaf. Wash and dice the green onion. Mince the ginger until you have 1/2 teaspoons.

In a medium bowl, combine the ground with the dark soy sauce, sesame oil, sugar and salt. Add the lightly beaten egg and the vegetables. This is wonton filling.

Heat the oil to 375 degrees Fahrenheit. While the oil is heating, prepare the wontons. Lay a wonton wrapper in front of you. Place a teaspoon of the filling in the middle. Fold up the wonton so that it resembles a nurse's cap, wetting the edges to seal .

Add the won tons to the hot oil, a few at a time, sliding them in carefully. Deep-fry the wontons in batches until they are golden brown, turning to make sure they brown evenly. Drain on paper towels or a tempura rack if you have one. As with egg rolls, wontons should be served as soon as possible, to ensure they remain crispy. Serve with Sweet and Sour Sauce or red rice wine vinegar.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Mexican Spicy Rice</name><contributor>Brittany Finkelman</contributor><category>Main Course</category><description>This recipe takes about 1 hour to make.  the spices can be altered to make it more/less spicy this recipe was obtained from a cooking class</description><spices>dried oregano, ground cumin, chili powder, ground black pepper</spices><source>hand-out at cooking class</source><rating>medium</rating><ingredients>15ml oil, 1 medium chopped onion, 5ml dried oregano, 5ml ground cumin, 5ml chili powder, 1ml black ground pepper, 125ml white long-grain rice, 185ml vegetable stock, 400ml canned chopped tomatoes with juice, 250ml red canned kidney beans</ingredients><directions>Place onions and oil in medium pot on medium heat.  Cook, stirring until soft.  add herbs and spices.  cook for one more minute.  add rice, stir to coat with oil, add stock, tomatoes with juice and beans.  Bring to a boil, stirring occasionally.  Transfer to a casserole, cover and bake at 350F (180C) for 30 minutes.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Grilled Venison Backstrap</name><contributor>Yernar Suyerbayev</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Tender chunks of venison are marinated twice, and wrapped in thick bacon before being grilled until crispy on the outside. A venison version of Filet Mignon. This is a heavenly use of the best part of a deer. For the BBQ sauce, I prefer hickory flavored.</description><spices>none</spices><source>none</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>null</ingredients><directions>1.   Place chunks of venison into a shallow baking dish, and pour enough apple cider in to cover them. Cover, and refrigerate for 2 hours. Remove, and pat dry. Discard apple cider, and return venison to the dish. Pour barbeque sauce over the chunks, cover, and refrigerate for 2 to 3 more hours.
2. Preheat an outdoor grill for high heat. Charcoal is best, but if you must, use gas. Remove meat from the refrigerator, and let stand for 30 minutes, or until no longer chilled. Wrap each chunk of venison in a slice of bacon, and secure with toothpicks.
3. Brush the grill grate with olive oil when hot, and place venison pieces on the grill so they are not touching. The bacon will kick up some flames, so be ready. Grill, turning occasionally, until the bacon becomes slightly burnt, 15 to 20 minutes. The slower, the better. Dig in, and prepare to want more!</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Mikes Awesome Chicken</name><contributor>Michael Evans</contributor><category>Appetizer</category><description>null</description><spices>Chilli Powder</spices><source>Home</source><rating>Spicy</rating><ingredients>4 chicken breasts
1 cup mayonnaise
1 teaspoon salt
1/2 cup of chopped onions
1/2 cup chopped garlic
1 teaspoon chilli powder</ingredients><directions>In a blender, puree onion, garlic, and mayo. Slather mayo sauce on top of the breasts then sprinkle chilli powder and salt on top. Cook for 45 min at 350. Serve with anything. Makes 4 servings.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Chicken Bombay</name><contributor>Jordan Kennedy</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This tender chicken dish has a mild and slightly sweet curry flavor.</description><spices>Chili powder
Curry powder</spices><source>Company's Coming, Make-Ahead Meals (pg.82)</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>1/4 cup butter
1/4 cup prepared mustard
1/2 cup liquid honey
1/2 teaspoon seasoned salt
1/4 teaspoon chili powder
1/4 teaspoon onion powder
1/4 teaspoon curry powder
1/2 teaspoon salt
1/4 teaspoon pepper
3 lb.chicken livers</ingredients><directions>Mix first 9 ingredients in a small saucepan. Heat and stir to liquefy.

Roll each part of chicken in sauce. Place in single layer in greased 9 x 13 inch
(22 x 33 cm) pan. Bake, uncovered, in 375*F(190*C) oven for about 1 hour until
tender, spooning on any remaining sauce at half-time.

Makes 4 servings.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Spicy Meatballs Recipe</name><contributor>Tyler Bray</contributor><category>Appetizer</category><description>This is a nice appetizer for when friends or family come over for gatherings.</description><spices>fresh red chillies</spices><source>indonesian recipe</source><rating>Mildly Hot</rating><ingredients>450g lean minced (ground) beef
1 large onion, coarsley chopped
1-2 fresh red, chillies, seeded and chopped
2 crushed garlic cloves
1/2 in cube shrimp paste
1 tablespoon coriander seeds
1 teaspoon cumin seeds
2 teaspoon dark soy sauce
1 teaspoon dark brown sugar
Juice of 1/2 lemon
A little beaten egg
Oil ofr shallow frying
Salt
Ground black pepper
Fresh coriander springs to garnish</ingredients><directions>1. Put the onion, chillies, garlic and shrimp paste in a food processor. Process but do not over-chop or the onion will become too wet and spoil the consistency of the meatballs. Dry-fry the coriander and cumin seeds in a preheated pan for about 1 minute to release the aroma. Do not brown the seeds. Grind with a morta and pestle
2. Put the meat in a large bowl. Stir in the onion mixture. Add the ground coriander and cumin, soy sauce, seasoning, sugar and lemon juice. Bind with a little beaten egg and shape into small but evenly sized balls.
3. Chili the meatballs briefly to firm up, if necessary. Fry in shallow oil. Turn meatballs often until cooked through and browned. This normally takes about 4 to 5 minutes depending on the size of the meatballs.
4. Remove from the pan and drain well on a paper towel. Serve, garnished with coriander springs.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Spicy Meatballs Recipe</name><contributor>Tyler Bray</contributor><category>Appetizer</category><description>This is a nice appetizer for when friends or family come over for gatherings.</description><spices>fresh red chillies</spices><source>indonesian recipe</source><rating>Mildly Hot</rating><ingredients>450g lean minced (ground) beef
1 large onion, coarsley chopped
1-2 fresh red, chillies, seeded and chopped
2 crushed garlic cloves
1/2 in cube shrimp paste
1 tablespoon coriander seeds
1 teaspoon cumin seeds
2 teaspoon dark soy sauce
1 teaspoon dark brown sugar
Juice of 1/2 lemon
A little beaten egg
Oil ofr shallow frying
Salt
Ground black pepper
Fresh coriander springs to garnish</ingredients><directions>1. Put the onion, chillies, garlic and shrimp paste in a food processor. Process but do not over-chop or the onion will become too wet and spoil the consistency of the meatballs. Dry-fry the coriander and cumin seeds in a preheated pan for about 1 minute to release the aroma. Do not brown the seeds. Grind with a morta and pestle
2. Put the meat in a large bowl. Stir in the onion mixture. Add the ground coriander and cumin, soy sauce, seasoning, sugar and lemon juice. Bind with a little beaten egg and shape into small but evenly sized balls.
3. Chili the meatballs briefly to firm up, if necessary. Fry in shallow oil. Turn meatballs often until cooked through and browned. This normally takes about 4 to 5 minutes depending on the size of the meatballs.
4. Remove from the pan and drain well on a paper towel. Serve, garnished with coriander springs.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Spicy Mushroom Chicken Pesto Pasta</name><contributor>Rovic Perdon</contributor><category>Main dish</category><description>This is a pasta dish I was bored one day and threw together but ended up liking it a lot.</description><spices>Peri-peri chilli pepper, or red chilli pepper</spices><source>My twisted mind - Rovic Perdon</source><rating>Chemical Warefare - May cause blindness</rating><ingredients>200g of Pasta (uncooked)

1/2 cup virgin olive oil

sliced musrooms
finely minced basil
75g of parmegean cheese
chicken breast
1 peri-peri chilli
pinch of red chilli pepper
1 clove garlic</ingredients><directions>Cook pasta, prepare sauce by finely chopping the basil into small amounts, crush garlic and chop into small pieces, grate parmegean into small amount and mix ingredients into virgin olive oil. Slice chicken into manageable bites. Fry in a pan, add a bit of virgin oilive oil when frying, chop peri-peri chilli and mushrooms into small pieces. add pinch of red chilli, mushrooms and peri peri with the chicken once near cooked. Strain pasta, add sauce and chicken. Enjoy!</directions></recipe><recipe><name>INDIAN SPICY BIRYANI</name><contributor>MITESH GUDHKA</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Biriyani is a delicious Indian rice dish which is often reserved for very special
occasions such as weddings, parties, or holidays such as Ramzan. It has a lengthy
preparation, but the work is definitely worth it. For biryani, always use long
grain rice.Basmati rice with its thin, fine grains is the ideal variety to use.</description><spices>Dried red chili</spices><source>India recipe</source><rating>HOT</rating><ingredients>4 tablespoons vegetable oil
4 small potatoes, peeled and halved
2 large onions, finely chopped
2 cloves garlic, minced
1 tablespoon minced fresh ginger root
1/2 teaspoon chili powder
1/2 teaspoon ground black pepper
1/2 teaspoon ground turmeric
1 teaspoon ground cumin
1 teaspoon salt
2 medium tomatoes, peeled and chopped
2 tablespoons plain yogurt
2 tablespoons chopped fresh mint leaves
1/2 teaspoon ground cardamom
1 (2 inch) piece cinnamon stick
3 pounds boneless, skinless chicken pieces cut into chunks
1 large onion, diced
1 pinch powdered saffron
5 pods cardamom
3 whole cloves
1 (1 inch) piece cinnamon stick
1/2 teaspoon ground ginger
1 pound basmati rice
4 cups chicken stock
1 1/2 teaspoons salt</ingredients><directions>In a large skillet, in 2 tablespoons vegetable oil (or ghee) fry potatoes until brown,
drain and reserve the potatoes. Add remaining 2 tablespoons oil to the skillet and fry
onion, garlic and ginger until onion is soft and golden. Add chili, pepper, turmeric,
cumin, salt and the tomatoes. Fry, stirring constantly for 5 minutes. Add yogurt, mint,
cardamom and cinnamon stick. Cover and cook over low heat, stirring occasionally until
the tomatoes are cooked to a pulp. It may be necessary to add a little hot water if the
mixture becomes too dry and starts to stick to the pan.
When the mixture is thick and smooth, add the chicken pieces and stir well to coat them
with the spice mixture. Cover and cook over very low heat until the chicken is tender,
approximately 35 to 45 minutes. There should only be a little very thick gravy left when
chicken is finished cooking. If necessary cook uncovered for a few minutes to reduce the
gravy.
Wash rice well and drain in colander for at least 30 minutes.
In a large skillet, heat vegetable oil (or ghee) and fry the onions until they are golden.
Add saffron, cardamom, cloves, cinnamon stick, ginger and rice. Stir continuously until the
rice is coated with the spices.
In a medium-size pot, heat the chicken stock and salt. When the mixture is hot pour it over
the rice and stir well. Add the chicken mixture and the potatoes; gently mix them into the
rice. Bring to boil. Cover the saucepan tightly, turn heat to very low and steam for 20 minutes.
Do not lift lid or stir while cooking. Spoon biryani onto a warm serving dish.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Falafel</name><contributor>Andrew Soknacki</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>null</description><spices>Parsley, Cumin, Coriander</spices><source>Middel Eastern  recipe</source><rating>I dont find it spicy</rating><ingredients>1 cup dried chickpeas or 16 oz. can of chickpeas
1 large onion, chopped
2 cloves of garlic, chopped
3 tablespoons of fresh parsley, chopped
1 teaspoon coriander
1 teaspoon cumin
2 tablespoons flour
Salt
Pepper
Oil for frying</ingredients><directions>If using dried chickpea's let soak over knight,Drain the chick pea's, put chick pea's in a fresh pot of water.
Allow to boil for 5 minutes, then let simmer on low for about an hour.Drain and allow to cool for 15 minutes.
Combine chickpeas, garlic, onion, coriander, cumin, salt and pepper (to taste) in medium bowl. Add flour.Mash chickpeas,
ensuring to mix ingredients together. The desired constistancy should be a paste Form the mixture into small balls,
about the size of a ping pong ball. ( size is not to important just make shure that they are not to large or small)
Slightly flatten.Fry in 2 inches of oil at 350 degrees until golden brown (5-7 minutes).
Serve hot.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Tourtiere du Saguenay</name><contributor>Jean-Benoit Aubin</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>The tourti?res of the Saguenay-Lac-Saint-Jean area are slow-cooked deep-dish meat pies made with potatoes and various meats (often including game), which are cut into small cubes.</description><spices>Salt</spices><source>Food Network</source><rating>Medium</rating><ingredients>1/2 pound pork shoulder, cut into 1/2-inch cubes
1/2 pound veal shoulder, cut into 1/2-inch cubes
1/2 pound beef shoulder, cut into 1/2-inch cubes
4 ounces salt pork, cut into 1/2-inch cubes
1 cup finely chopped onions
1 tablespoon chopped garlic
2 medium potatoes, peeled and diced 1/2-inch thick
2 teaspoons salt
1 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper
1 egg, beaten</ingredients><directions>Using a meat grinder or an electric mixer fitted with a medium coarse die, grind the meat and fat together. In a mixing bowl, combine the ground meat, onions, garlic, salt and pepper. Mix well, cover and refrigerate overnight.
Place the potatoes in a medium bowl and cover with water, cover and refrigerate overnight.
Combine the meat and potatoes together and mix well.
In a mixing bowl, combine the flour and salt. Mix well. Add the shortening and mix until the mixture resembles coarse crumbs. Add the water and let sit for 1 minute. Using either a fork or your hands, carefully press the mixture together forming a soft ball. Wrap in plastic wrap and refrigerate for at least 30 minutes. Remove the dough from the refrigerator and place it on a lightly floured surface. Cut the dough in half and roll the dough out on the floured surface into a circle about 12-inches in diameter and 1/8-inch thick.
Preheat the oven 350 degrees F.
Gently fold the circle of dough in half, and then in half again so that you can lift it without tearing it, and unfold into a 9 by 2-inch deep-dish pie pan. Spoon the meat mixture into the pie crust. Brush the edges with the beaten egg. Lay the second pie crust over the meat mixture. Crimp the edges and place in the oven. Bake for 30 minutes. Reduce the heat to 300 degrees F and continue to cook for 1 1/2 hours.
Remove from the oven and cool for 10 to 15 minutes before serving. Slice the pie into individual serving. Garnish with parsley.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Curry Beef</name><contributor>Mitchell J.</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional Indian-style recipe. I learned it from my mom who found it in a cooking magazine. It should taste slightly spicy and a little bit sweet. You can go without the peas if so desired.</description><spices>Curry</spices><source>Indian recipe</source><rating>Slightly Spicy</rating><ingredients>1 pound of lean ground beef, 1/2 cup thawed frozen peas, 1 cup white rice, 1 can Indian curry</ingredients><directions>In a medium saucepan, cook ground beef until cooked all throughout. Meanwhile, boil white rice and thaw out the frozen peas. When meat is cooked, add curry sauce to the simmering meat and mix around until well coated. Scoop rice onto plates and pour the beef and sauce overtop. Finally, sprinkle the thawed peas overtop. Serves 4.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Spaggetti and Meatballs</name><contributor>Jozef Lewitzky</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>My family's favorite dinner meal, a basic pasta with our family's homemade meatballs.</description><spices>garlic</spices><source>Family secret</source><rating>Delicious</rating><ingredients>1 bag of spaggetti or pasta of your choice
ground beef
bread crumbs
garlic
tomato sauce
parmesean cheese</ingredients><directions>Cook spagetti as directed on it's package. While doing so, Mix ground beef, garlic and bread crumbs in a bowl until throughly combined, beef should be paste like texture. Roll the mixture into balls and cook in a medium saucepan. Carefully turn each meatball as soon as it's black and hard on the bottom, and continue turning until all sides of the meatballs are black as well. This creates a meatball with cruncy, peel off sides and a juicy center. Serve pasta with tomato sauce and shredded parmesean cheese, and the meatballs on top.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Baked Potatoes with Zesty Tofu Topping .</name><contributor>Muna Jaddou</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Recipe from a vegetarian cook book, very healthy and great tasting! great for those who love tofu :) for 3 people</description><spices>salt</spices><source>vegetarian cooking book</source><rating>little too zesty</rating><ingredients>5 oz Regular or "lite" silken tofu (half of a 10-ounce aseptic pack)
2 tb ketchup or store-bought tomato sauce
1 tb Prepared red or white horseradish; or more to taste
1 tb Dijon mustard
1 Scallion; cut into 4 pieces OR 1 tablespoon freeze-dried chives
1/2 ts Salt
3 Baked potatoes; heated and split</ingredients><directions>In a food processor, combine all of the ingredients except the potatoes and process to a smooth puree. Taste and add more horseradish as desired. (The topping can be prepared up to 5 days ahead, covered, and refrigerated. Bring to room temperature and stir well before using.)

Serve the topping spooned over the hot baked potatoes.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Bengal Canapes</name><contributor>Edmond NKINZO KABUSHEMEYE</contributor><category>Appetizer</category><description>This is a traditional Bengal recipe. I found it from an
cooking ebook. Be sure to dose the paprika to taste. And add as much grated parmesan cheese as you like.</description><spices>Paprika, Mango chutney</spices><source>Recipesource.com</source><rating>NICE</rating><ingredients>8 slices of bread, 1 tablespoon of butter, 4 oz of chopped ham, half a cup of grated cheddar cheese, mango chutney, grated parmesan cheese, and paprika to taste</ingredients><directions>Make toasted bread croutons:  Using a small glass, cut 2-inch rounds out of slices of bread (you'll get about two per slice). Lightly toast both sides of bread. Heat butter, ham and cheese together.  Spread on toasted bread croutons. Top with a dab of mango chutney and grated Parmesan cheese. Brown slightly under broiler.  Sprinkle with a little paprika and serve hot. Note:  If you make your own French bread, make a loaf smaller in diameter. Freeze, then slice frozen to crouton thickness or thinner. Makes for better base.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Sauteed Apples</name><contributor>100764305</contributor><category>Desert/Topping</category><description>This is great for any meal, but is great for breakfast.
The syrup from the apples is great on homemade waffles. You may add raisins to the sauce if you wish.</description><spices>Cinnamon</spices><source>AllFood</source><rating>BLAND</rating><ingredients>1/4 cup butter
4 large tart apples - peeled, cored and sliced 1/4 inch thick
2 teaspoons cornstarch
1/2 cup cold water
1/2 cup brown sugar
1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon</ingredients><directions>1.   In a large skillet or saucepan, melt butter over medium heat; add apples.
Cook, stirring constantly, until apples are almost tender, about 6 to 7 minutes.
2. Dissolve cornstarch in water; add to skillet. Stir in brown sugar and cinnamon.
Boil for 2 minutes, stirring occasionally. Remove from heat and serve warm.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Chilean Empanadas</name><contributor>Felipe Arellano-Silva</contributor><category>Appetizer</category><description>This is a traditional Chilean recipe for a dish famous throughout Latin America.</description><spices>Cayenne</spices><source>http://recipes.epicurean.com</source><rating>MILD</rating><ingredients>DOUGH
3 Cups All-purpose flour
1 Teaspoon Coarse salt
8 Tablespoons Unsalted butter -- cut in bits
2 Egg yolks
2 Tablespoons Tarragon vinegar
9 Tablespoons Cold water

FILLING
1 tablespoon Olive oil
1 teaspoon Spanish paprika
1/8 teaspoon Cayenne
2 tablespoons Unsalted butter
2 medium Onions -- chopped fine
1/2 pound Lean ground beef
1/4 teaspoon Dried oregano
2 teaspoons Coarse salt
1 Bay leaf
1/2 cup Beef stock
3 tablespoons Seedless raisins
8 Kalamata olives -- chopped
1 Hard-boiled egg -- chopped

GLAZE
1 Egg yolk
1 whole Egg
1 tablespoon Cold water</ingredients><directions>Sift the flour and salt into a bowl. Add the butter, egg yolks, and vinegar and mix quickly and thoroughly with your fingertips until all ingredients are well incorporated. Add 5 tablespoons of the water and continue mixing, adding just enough of the remaining water, a little at a time, to make a firm dough. Refrigerate until ready to use.
For the filling, heat the oil and butter in a saute pan. Add the onions and saute over medium heat until light brown around the edges, about 5 minutes. Add the beef, oregano, salt, and bay leaf and cook until all the liquid has evaporated. Add the stock and continue cooking until the stock has almost -- but not quite -- evaporated. Mix in the raisins and olives. Remove from the heat and let cool. Stir in the chopped hard-boiled egg. Correct the seasoning with salt to taste. Set aside.
Preheat the oven to 375 degrees. On a floured board, roll out the dough about 1/8-inch thick, shaping it into a 16-inch square. Cut out circles about 5-inches in diameter. Knead and re-roll the scraps and cut into additional circles. Place a heaping tablespoon of the meat filling about 1/2-inch from the edge of each circle. Brush the border of the circle with juices from the filling or with water. Fold the dough over to form a half-moon, pressing the edges together with your fingertips or the tines of a fork to seal. Prick the top of each empanada once or twice with the tines of the fork. Repeat this process until all the empanadas are assembled.
Make the glaze by beating the egg yolk and egg with the water. Spread parchment paper on a baking sheet. Arrange the empanadas on top and brush with glaze. Bake for 30 minutes, or until golden. Remove the baking tray from the oven, and transfer the empanadas to a serving platter or individual plates, and serve hot.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Potato Salad</name><contributor>Natasha</contributor><category>Salad</category><description>Whether it is for a family picnic, summer Sunday dinner or any day tasty side dish, there is something about classic potato salad that keeps us all coming back for more.</description><spices>Salt
Pepper</spices><source>http://www.cookingnook.com/potato-salad-recipe.html</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>4 cups potatoes, cooked, peeled and cubed (about 6 or 7 whole potatoes)
1 cup Miracle Whip or mayonnaise
1 teaspoon mustard
1/2 teaspoon celery seeds
1/2 teaspoon salt
1/8 teaspoon pepper
2 hard boiled eggs, chopped
1/2 cup onion, chopped
1/2 cup celery, finely chopped
1/2 cup sweet pickles, finely chopped</ingredients><directions>Boil potatoes whole, with the skins on, in salted water for about 15 to 20 minutes until they are tender in the middle when you prick with a fork. Do not overboil or the salad will be mushy.

Cool the potatoes a bit then peel them, cut into cubes and place in a large bowl.

In a separate smaller bowl combine the mayonnaise, mustard, celery seeds, salt and pepper. Mix well. Add the chopped eggs, onion, celery and pickles and mix together to combine.

Pour dressing over the cubed potatoes and mix lightly so as not to break up the potatoes too much. Cover and chill until time to serve.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Cilantro-Potatoes</name><contributor>Ia Vaquilar</contributor><category>Appetizer</category><description>This is a modified version of a traditional Indian recipe I found from allrecipes.com.  I have substituted some ingredients for similar flavours that are conveniently available in any grocery store.  The result was a quick and simple recipe with a delectable harmony of spices.</description><spices>cumin seeds
green chile peppers
chili powder
coriander</spices><source>http://allrecipes.com/Recipe/Best-Potatoes-Ever/Detail.aspx</source><rating>mild</rating><ingredients>4 large potatoes, cubed
1 tablespoon olive oil
1 teaspoon cumin seeds
2 green chile peppers, chopped
1 inch piece of fresh ginger root, finely chopped
1 teaspoon chili powder
1 teaspoon coriander, ground
1 lime, juiced
1/2 teaspoon salt
1 bunch fresh cilantro, chopped</ingredients><directions>1. Place the potatoes in a saucepan with enough water to cover. Bring to a boil, and cook 10 minutes, until tender. Drain and allow to cool slightly,
2. Heat the oil in a large pan over medium heat. Lightly toast the cumin seeds in the heated oil. Mix in the green chile peppers and ginger. Season with chili powder and coriander. Stir in the potatoes, and cook about 5 minutes. Season with salt, and lime juice. Continue cooking for about 15 more minutes. Mix in the chopped cilantro before serving. Makes 4 servings.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Chicken biryani</name><contributor>Yacoub abdulla</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional Indian recipe.  i asked my mom to help me with this recipe and its a bit spicey</description><spices>biryani curry paste</spices><source>Indian recipe</source><rating>Medium Hot</rating><ingredients>1 cup(250 ml) frozen peas
1 onion, thinly sliced
2 carrots, diced
6 skinless, boneless chicken thighs or 3 skinless, bonless breasts
1/4 cups(50 ml) biryani curry paste
1 cup(250 ml) basmati rice
2 cups(500 ml) water
1/2 tsp (2 ml) salt
1 cup(250 ml) coarsely chopped cilantro</ingredients><directions>Measure out peas and leave at room temperature. Prepare vegetables. Lightly coat a large saucepan with vegetable oil and set over medium heat.
Add onion and carrots. Stir occasionally until onion has softened, 3 to 5 min. Meanwhile cut chicken into bite-size pieces. Add to vegetables
and saute until lightly golden, about 5min.
Add biryani paste and stirr until chicken is well coated. Mix in rice, water and salt. Cover and bring to a boil. Stir, then reduce heatto low.
Simmer, covered for 15min.
Then mix in peas. Cover and continue to simmer until water is absorbed, from 5 to 7 mor min. Remove from heat. Sprinkle with cilantro. Scoop
into large bowl.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Cilantro-Potatoes</name><contributor>Ia Vaquilar</contributor><category>Appetizer</category><description>This is a modified version of a traditional Indian recipe I found from allrecipes.com.  I have substituted some ingredients for similar flavours that are conveniently available in any grocery store.  The result was a quick and simple recipe with a delectable harmony of spices.</description><spices>cumin seeds
green chile peppers
chili powder
coriander</spices><source>http://allrecipes.com/Recipe/Best-Potatoes-Ever/Detail.aspx</source><rating>mild</rating><ingredients>4 large potatoes, cubed
1 tablespoon olive oil
1 teaspoon cumin seeds
2 green chile peppers, chopped
1 inch piece of fresh ginger root, finely chopped
1 teaspoon chili powder
1 teaspoon coriander, ground
1 lime, juiced
1/2 teaspoon salt
1 bunch fresh cilantro, chopped</ingredients><directions>1. Place the potatoes in a saucepan with enough water to cover. Bring to a boil, and cook 10 minutes, until tender. Drain and allow to cool slightly,
2. Heat the oil in a large pan over medium heat. Lightly toast the cumin seeds in the heated oil. Mix in the green chile peppers and ginger. Season with chili powder and coriander. Stir in the potatoes, and cook about 5 minutes. Season with salt, and lime juice. Continue cooking for about 15 more minutes. Mix in the chopped cilantro before serving. Makes 4 servings.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Coconut Sambol</name><contributor>Thuvaragan</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional Sri Lankan tamil recipe. My family makes it to eat with other dishes
such as string hoppers, rice and stuff.</description><spices>chili powder made sri lankan style</spices><source>Sri Lankan tamil recipe</source><rating>WAY TOO HOT EVEN FOR A LANKAN TO HANDLE</rating><ingredients>2 cups grated fresh or packaged unsweetened coconut
flesh of 1/2 coconut
1 medium onion
1/4 teaspoon of chilli powder
2 teaspoons lemon or lime juice
1/2 level teaspoon salt</ingredients><directions>To make the coconut sambal, quite simply grate the coconut and the onion straight into a bowl,
then sprinkle in the chilli powder, the lemon or lime juice and the salt.
Stir to get everything nicely blended, then sprinkle just a tiny dusting of
chilli powder over the top, cover and chill slightly until needed.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Potato Skins</name><contributor>Gehana Booth</contributor><category>Snack/Appetizer</category><description>A plate full of crispy potato skins, filled with melty cheddar cheese, and topped with bacon bits, sour cream and green onions.</description><spices>Salt
Pepper</spices><source>http://www.elise.com/recipes/archives/007113potato_skins.php</source><rating>Not Spicy At All</rating><ingredients>6 small to medium sized russet baking potatoes (total 3 pounds)
Olive oil
Canola oil or grapeseed oil
Kosher salt
Freshly ground pepper
6 strips of bacon
4 ounces grated cheddar cheese
1/2 cup sour cream
2 green onions, thinly sliced, including the greens of the onions</ingredients><directions>1. Scrub the potatoes clean then bake the potatoes using an oven set to 400?F for an hour.

2. While the potatoes are cooking, cook the bacon strips in a frying pan on medium low heat for 10 to 15 minutes, or until crisp. Drain on paper towels. Let cool. Crumble.

3. Remove the potatoes from the oven and let cool enough to handle. Cut in half horizontally. Use a spoon to carefully scoop out the insides, reserving the scooped potatoes for another use, leaving about 1/4 of an inch of potato on the skin.

4. Increase the heat of the oven to 450?F. Brush or rub grapeseed oil or canola oil (or another high smoke point oil) all over the potato skins, outside and in. Sprinkle with salt. Place on a baking rack in a roasting pan. Cook for 10 minutes on one side, then flip the skins over and cook for another 10 minutes. Remove from oven and let cool enough to handle.

5. Sprinkle the insides with freshly ground black pepper, cheddar cheese, and crumbled bacon. Return to the oven. Broil for an additional 2 minutes, or until the cheese is bubbly. Remove from oven. Use tongs to place skins on a serving plate. Add a dollop of sour cream to each skin, sprinkle with green onions.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Dragonbreath Chili</name><contributor>Lyle Horning</contributor><category>Main Course</category><description>Use: Ocasionally belch flame at enemies struck in melee for the next 10min.

Grants a somewhat dragon-like quality, belching this fire doesnt hurt you.
However this flame is extremely hot to others! Eat with caution.</description><spices>Hot Spices,
Flame Sac</spices><source>Blizzard Entertainment</source><rating>Awesome</rating><ingredients>Mystery Meat,
Flame Sac,
Hot Spices,
Onions,
Garlic,
Salt,
Pepper</ingredients><directions>Gather your ingredients.
Flame sac can be obtained from slaying the nearest dragon.

Heat oil in heavy saucepan over medium-high heat. Add onions, garlic,
Saute for about 8 minutes
Add ground Mystery Meat and cook until brown, breaking up meat with a spatula as it cooks.
Add chili salt, pepper, and Hot Spices to the meat.
Stir in Flame Sac innards.
Add pieces of the flame sac outside for even more spice.
Reduce heat to low and simmer for at least 1 and a half hours.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Fireball Burgers</name><contributor>Jonathan Murphy</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Very spicy bugers.</description><spices>pepper</spices><source>the LUElinks cookbook</source><rating>very hot</rating><ingredients>4oz ground beef, tobasco sauce, pepperjack cheese, spicy barbeque sauce, lettuce, tomato, mayonnaise, hamburger buns</ingredients><directions>1. Prepare the patties, seasoning them with a dash of salt and a liberal amount of Tabasco sauce and pepper.
2. Cook the burgers; grilling is your best bet here. When you flip the burgers, add more pepper and Tabasco sauce.
3. When finished, let it sit momentarily, then put a slice of cheese on each patty and microwave them until the cheese melts.
4. Add more Tabasco sauce as well as the BBQ sauce and mayo. Don't add much mayo, or it will nullify the BBQ.
5. Combine bun, lettuce, and tomato.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>SLOP</name><contributor>Conor Rochon</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is my favorite thing to make at the end of the week with what I got in the fridge,
Looks a bit ugly but man is it good.</description><spices>BBQ Sauce</spices><source>Made it up</source><rating>Depends whats in it</rating><ingredients>Pottato(whole and pre-cooked or caned)
Chicken Brest
Smokey BBQ Sauce
Cooking oil of some kind

Optional ingredients(Leftovers)

Rice
Vegies(corn's good)
Apple slices(for sweetness)
Whatever really</ingredients><directions>In a fryingpan gresed with cooking oil, on a relitivly hot seting(around 7 or 8 on my stove)
Begin cooking the Pottatos. Usualy I throw them in and cut them into tinyer peices in the pan.
Once they have browned a bit take them out and put the chicken(sliced thin) in,
cook it untill it starts to get white then throw the Pottatoes back in. Stiring consistantly
throw whatever else you want inand coat libraly with your favorite BBQ Sauce.
Let cook until the chicken is white all the way through(Unless you don't mind samonella). and eat it.
It's good I swear.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Shepherd's Pie</name><contributor>100684673</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Mashed potatoes and meat, what more could you want?</description><spices>Garlic, Salt, Pepper</spices><source>England</source><rating>Not</rating><ingredients>Ground Lamb or Beef: 1 lb
Frozen Green Peas: 1/2 cup
Carrots: 1/4 cups, chopped
Onion: 1 medium, chopped
Garlic: 1 clove, diced
Worcestershire Sauce: 2 tbsp (or replace it with your favorite steak sauce)
Potatoes: 4 medium, peeled and sliced
Onion Spring: 1 tbsp, chopped
Cream Cheese: 1-2 tbsp
Milk: 1-2 tbsp
Butter: 2-3 tbsp
Vegetable Oil: 1 tbsp
Salt
Pepper</ingredients><directions>1. Boil potatoes in salted water for 15 min or till tender.

2. Meanwhile, saute chopped onion, carrots and garlic with vegetable oil in a frying pan for 5 min.

3. Add ground meat and saute for 10 min until no longer pink. Add salt, pepper and Worcestershire sauce and cook for 5 more min. Add frozen peas and cook 2-3 more min.

4. Mash hot potatoes and melt butter with them. Add milk, chopped onion springs and cream cheese. Use a spoon to mix them well. Season with salt and pepper to taste.

5. Transfer meat to a baking dish and cover with mashed potatoes.

6. Cook in 400 F preheated oven for 30 min until crisp on top.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Irish Spicy Cornbread</name><contributor>Trevor Malone</contributor><category>Appetizer</category><description>A nice mildly spicy cornbread recipe. Great with chili. You may want to adjust the amount of cayenne and hot sauce to taste. For this recipe I use cast iron pans that have 5 small corn cob shapes
in them, but any cast iron frying pan will do.</description><spices>Cayenne Pepper</spices><source>http://allrecipes.com/Recipe/Irish-Spicy-Cornbread/Detail.aspx</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>2 cups all-purpose flour
1 cup yellow cornmeal
1/3 cup white sugar
4 1/2 teaspoons baking powder
1 1/2 teaspoons salt
1 1/2 teaspoons cayenne pepper
1/2 cup shortening
1 1/2 cups milk
2 eggs, beaten
4 1/2 teaspoons hot pepper sauce</ingredients><directions>Preheat oven and skillet to 400 degrees F (200 degrees C).
In a large bowl, mix together flour, cornmeal, sugar, baking powder, salt, and cayenne pepper. Cut in shortening until the mixture resembles coarse bread crumbs. In a small bowl, beat together milk,
eggs and hot pepper sauce. Stir milk mixture into the flour/cornmeal mixture until just blended. Remove hot skillet from oven, spray with non-stick cooking spray and pour batter into skillet.
Bake in preheated oven for 20 to 25 minutes, or until a toothpick inserted into center of loaf comes out clean.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Stuffed Bell Peppers</name><contributor>James Wallwork</contributor><category>Main Dish</category><description>This is a simple dish best served hot, ontop-of/cut-into rice. Being such a basic recipe, there is a lot of room for you to add your own twists. Most of the flavour comes from the juice, which coats the rice, but you can spice the beef as you like for extra flavour. *NOTE* There are different types of V8 juice available, including "Low Sodium" Should you choose to use this type, you can add a pinch of salt on top of the dish once prepared to give the same flavour. Unless you really like salt, don't add salt if you're using a standard V8 (the taste can be overpowering).</description><spices>Salt
Pepper</spices><source>Common in most Prepared Foods sections of your local Grocery Store.</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>Bell Peppers (any colour)
Medium Ground Beef
Salt and Pepper
Rice
Chopped Onion (1 per 6 peppers)
Optional Additional Spices
Optional Cheese, grated (any type will do)</ingredients><directions>Saut?e the onion, then combine with beef, until brown (adding spices and and stirring regularily), meanwhile chopping some bell peppers in half, length-wise. Flash-fry the pepper-halves briefly (microwave, high-oven heat, or in a frying-pan for about a minute or two in all cases), then pack the beef into the peppers (at this point, add the cheese on top) and place into a deep flat dish. Add V8 juice into base of dish, and over peppers (safely half the height of the peppers) then bake in an oven at a medium heat (until the cheese browns).</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Beef and Carrott Stir-Fry</name><contributor>Alex Fait</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional Canadian Recipe. I found it from an old cooking book in my grandmothers house. It's main ingredients are Beef and rice.</description><spices>Garlic, Dried pepper, Black pepper</spices><source>Canadian Recipe</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>2/3 lb rum steak
1 small carrot
1 stalk celery
3 cayenne pepper
1/3 oz. scallion
1 clove garlic</ingredients><directions>Chinese Recipe : Stir Fried Beef with Carrot

Serves 4

Ingredients:

2/3 lb rum steak
1 small carrot
1 stalk celery
3 cayenne pepper
1/3 oz. scallion
1 clove garlic

Seasoning A:
? tsp salt
? tsp MSG
1 tbsp rice wine
1 tsp soy sauce

Seasoning B:
1 tbsp rice wine
1 tbsp soy sauce
1/3 tsp vinegar
1/3 tsp MSG
1 tsp sugar
? tsp caramel sauce (optional)
? tbsp sesame oil
Cooking oil


Directions:

1. Cut the beef along the grain into 2 1/2 inch long strips. Peel the carrot and remove the tough parts of celery. Cut the carrot and celery into 2 1/2 inch strips.

2. Cut the cayenne pepper into 1/2 inch pieces and remove the seeds. Shred the scallion into 2 inch strops. Slice the garlic.

3.Pour 2 cups of oil and drop the beef into fry. Stir occasionally and cook for approximatly twenty minutes on medium. Add seasoning and vegetbles and cook until desired tenderness.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Manti</name><contributor>Saken Khudaibergenov</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional north-central asian recipe. I found it from a web site. It is very tasty.</description><spices>Red pepper</spices><source>Fake recipe</source><rating>MILD</rating><ingredients>* 3 cups all purpose flour
* 1 cup water
* 1 large egg
* 1 tablespoon olive oil
* 1 teaspoon salt
* 250 gr ground meat
* 1 large onion (chopped in very small pieces)
* Salt and black pepper
* 2 cups plain yogurt
* 2-3 cloves of garlic
* 1/4 cup water
* 1/2 teaspoon salt
* 6-7 tablespoons olive oil
* 2 teaspoons red pepper ( hot or mild, its up to you)</ingredients><directions>1. In a large bowl, stir together the flour, water, egg, olive oil and salt.
2. Knead them very well until the dough is formed. The dough should be smooth and not sticky. If you feel it is sticky, add a little bit more flour.
3. Cover the bowl with some plastic wrap and let stand at cool room temperature for an hour.
4. Meanwhile, prepare the filling. In a medium bowl, put onions, meat, salt and black pepper. Knead them together for one minute (do not cook.)
5. Lightly dust a work surface and a rolling pin with flour. Divide the dough into 4 equal balls. Roll out each ball into sheets as thin as you can roll out, but be careful don't tear it.
6. Cut each sheet into squares of about 1.5"x1.5".Put a very small piece of filling at the center of each square. Continue until the dough is finished.
7. As you see below, bring the opposite corners together and make a triangle or, fold them to make a rectangle. Both works fine. Press the sides firmly. (Don't forget to hide your chickpeas for the game. :)
8. Bring two of the adjacent corners together as shown in the picture.
9. In a large pot, boil the water and add a little bit salt, olive oil. Add Manti and stir. Cook for about 15 minutes. Please check while cooking. Don't overcook.
10. Meanwhile, prepare the sauces. Firstly, in a small bowl, grate cloves of garlic and add yogurt, water, salt. Stir them together. Secondly, in a separate sauce pan add olive oil and red pepper, stir together and cook them only for half a minute.
11. When Manti is ready, you can drain well or not, the way you like, it is up to you.
12. Serve warm with yogurt sauce and red sauce.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Baked Chicken with Stuffing</name><contributor>Matt Brown</contributor><category>Main Course</category><description>This is a clssic recipe. It's generally loved by the whole family, as it contains only common ingredients, and they are all well loved. It is also large enough to serve many, and leftovers are easily kept.</description><spices>Parsley</spices><source>Kraft Cooking</source><rating>Very Mild</rating><ingredients>2 Cans of Campbell's Cream of Chicken Soup
Any Amount of Large Chicken Breasts
Stuffing (Stovetop Brand usually works best)</ingredients><directions>In a large caserole dish, place chicken breasts in, with enough space in between them. You cannot use GridBagLayout to organize the chicken, sorry. Open and pour the two cans of Cream of Chicken Soup into the caserole dish, and spread evenly throughout. Next, take the pre-cooked stuffing/dressing and cover the chicken. Spread this out evenly. Set the oven to 450 degrees fahrenheit, and place on middle rack. Cook for 45 minutes, or until stuffing/dressing on top is a crispy brown.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Waterboard Me Smoothie</name><contributor>Sean</contributor><category>Energy Drink</category><description>Pain is the best pick-me-up.</description><spices>Naga Jolokia peppers
Wasabi</spices><source>Intoxication</source><rating>Do not injest. If injested accidentally induce vomiting then immediately seek medical attention.</rating><ingredients>10 Naga Jolokia peppers
1 large onion
2 cups wasabi
5 cups tobasco sauce</ingredients><directions>Add ingredients to blender and blend until eyes start to water.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Homemade Pasta Sauce</name><contributor>Clayton Shier</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a delicious pasta sauce perfect for Spaghetti or Lasagna.</description><spices>Garlic</spices><source>Family Recipe</source><rating>Scrumptious</rating><ingredients>2 Cans Hunts' Tomato Sauce
1 Can Hunts' tomato paste
1 lb. Fresh Mushrooms
1 Red Pepper
1 Green Pepper
1 Large Onion</ingredients><directions>In a large pot, pour the tomato sauce and paste in. Chop all other ingredients
to a fine size. Cook the sauce for 4 - 5 hours on very low heat. Add to your favorite
pasta.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Easy Ground Beef and Pasta Casserole</name><contributor>Ryan Chong-Kee</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a basic but hearty and delicious casserole, made with pasta and ground beef, along with tomatoes and seasonings. Top this casserole with Monterey Jack cheese or use a blend shredded American and Jack or Cheddar cheeses.</description><spices>NA</spices><source>Diana's Kitchen</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>3 cups uncooked medium shells or mini penne pasta
1 pound lean ground chuck or ground round (85 to 90% lean)
1 cup chopped onion
1 cup chopped celery
1 clove garlic, minced
1/2 teaspoon salt
1 can (14.5 ounces) diced tomatoes with juice
1 large can (15 ounces) tomato sauce
2 teaspoons granulated sugar
1 cup shredded Monterey Jack cheese</ingredients><directions>Heat oven to 350?. Lightly spray or grease an 11x7-inch baking dish.

Cook pasta according to package directions until just tender; drain well.
In a large skillet over medium heat, saute beef with onion and celery, breaking up with a spoon. Cook, stirring, until almost cooked through. Add garlic and salt and cook for 2 to 3 minutes longer. Stir in the tomatoes, tomato sauce, granulated sugar, and the cooked drained pasta. Spoon into the prepared baking dish and cover dish tightly with foil. Bake for 30 to 40 minutes, or until hot and bubbly. Remove foil. Sprinkle with the cheese and bake uncovered for about 5 minutes longer, or until cheese is melted.
Serves 4 to 6.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Mexican Wrapped Hotness</name><contributor>Shawn Reichert</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is your basic Mexican dish, its what the average Mexican eats for breakfast, lunch or dinner.</description><spices>Hot Tamolies and MegaDeth Hot Sauce</spices><source>Mexico</source><rating>Dial 911 before taking a bite!</rating><ingredients>1 Large Soft Taco\n1/4 cup Hot Tamolies\n250ml MegaDeth Hot Sauce\n50g Grounded Hot Tamolies\n100g Crumbled Nachos\n1/4 Cup Guacamole\n1/4 Cup Salsa\n1/3 Cup Ground Beef\n100g Sliced Cheese</ingredients><directions>Take your hot tamolies, and dip them in the MegaDeth hot sauce. Next, bread them in the crushed hot tamolies. Finally throw all your ingredients onto the Soft Taco and wrap it up.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Granola Bars!</name><contributor>Devon Plouffe</contributor><category>Snack</category><description>Great Tasting Homemade Granola Bars</description><spices>sesame seeds</spices><source>www.recipezaar.com</source><rating>5 stars</rating><ingredients>3 cups rolled oats
1 cup sliced almonds
1 cup sunflower seed
1 cup raisins
1 cup craisins (optional)
1 cup chocolate chips (optional)
1/2 cup sesame seed
1/2 cup unsweetened coconut
1/4 cup butter or margarine, melted
1 (14 ounce) can sweetened condensed milk</ingredients><directions>1 Preheat oven to 325 F (160C).
2 Grease baking sheet well. (Or use parchment paper).
3 Combine dry ingredients in a large bowl.
4 Stir in melted butter and sweetened condensed milk.
5 Mix well and pour onto baking sheet.
6 Press down evenly with your hands using waxed paper.
7 Bake for 25-30 minutes until golden brown (could be as long as 40-45 minutes depending on how crunchy you want them).
8 Cool for 15 minutes and cut.
9 Let cool completely and store in airtight container.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Brocoli Salad</name><contributor>JP Landry</contributor><category>Side Dish</category><description>A sweet, creamy salad with lots of brocoli</description><spices>None</spices><source>Mother</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>Broccoli
Bacon
green onions
2 cups cheese
6tbs vinegar
? cup sugar
1 cup mayonnaise</ingredients><directions>Add all ingrediants together in a large bowl and mix well</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Invigorating Borscht</name><contributor>Fedor Ilitchev</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Borscht! From Russia! You know, that famous crimson soup...</description><spices/><source>Mother.</source><rating>mild</rating><ingredients>1 onion2 cloves of garlic4 potatoes5 carrots1/3 of a cabbage head6 table spoons of tomato sauce1 can of beans1 small handful of dill0-1 package of sour cream0-1 table spoon of salt0-1 table spoon of pepper2 bouillon cubes1 small quantity of olive oil1/2 Beat1 table spoon of sugar6 table spoons of tomato sauce</ingredients><directions>Fill a large (larger than most - the kind where most of your head could fit into it... if it had to) casserole about 3/4 full of water. Start boiling it with the two bouillon cubes. Chop up all the vegetables (not super-fine, the slices could be perhaps each be 5mm thick). Spread some oil on a frying pan and fry the onion on it, then transfer it to the water once it softens up - don't let it get brown! Next, fry ONE OF the garlic cloves, you can salt it as you fry. Throw it in the water after a couple of minutes! Next, do the same thing with the beat (fry, salt and throw). Then repeat for the potatoes. Then, for the beats. Then, for the cabbage. Finally, add the beans, the sugar and the tomato paste. Then let it sit and boil under light fire for some 10-15 minutes (until cabbage isn't hard anymore). Finally, disable the fire, and throw in the 2nd garlic clove and the dill. Important: Wait AT LEAST two hours before eating. Eat with sour-cream. Also nice to eat with an egg.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Ground Steak Souffle</name><contributor>Daniel Beimers</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a recipe that can serve up to four people (as per the listed ingredients). I found this in with recipe's that were kept together at my home. It should taste pretty good, if memory serves, and it shouldn't be spicy, although you may add cayenne pepper to the souffle topping, as well as other herbs to the ground steak.</description><spices>Oregano

Cayenne Pepper</spices><source>Supper Dishes Card</source><rating>Not spicy</rating><ingredients>Ground Steak:
1 small green sweet pepper
1 small onion
2 tomatoes
1/2 cup sliced mushrooms
1 tablespoon oil
16-oz. of ground beef
pinch of oregano and/or mixed herbs

Souffl? Topping:
1/2 cup finely grated Cheddar cheese
1/4 cup evaporated milk
2 eggs
salt
pinch of cayenne pepper</ingredients><directions>Chop the pepper, removing seeds and core, skin and chop the onion, skin and slice the tomatoes.
Heat the oil and lightly fry all the vegetables until onion is golden brown.
Place the ground beef in the ovenproof dish, top with the vegetables.
Sprinkle seasonings on top.
Make souffl? by melting the cheese in the evaporated milk in a bowl over hot water. Allow to cool slightly.
Stir in the egg yolks.
Beat egg whites stiffly, then fold in the cheese mixture. Season.
Place on top of the meat and vegetables.
Bake until the souffl? is well risen and lightly browned. About 20-25 minutes.
Serves 4.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Masal Dosa</name><contributor>menan vadivelpillai</contributor><category>South Indian</category><description>This is a traditional south indian recipe. i know this for a long while. It tastes good with some spicy curry.</description><spices>curry</spices><source>South indian recipe</source><rating>not that hot</rating><ingredients>1 1/2 cups rice
1/2 cup urad dal
salt to taste
Oil
Masala Filling:
2 large potatoes
1 medium onion (chopped)
1/2 teaspoon yellow split peas
1/2 teaspoon mustard seed
1/2 teaspoon turmeric
1-2 green chili
1 tablespoon oil
salt to taste</ingredients><directions>* Separately soak rice and urad dal at least 6 hour or overnight in water.
* Grind to paste.
* Mix together, add salt with water to make batter.
* Leave in room temperature overnight.
* Mix onion and chilies to the thin batter.
* Heat pan or griddle with little ghee or oil.
* Spread the mix on pan in circular motion to make thin Dosa.
* Cook on both the sides, if desired.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Papaya Salad</name><contributor>Stephany Lay</contributor><category>Side Dish</category><description>An southeast asian dish that`s very popular in Thailand and Cambodia.
It is normally eaten with sticky rice though tastes just as good with white rice as well.
A mixure of sour and spicy but extremely tasty.</description><spices>chilli peppers
garlic
salt
sugar</spices><source>Thai/Cambodian recipe</source><rating>Hot to Very hot</rating><ingredients>green papaya (shredded)
garlic
chilli peppers
cherry tomatoes
fish sauce
shrimp paste
lime juice
salt
sugar
peanuts(optional)
dried shrimp or salted crabs(optional)</ingredients><directions>Using a mortar and pestle, pound the garlic, cherry tomatoes and chilli a few times until it's just the right spicyness for you.
Add the fish sauce, shrimp paste and lime juice and add a pinch of salt and sugar to the mixture.
Afterward, add your shredded papaya and kneed the mixture until it's nicely blended and toss it to mix the ingredients.
If you want peanuts and/or shrimp/crab, add them with the fish sauce etc.
There should be a bit of liquid but not so much that the papaya is downing in it.
Tasting the food regularly is the best judge of measurement for the ingredients.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Mac 'n Cheeseburger Casserole</name><contributor>Derek Langlois</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>A cheesy beef and pasta dish with mushrooms, peppers, onions, celery, and tomatos from Rediscover Campbell's. M'm! M'm! Good!</description><spices>Chili Powder
Worcestershire Sauce</spices><source>Campbell's</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>1 lb of extra lean ground beef
2 cups of sliced mushroom
1 cup of chopped red and yellow peppers
1/2 cup of chopped onions
1/2 cup of chopped celery
1 can of stewed tomatoes, undrained
1 can of Campbell's Condensed Low Fat Cream of Mushroom Soup
2 cups of uncooked whole wheat elbow pasta
2 tbsp of worcestershire sauce
1 tbsp of chili powder
1/4 cup of shredded sharp cheddar cheese</ingredients><directions>cook beef until browned at medium-high heat in large non-stick skillet. Add mushrooms, peppers, onions, and celery. Cook and stir for 3 minutes. Place mixture into shallow 2 qt (2L) baking dish. Stir in all other ingredients, except cheese. Bake, covered, at 400 degrees F (200 degrees C) until pasta is tender - about 50 minutes. Sprinkle with cheese and let stand 5 minutes before serving. Makes 6 servings.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Apple Chicken Quesadilla</name><contributor>Karim Al Anani</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional Mexican recipe. I found it in my mum's old notebook on cookery. It should taste somewhere between mild and sweet. Some people
like it with pepper.</description><spices/><source>Traditional Mexican recipe</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>4 Flour tortillas (approximately 8-inches wide)
1 cup cooked, shredded or chopped, chicken meat
1/4 lb cheddar or Monterey jack cheese, sliced or grated
1 apple, sliced
1/4 cup salsa</ingredients><directions>Heat a large skillet on medium high heat. Place one tortilla in the skillet. Flip it a couple of times with a spatula, then let it sit in the pan heating up until air pockets form and parts of the tortilla begin to puff up. Flip it again.

Place cheese slices on half of the tortilla, at least 1/2-inch from the edge of the tortilla. Add chicken pieces on top of the cheese. Fold the tortilla over like an omelette, and press down on the folded tortilla with the spatula. Lower the heat to medium. At this point, if you have enough room in your skillet, you can add a second tortilla to the pan to begin to heat it up.

When the cheese inside the quesadilla has melted, remove the quesadilla to a cutting board. Open it wide and layer on apple slices and salsa. Fold the tortilla back again, and cut it into 3 triangles, as if you were cutting a pie. (You don't have to cut the quesadilla into triangles, it just makes it easier for kids to eat.)

Repeat for each tortilla.

Makes 12 Quesadilla triangles.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Greek food</name><contributor>Navid Jalili</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Greek food is a wonderful mix of oriental and European dishes, cooked using different methods, from frying to broiling to boiling. Food in Greece is both easy to make, as the following recipes show, and delightful. Much of Greek food is seasonal and a lot of it is prepared during different times of the year, mainly around dates of religious events, such as Easter, Christmas or New Year.</description><spices>Red Chilli Powder</spices><source>Greek recipe</source><rating>Medium</rating><ingredients>1 pound of boneless chuck
1 pound of boneless lamb,
1 pound of boneless turkey,
1 pound of boneless pork,
2 teaspoons of sea salt,
1/2 teaspoon of freshly ground black pepper,
1/8 teaspoon of savory,
2 tablespoons of prepared mustard,
2 tablespoons of extra virgin olive oil,
4 tablespoons of Worcestershire sauce,
1 pound of feta cheese, crumbled,2 cups of water</ingredients><directions>Cut all meat into small chunks, approximately the same size (about 1 to 1 1/2 inch squares).In a large bowl, pot, or pan, combine all ingredients, cover, and place in the refrigerator to marinate for about 10 hours.Preheat oven to 390?F (200?C).Transfer meats and marinade to a covered casserole dish or dutch oven and cook at 390?F (200?C) for 1 hour and 30-45 minutes until all meat is fork tender.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Stir Fried Ginger Chicken</name><contributor>Vibol Him</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a very tradition Cambodian dish.  Warm and comforting with a
very gentle heat, it is a perfect dish for cold days.</description><spices/><source>Cambodia</source><rating>mild</rating><ingredients>1LB of chicken breast
1 sliced onion
2 cloves of chopped garlic
1 chopped green onion
1 tbsp of oyster sauce
1/4 tbsp of salt
1/2 cup of finely chopped ginger
2 tbsp of vegetable oil</ingredients><directions>Slice the chicken breast into thin slices, about 2"x2" and 1/8" thick; set aside.
Heat up the vegetable oil in a pan at med-high heat.  Add the garlic to the pan and cook for
1-2 min.  Add the ginger and cook for another 2-3 min.  Add the chicken, salt and oyster
sauce.  2 min before the chicken is done, and the green onions.  When the chicken is done,
remove from the heat and serve with steamed rice.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Sticky Buns</name><contributor>Peter Elliott</contributor><category>Dessert</category><description>Sticky cinnamon buns, way to good to be healthy, family recipe for holiday's. For sharing with family and friends.</description><spices>Cinnnamon</spices><source>Family recipe stash.</source><rating>Sweet</rating><ingredients>1 c milk, 1/2 c sug, 2 tsp salt, 1/2 c shortening (marg), 1/2 c water, 1 pkg yeast, 1 egg, 2c flour, 2 1/2 - 3c flour, 1/4 c butter, 1/2 c br sug, (optional) pecans and half cherries. on dough; 1/4 c sugar, 1 tsp cinnamon, 1/2 C nuts or raisins.</ingredients><directions>Add and scald milk, sugar, salt, shortening (marg) -mix. Add water, yeast (instant or bread machine), egg, flour -beat. Add more flour -knead (work in with hands). Let rise 1 1/4 hr at 80F. Makes rolls in two 9x9 pans. Sticky part is half recipe. In pan; add butter, brown sugar, pecans*, and half cherries* (*optional). On dough: sugar, cinnamon, nuts/rasins -roll out dough and moisten with wet brush then sprinkle with mix - roll up and seal long edge, cut into 12 slices -place slices flat in pan -rise 1  hr. bake at 400 for 20 min or till done.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Cuban Tostenes</name><contributor>Sean Keith</contributor><category>Appetizer</category><description>This is a traditional Cuban appetizer or side dish that is used to accompany any main
main course. Tostenes are fried squished plantains and are often served with a garlic
sauce.</description><spices>Garlic Cloves</spices><source>Cuban Recipe</source><rating>Very Mild</rating><ingredients>2 Whole Green Plantains
Vegetable Oil
12 Garlic Cloves</ingredients><directions>Fill a frying pan with vegetable oil until the oil is around an inch/ inch and a half
deep. Put the stove on high and then once the oil is heated, add in plantain slices that
are around an inch thick. Fry for 2-4 minutes and then flip the slices. Fry for another
2-4 minutes and then let cool for 5 minutes. Once cooled, flatten the slices and fry them
once more for 2 minutes. The garlic dipping sauce is optional and goes great with this  dish.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Home Made Mac n Cheese</name><contributor>Daniel Peeler</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional Pasta recipe. I saw my father making it once. It should taste very cheesey and creamy. You can also not use butter and/or milk.</description><spices>none</spices><source>Household recipe</source><rating>Epicly good</rating><ingredients>1/3 cups milk
, butter4 cup shell noodles2cups cheese Wiz</ingredients><directions>In a medium pot, fill with 3/4 water; bring to a boil. Add shell noodles. stir often till noodles are fully cooked. Add Milk, butter and cheese Wiz and stir thourghly.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Spicy Italian Beef</name><contributor>Jeff Francom</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>A spiced beef which can be served as a main dish, or used as a filling for fajitas or sandwhiches. Note: Peperoncini are 2- 3 inch pickled mild peppers. Best found in Italian or pickled food sections.</description><spices>Peperoncini Peppers</spices><source>"Cooking With Beer"</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>1 boneless beef chuck roast (3 to 4 pounds)
1 jar (12 ounces) peperoncini
1 can (14 1/2 ounces) beef broth
1 bottle (12 ounces) amber ale
1 onion, peeled and minced
2 tablespoons Italian herb blend
1 loaf French Bread, cut into thick slices
10 slices provolone cheese (optional)</ingredients><directions>Slow Cooking Directions:
1. Trim fat from roast. Cut roast, if necessary, to fit in slow cooker, leacing meat in as many large pieces as possible.
2.Drain peppers; pull off stem ends and discard. Add peppers, broth, ale, onion and herb blend to slow cooker. DO NOT STIR. Cover; cook on LOW 8 to 10 hours.
3. Remove meat from slow cooker; pull with 2 forks. Return meat to slow cooker. Mix well.
4. Serve on French bread, topped with cheese if desired. Add additional sauce and peppers as desired.

Makes 8 to 10 servings.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Pasta with Herbs, Lemon and Shrimp Sauce</name><contributor>Daniel Kelly</contributor><category>Pasta</category><description>A flavourful pasta made for all the shrimp lovers out there.</description><spices>Hot pepper flakes
Basil
Oregano
Parsley
Black Pepper</spices><source>Aunt</source><rating>Medium</rating><ingredients>? cup (1 stick) butter
Grated zest of 1 large lemon
6 large garlic cloves, chopped
? tsp hot pepper flakes
2 tsp dried basil
2 tsp dried oregano
500 grams raw medium shrimp, shelled and deveined
? cup finely chopped fresh parsley
2 whole green onions, finely chopped
Salt
Lots of freshly ground black pepper
? cup fresh lemon juice
? cup freshly grated Parmesan cheese</ingredients><directions>Melt butter in a large, heavy skillet. Add lemon zest, garlic, red pepper flakes, basil and oregano and cook for two minutes. Add shrimp and saut? until opaque, about four minutes. Add parsley, green onions, salt and pepper and cook one minute. Stir in lemon juice and cook another minute, then toss with hot pasta and Parmesan cheese. Serve at once, with extra grated cheese. Recommended pasta: linguini or spaghetti.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Ukrainian Borsh</name><contributor>Kyryl Kozlov</contributor><category>Soup</category><description>In Russian and Ukraine cuisines borsch (borshch, borscht)  is very popular. It has a lot in common with another popular Russian dish - shchi. The main ingredient of any borsch is a beet. This is why any borsch has very reach taste and bright red color. Real borsch has a little bit sweetish taste. There are many very popular recipes of borsch. As with kasha you can experiment with ingredients and create you own borsch recipe, including vegan or vegetarian recipes.  You can try such ingredients as beans, cabbage, carrots, cucumber, potatoes, onions, or tomatoes, mushrooms, and meats (chicken, pork, or beef).</description><spices>Salt, pepper</spices><source>Recipe Zaar</source><rating>WAY TOO HOT</rating><ingredients>1 lb beef tenderloin steak
3 carrots (chopped)
3 onions (chopped)
2 big beets
3 medium potatoes
1 small head of cabbage</ingredients><directions>1 - Cook meat for 2 hours in *water* or until meat is very tender -reserve liquid (*add water if needed along the way)
2 - Get meat out of pot and shred-set aside.
3 - Saute' onion, carrots in small skillet-set aside with meat.
4 - Boil beets in meat broth/water until soft.
5 - Take beets out and shred.
6 - Cut up raw potatoes and raw cabbage.
7 - Put all-(the saute'ed mixture--beets, meat, raw ingredients)--together in broth/water.
8 - Boil until potatoes are done (about 30 minutes).
9 - Add spices according to taste.
10 - SERVE WITH SOUR CREAM!</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Shrimp Salad Rolls</name><contributor>Greg McLaren</contributor><category>Main Course</category><description>This is a twist on the normal shrimp or salad appetizer. This Thai wrap similar to an eggroll combines
different groups of flavors to create either a light meal or a delicious appetizer. Feel free to experiment with
adding your favorite twists to this recipe to make it your own.</description><spices>Hot pepper sauce</spices><source>Thai Recipe</source><rating>Slightly spicy</rating><ingredients>1 pkg(340g) High Liner White Wine and Herb Marinated Shrimp
1 cupeach sweet red perpp and mango thinly sliced
1 cup bean sprouts
1/4 cup each fresh coriander and red onion, thinkly sliced
Dash of hot pepper sauce (depending on how spicy you like it)
8 rice papers (21cm diameter works perfectly)
2 cups of packed baby spinach
1/2 cup sweet Thai chili sauce or plum sauce(dip)</ingredients><directions>1. Cook shrimp according to package directions, let cool completely. Remove the tails from the shimp if there
are any. Toss shrimp with red pepper, mango, bean sprouts, coriander, onion, oil, ginger, salt and hot pepper sauce until evenly coated.
2. Dip each rice paper wrapper into warm water for 20 seconds or until softened and pliable. Lay flat on clean damp towel. Center 1/4 cup
of spinach along hte bottom third of the wrapper leaving 1 inch border. top with 1/2 cup of shrimp mixture.
3. Starting at bottom, roll tightly just until folling is covered. Fold hte sides in and continue to roll tightly until folling is enclosed.
Cut in half diagonally, and repeat for each wrapper.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Kabab-e Barg</name><contributor>Kaveh Aminian Razavi</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional Iranian food. Almost every single resturant in Iran serves this food since
it is very popular.</description><spices>Garlic, black pepper, saffron, salt, sumac</spices><source>http://personal.ee.surrey.ac.uk/Personal/F.Mokhtarian/recipes/</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>(6 servings)
fillet of lamb, 1 kg
extra-virgin olive oil, 1/2 cup
3 onions, grated
2 cloves of garlic, crushed
6 medium tomatos
saffron, 1/2 teaspoon (optional)
salt
black pepper
sumac (optional)</ingredients><directions>Prepare marinade: mix olive oil, onions, garlic, saffron, salt and black pepper. Cut lamb into 1 cm
thick and 4-5 cm long pieces. Do not remove all the fat as you will need it to melt. Marinate
overnight (preferrably 24 hours) in refrigerator. Container should be covered.
Thread lamb on long, thin metal skewers. Thread whole tomatoes separately on another skewer.
Brush with marinade. Barbeque for about 5-10 minutes on each side, turning frequently.
Kabab Barg can also be made in the oven. Prepare as before, pre-heat the grill to a high temperature
and place just under the grill, again turning frequently. Serve hot with basmati rice or on
middle-eastern bread. If served with rice, some sumac may be sprinkled on.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Hippie Pancakes</name><contributor>Greg Poapst</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a recipe for those who are morally conscious. It has all natural and organic ingredients. It should taste a bit saltier than other pancakes.</description><spices>Salt</spices><source>The 60s</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>1 C. unbleached wheat blend flour
2 tsp. baking powder
1 tsp. unrefined sugar
1/4 tsp. coarse kosher salt
1 free-range egg
1 1/4 C. hormone-free milk
1 tsp. organic vegetable oil</ingredients><directions>Pre-heat griddle over medium heat. Combine dry ingredients in a mixing bowl. Stir in egg, milk and oil. Use a large spoon or gravy ladle to transfer pancake batter to the griddle. Pancakes are ready to flip when large bubbles can be seen on top.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Stuffed peppers</name><contributor>Kuralay Omarova</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is the easiest meal for everybody, espesially for students because it doesn't need to much ingredients and doesn't need to much time.</description><spices>salt, paprika and any spices that you like</spices><source>from own experience</source><rating>medium</rating><ingredients>4 green pepper
200 gramm of ground beef
onion
200 gramm of cooked rice
and spices</ingredients><directions>Wash peppers then remove stem ends, seeds, and white membranes. chop onions and mix it with ground beef and with rice and some salt and paprika.fill the peppers with this mix, after stir fry onions for 3 mins and put peppers to that bowl add some water and spices  and cook it for 30 min</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Spicy Spaghetti</name><contributor>Benjamin Coyle</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>null</description><spices>Dried red chili
Black pepper
cayenne pepper</spices><source>Father</source><rating>Hot</rating><ingredients>2 packages of ground beef
1/2 chopped onion
1 onion, chopped
2 garlic cloves, finely chopped
2 dried red chilies
1 can tomato paste
3 tablespoons black pepper
1 can diced tomatoes
1 package spaghetti</ingredients><directions>In a large pot, empty both packages of groud beef. At the same time, fill a medium pot halfway with water; bring it to a boil. When your meat is finished cooking add the tomato paste, diced tomatoes, garlic, chilies, pepper, and onion. Stir together on low heat When water comes to a boil, take one handful of spaghetti for each person eating, break it in
half, and add the pasta into the pot slowly, to avoid splashing yourself. Stir the pasta frequently to avoid having the pasta stick together. Cook for 8 minutes. Drain and serve pasta. Top with sauce. Preserve the sauce by covering it with a paper cloth and seran wrap. Makes about 6 servings.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Vegan Banana Spiced Pancakes</name><contributor>Benjamin Jeffery</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>A wonderful vegan breakfast from the post punk kitchen. They are very filling, full of delicious banana flavour, and taste great if you add some berries (especially currants).</description><spices>Cinnamon
Allspice</spices><source>www.theppk.com</source><rating>not spicy</rating><ingredients>1 1/2 cups whole wheat flour
2 tablespoons raw sugar
2 teaspoons baking powder
1/2 teaspoon salt
sprinkle of cinnamon
sprinkle of allspice
1 1/4 cup vanilla soymilk
3 medium sized ripe bannannas peeled and sliced
oil or non-stick cooking spray</ingredients><directions>1. In a bowl combine all the dry ingredients exept bananas.
2. Next in a blender add in half of the bananas and the soymilk and puree until smooth. Pour wet to dry and fold in unprocessed bananas.
3. Heat the griddle with the oil on there over medium heat.
Put some of the pancake batter on the griddle and cook until lots of tiny bubbles start to pop. Flip the pancakes over and continue to cook until pancakes are browned. Serve with syrup.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>World's Best Banana Bread</name><contributor>Chris Fillmore</contributor><category>Snack</category><description>This is the best banana bread in the world. If you think you've tasted better, you are wrong.</description><spices>None</spices><source>Van Nostrand heritage</source><rating>Not hot, it's banana bread.</rating><ingredients>3 overripe bananas
1.5 cups sugar
1 egg
1 tsp vanilla
1.5 cups all-purpose flour
0.5 tsp salt
1 tsp baking powder
1 tsp baking soda
2 tbsp butter, melted</ingredients><directions>Preheat oven to 350 F. In a large bowl, mash bananas. Add sugar, egg, and vanilla. Mix well. In a separate bowl, whisk together flour, salt, baking powder, and baking soda. Add slowly to banana mixture, mixing as you go. Once it is completely mixed, add melted butter. Bake for 45 minutes in oven, or until toothpick in center comes out clean! Enjoy.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Kristi's Tetrazzini</name><contributor>Paul Raubic</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Great to make the night before, especially good for a potluck contribution</description><spices>Onions, garlic,paprika</spices><source>www.allrecipes.com</source><rating>Mildly hot</rating><ingredients>4 skinless, boneless chicken breast halves
1 (12 ounce) package wide egg noodles
2 (10.75 ounce) cans condensed cream of chicken soup
2 fresh broccoli, minced
3 stalks celery, chopped
1 cup fresh sliced mushrooms
1 onion, chopped
salt to taste
ground black pepper to taste
1 pinch seasoned salt
1/4 cup shredded Cheddar cheese
1/4 cup mozzarella cheese, shredded
1 pinch paprika</ingredients><directions>Preheat oven to 325 degrees F (165 degrees C). Coat a 13x9 inch baking dish with cooking spray.
In a 3 quart saucepan, boil chicken for about 30 minutes. Drain, and cut into bite sized pieces.
Meanwhile, cook pasta according to directions. Drain.
In a large bowl, mix together cream of chicken soup, broccoli, celery, sliced mushrooms, seasoned salt, salt, pepper, and onion. Stir in pasta and chicken pieces. Spread mixture into the prepared baking dish. Sprinkle with shredded cheese and paprika.
Bake for 45 minutes.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Good Old Meat Pie</name><contributor>Mohamad Hamadi</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>great deep dish meat pie made with potatoes, carrots and peas in a rich gravy. Lamb chicken or pork can be used in place of beef. A great recipe for leftover meat!"</description><spices>Black pepper</spices><source>white mans recipe</source><rating>HOT</rating><ingredients>1 recipe pastry for a 9 inch single crust pie
3 tablespoons margarine
1/2 cup chopped onion
1 potato, diced
1/3 cup all-purpose flour
1/2 teaspoon dried oregano
1/2 teaspoon garlic powder
1/4 teaspoon black pepper
1 1/4 cups beef broth
1 carrot, chopped
1 cup frozen green peas
2 cups cubed cooked or leftover beef</ingredients><directions>1. Preheat the oven to 425 degrees F (220 degrees C). On a lightly floured surface, roll the pie crust out into a 12 inch circle. Set aside.
2. Melt margarine in a saucepan over medium heat. Add potato and onion, and cook until the onion is tender, but not brown. Sprinkle the flour over the mixture, and stir to blend. Season with oregano, black pepper and garlic powder. Pour in the beef broth, and add the peas, carrot and beef. Bring to a boil. Transfer the mixture to a 2 quart casserole dish, and place the pastry over the top. Cut slits for steam, and flute the edges.
3. Place on a baking sheet, and bake for 25 to 30 minutes, or until crust is golden. Let stand 10 minutes before serving to thicken.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Shawarma</name><contributor>Sakhravi</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional Arabic recipe.Shawarma is thinly sliced cuts of meat, like chicken, beef, goat, lamb, and sometimes turkey, rolled into a large piece of flatbread or pita that has been steamed or heated. Inside the pita, foods like hummus, tahini, pickles, vegetables, and even french fries are added. Think of shawarma as a taco or burrito Middle Eastern style</description><spices>Red Chilli Powder
Hot Pepper
Garlic Powder
Turmeric Powder
Salt
Feelings - Gemini</spices><source>Arabic recipe</source><rating>Hot and Spicy</rating><ingredients>5 kg bonelesse chicken,
400 g Lemon juice,
400 g olive oil
150 g rushe garlic
1T Salt,
2 t Pepper,
100 g cordamon powder,
100 g cunin powder,
100 g Coriander powder,
2 T mustard,
1 c White vinegar,
1 ds cloves powder,
1 ds nutmic grined,
1 c plane youghurt.</ingredients><directions>Remove the skin from chicken,cut chicken into 1/4 flaten the chicken pieces ,marinatad with all ingredients,keep them in the refrigerator over night (12hours),insert the meat on ashawarma spick on top each other (pc by pe till the chicken are combleted 2. Grilli on a shawarma machine or slice them and grill on top frying grill3. Served as sandwiches or in a plate , served with garlic sauce ,mint leaves and pickels.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Blackened Fish</name><contributor>parwiz dawod</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This recipe calls for trout, but catfish or red snapper would be equally good.
Be sure to have a well ventilated kitchen</description><spices>dried thyme</spices><source>allrecipes.com</source><rating>4/5 great</rating><ingredients>tablespoon paprika
2 teaspoons dry mustard
1 teaspoon cayenne pepper
1 teaspoon ground cumin
1 teaspoon black pepper
1 teaspoon white pepper
1 teaspoon dried thyme
1 teaspoon salt
3/4 cup unsalted butter, melted
6 (4 ounce) fillets trout
1/4 cup unsalted butter, melted</ingredients><directions>In a small bowl, mix together paprika, dry mustard,
cayenne pepper, cumin, black pepper, white pepper, thyme and salt;
set aside. Heat a heavy cast iron pan on high heat
until extremely hot, about 10 minutes.

Pour 3/4 cup melted butter into a shallow dish. Dip each fillet
into butter, turning once to coat both sides. Sprinkle both sides
of fillets with spice mixture, and gently pat mixture onto fish.

Place fillets into hot pan without crowding. Carefully pour about 1 teaspoon
melted butter over each fillet. Cook until fish has a charred appearance, about
2 minutes. Turn fillets, spoon 1 teaspoon melted butter over each, and cook until
charred. Repeat with remaining fish.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>World's Best Banana Bread</name><contributor>Chris Fillmore</contributor><category>Snack</category><description>This is the best banana bread in the world. If you think you've tasted better, you are wrong.</description><spices>None</spices><source>Van Nostrand heritage</source><rating>Not hot, it's banana bread.</rating><ingredients>3 overripe bananas
1.5 cups sugar
1 egg
1 tsp vanilla
1.5 cups all-purpose flour
0.5 tsp salt
1 tsp baking powder
1 tsp baking soda
2 tbsp butter, melted</ingredients><directions>Preheat oven to 350 F. In a large bowl, mash bananas.
Add sugar, egg, and vanilla. Mix well. In a separate bowl,
whisk together flour, salt, baking powder, and baking soda.
Add slowly to banana mixture, mixing as you go. Once it is
completely mixed, add melted butter. Bake for 45 minutes in
oven, or until toothpick in center comes out clean! Enjoy.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Cameron Three Bean Chili</name><contributor>100740541</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This spicy chili contains no meat, but a lot of protein. It's a great choice for vegetarians.</description><spices>Cumin
Chili Powder
Garlic</spices><source>Family Recipe</source><rating>Pretty spicy</rating><ingredients>2 Tablespoons olive oil
2 medium onions, chopped
1 medium red pepper, chopped
1 medium green pepper, chopped
1 large jalapeno pepper (seeded, de-veined and chopped)
6 cloves garlic, minced
1 cup beer
2 16 oz. cans diced tomatoes
1 14 oz. can black beans
1 16 oz. can dark red kidney beans
1 tablespoon ground cumin
2 tablespoons chili powder
1 tablespoon hot pepper sauce
1 teaspoon salt
1 can vegetarian refried beans with chiles</ingredients><directions>In a large pot, add olive oil and warm over medium heat.  Add onion, peppers, and garlic.  Saute until soft.Add tomatoes, black beans and kidney beans, stirring well to combine.  Add cumin, chili powder, hot sauce and salt.  Stir in refried beans.  Reduce heat to low and simmer for 15 minutes.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Cold Sesame Noodles</name><contributor>Xi Chen</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional Chinese noodle recipe. Lots of Chinese people,
specially people from Beijing and northeast part of China like it very much, me as well.
The taste is great and can be varies by adding different sauce.</description><spices>Dried red chili</spices><source>Chinese recipe</source><rating>Not very Hot</rating><ingredients>1 cup mung bean sprouts
12 ounces egg noodles
4 1/2 tablespoons sesame oil, divided
1 cucumber
3 tablespoons red rice, red wine or balsamic vinegar
2 tablespoons soy sauce
2 teaspoons granulated sugar
1 teaspoon hot chili oil
1 cup cooked chicken, shredded
2 tablespoons toasted sesame seeds</ingredients><directions>Blanch the mung bean sprouts in boiling water and drain thoroughly.
Cook the noodles according to the package directions. Drain the noodles thoroughly
and toss with 1 to 1 /2 tablespoons sesame oil.
Peel the cucumber, cut in half lengthwise and remove the seeds, and julienne.
To prepare the sauce, combine the remaining sesame oil, vinegar, soy sauce, and hot chili oil.
Set aside.
To serve, place the noodles on a serving plate. Arrange the cooked chicken, cucumber
and bean sprouts over top. Pour the sauce over. Sprinkle with the toasted sesame seeds. Serve cold.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Chicken Khurma</name><contributor>Nikhil P. H.</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional North Indian recipe which is a not very hot but a lot of spices are used in it. This particular dish has gravy and goes well with rotis or naans.</description><spices>Cloves, Dried Cinnamon Sticks, Bay leaf, Cumin Seeds, Corriander Powder</spices><source>Indian Recipe</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>1-1.5lb chicken
2 medium Onions
3 big Green Chillies, chopped
1/2 inch Ginger, chopped
1/4 cup Coconut grated
1/2 tsp turmeric powder
1/2 tsp Coriander powder
1/2 tsp Cumin seed powder
1 tsp Saunf
Garam masala
1 tsp (cloves - 1, cinnamon stick - 1, bay leaf - 1)
Salt to taste
4 tsp Oil
2 tbsp Coriander leaves</ingredients><directions>Grind the ginger, saunf and green chillies with half the onions (with little water) and set aside.
Grind the grated coconut with some water and set aside.
In a pan, heat oil and add the garam masala items and then the rest of the onions.
Saute the onions for a while. Then, add the chillies-ginger-onion paste and saute.
Then, add the turmeric powder, coriander powder, cumin seed powder and salt.
Fry this mixture for a while maybe adding a little bit of water.
Then, add the chicken pieces and some water and cover the pan with a lid and allow to cook for 1/2 hr - 1 hour (or until chicken is done).
When the chicken is cooked, stir in the coconut paste with some water and bring to a boil.
Add the coriander leaves for garnish.
Goes well with rice and rotis.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Superbowl Chili</name><contributor>Nikolas LeBlanc</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>A simple and customizeable slow cooker chili recipe</description><spices>Chili powder</spices><source>Slow cooker recipe</source><rating>HOT</rating><ingredients>2 packages of ground beef
2 packages of hot italian sausage
2 cans of tomato paste
2 to 3 cans of diced tomatoes (any flavour) (drained)
2 cans of kidney beans (drained)
2 cans of chicken broth
3 bell peppers (any colour)
1 jar of hot peppers (drained)
1 bottle of hot sauce
1 package of chili powder</ingredients><directions>Cooking Superbowl Chili should be a very personal experience, and it should taste a little different every time you cook it. Keep this in mind when you get started. Since you're going to need it in time for the Superbowl, and since a good chili should be cooked for roughly a day and a half, you'll want to get started early Saturday morning. I'd be more specific with the ingredients, but really it's something you have to get a feel for, and it's largely dependent on the size of your slow cooker. You'll need a slow cooker, and lots of meat. Preferably ground beef, and hot italian sausage. Typically you'll want to grab 2 regular sized packages of ground beef, and 2 packages of hot italian sausages. First you'll want to squeeze all of the meat out of the italian sausage, this part is fun, and sloppy. Collect it with your ground beef and brown them both together (cook it all halfway - don't worry, this meat will cook for a day and a half in the slow cooker later on). While the meat cooks, cover it with any spices you like and dice your bell peppers. When the meat is ready, drop it in your slow cooker and stir in your peppers along with 1 can of everything, half of your hot peppers (don't pour the juice in), and some of your hot sauce and chili powder. Be sure that you have at least 1 inch of clearance between your chili and the ridge of your slow cooker so nothing overflows. Now the fun begins. Set your slow cooker to Low and put the lid on it - remember, this is a slow and steady process. Now go do something else, and let the chili smell take over your house for an hour or two. But keep a lazy eye on it. You'll notice that as the chili cooks, condensation forms on the lid of the slow cooker, and it drips back into the chili, making it watery. This is ok for now. Just keep stirring it every once and awhile and if it gets very watery, leave the lid off and let it cook for about a half hour, this will dry the chili out and give you some room to work with. Just repeat this process until the Superbowl, and don't worry about letting it cook while you sleep. As long as you have a good inch between the edge of the slow cooker and the surface of the chili, you'll be fine, but be sure to leave the lid on while you sleep or else you'll end up with a real messy slow cooker full of crusty chili. When you get to whereever you're going to watch the game, add the rest of your ingredients. This will add layers of flavour to your chili since some will have been cooking for days and some will be real fresh. Then eat up. Enjoy the game. And get a good book in your bathroom cause you'll probably be spending alot of time there for the next couple of days.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Three Bean Salad</name><contributor>Nadra Waheed</contributor><category>Salad</category><description>Delicious, health easy to make recipe.</description><spices>1 cup white sugar
1 cup vinegar
1/2 cup salad oil
1 1/2 teaspoon salt
1 12 teaspoon pepper</spices><source>Malaysia recipe</source><rating>Not Hot</rating><ingredients>*error in data*</ingredients><directions>Put all of the beans into a large bowl and mix well. Mix the beans gently so you don't mush    the canned green and yellow beans. Place all dressing ingredients into a jar and shake well or mix together well in a bowl. Pour the dressing over the beans, mix and refrigerate. This is best made the day before to allow the flavors time to meld together</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Red rice</name><contributor>307835</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a traditional African recipe. I found it in an African cooking book. It can be prepared spicy depending on your preference.</description><spices>Red/Black Pepper</spices><source>African recipe</source><rating>Medium</rating><ingredients>2 c water, 1 3lb chicken cut into pieces, Pcs, 2 16oz cans stewed tomatoes, 2 t Salt, 1/4 t Black pepper, 3/4 c Cooked smoked ham (cubed), 1 c Uncooked Rice, 1 large Onions (sliced), 3 c cabbage (shredded), 1/2 lb Fresh green beans quartered and stems removed OR 1 10oz pk frozen beans, 1/4 t Ground cinnamon, 1/4 t Cayenne pepper.</ingredients><directions>1. Pour water into a large pot. Add the chicken, tomatoes, salt, and pepper. 2. Cover; bring to a boil, reduce the heat, and simmer for 30 minutes. 3. Stir in the ham, rice, onion, cabbage, green beans, cinnamon, and cayenne pepper. 4. Bring to a boil, then reduce heat to low. Cover and simmer until the chicken is fork-tender and the rice is cooked, 25-30 minutes.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Paneer Tikka on a Vegetable Platter</name><contributor>Niravkumar Patel</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a Indian traditional recipe. I found it from world wide web, and also
my mom cooks this all the time. It should taste a spicy and a little bit sweet. You can adjeust the level of spices.</description><spices>Red Chilli
cumin power
Ginger
Garlic Paste
bell peppers
red onions
chat masala</spices><source>Indian Recipe
Paneer
Tandoori Power
Sugar
Minced corinader leaves
minced mint leaves
carrots</source><rating>MEDIUM HOT</rating><ingredients>1/2 cup curd (yoghurt)
1 tsp red chilli powder
1 tsp cumin powder
2 tsp tandoori powder
1/2 tsp sugar
2 tsps ginger garlic paste
1 tbspn minced coriander leaves
1/2 tbsp minced mint leaves

3 cups of vegetables( bell peppers, red onions,
tomatoes, mushrooms, carrots)
2-3 tsp chat masala</ingredients><directions>Mix together all the ingredients for the marinade with
some salt and set aside. Cut the veggies into juliennes and add the chat masala
and remaining marinade(if any)to them. Brush the marinade on the paneer slices and refrigerate for
2-3 hrs. Heat some butter/oil and fry the paneer on both sides till well done.
Alternatively, you can brush each paneer piece with some oil and bake in a 350 deg f
oven till done. Heat some oil and stir fry the veggies till they are crisp. Just like
the paneer, you can alternatively bake these in an oven till they are done. In a platter,
arrange the paneer slices in the middle and place the veggies around it. Garnish with lemon wedges and serve hot.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Alfredo Sauce</name><contributor>Bruno Colantonio</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a Italian recipe. It taste very rich and creamy. It is usually served with
feterchini noodles but it can be used with any pasta noodle. If the
Parmesan cheese doesn't melt well, you can substitute it with Gruyere cheese.</description><spices>parsley</spices><source>Italian recipe that i found on the internet at
http://allrecipes.com/Recipe/Alfredo-Sauce-2/Detail.aspx</source><rating>rich &amp; creamy</rating><ingredients>1/4 cup butter
1 cup heavy cream
1 clove garlic, crushed
1 1/2 cups freshly grated Parmesan cheese
1/4 cup chopped fresh parsley</ingredients><directions>Melt butter in a medium saucepan over medium low heat. Add cream and simmer
for 5 minutes, then add garlic and cheese and whisk quickly, heating through.
Stir in parsley and serve.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Kool-Aid</name><contributor>David Johnson</contributor><category>Beverage</category><description>This is a tasty and thirst-quenching fruit drink that will satisfy your thirsty needs.</description><spices>None</spices><source>Family Recipe</source><rating>VERY SWEET!</rating><ingredients>1 cup sugar
1 packet of Kool-Aid
8 cups of water</ingredients><directions>Put the 8 cups of water into a large drink tupperware. Slowly pour and stir in the Kool-Aid powder, mixing the colouring and flavouring into the water. After the entire drink is the same colour, slowly stir in the cup of sugar until completely dissolved. Pour and enjoy. Refrigerate.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Easy Tasty Chili</name><contributor>James Howell</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a recipe for chili that my mother taught me to make
when I was a child. It's simple, quick, and easy to make. And it's tasty!</description><spices>Chili powder</spices><source>Family recipe</source><rating>Spicy</rating><ingredients>1 lb lean ground beef4 cans tomato soup2 cans kidney beans
1 tablespoon onion flakes3 teaspoons chili powder</ingredients><directions>In a large pot, add the lean ground beef and sprinkle the onion flakes over top. Cook over medium heat for about 30 minutes until the meat is brown and the fat has boiled off. Then add the 4 cans of soup and 2 cans of kidney beans. Add 3 teaspoons of chili powder, add more or less to taste. Stir until everything's mixed in. Continue heating for another 15 minutes until it starts to boil, then serve. Works great with bread or buns for dipping.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Franks Hot Ham Sandwhich</name><contributor>Brendan Cooper</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a homemade ham sandwhich reciple I invented. It has a lot of good spice and tons of flavour compared to any regular sandwhich.</description><spices>Franks Red Hot</spices><source>Homemade</source><rating>HOT</rating><ingredients>1-2 slices of Ham
Franks Red Hot
Melted Cheddar/Swiss Cheese
Honey Mustard
Fresh Whole Wheat Toasted Bread
Mayo
Tomatoes</ingredients><directions>Put bread in toaster, melt cheese and ham on bread in oven with franks red hot on it.
Then put the rest of the listed ingredients in between toast and enjoy! Careful its hot!</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Banana Chocolate Chip Muffins</name><contributor>daniel yang</contributor><category>Desert</category><description>None</description><spices>none</spices><source>Homemade</source><rating>good</rating><ingredients>1 medium egg.
1 cups of flour.
cup of milk.
cup of chocolate chips.
cup of brown sugar.
cup of pur??ed banana.
cup of vegetable oil.
3 teaspoons of baking powder.
teaspoon of salt.
teaspoon of cinnamon.
teaspoon of nutmeg.</ingredients><directions>Blend all of the ingredients together thoroughly.

Pour the mixture into greased muffin tins, about two-thirds full.

Bake at 400??F (205??C) for twenty minutes.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Tomatos with fried eggs</name><contributor>100710161</contributor><category>Side dish</category><description>A traditional Chinese side dish easy to make and easy to adjust to personal perferrences.Originally meant to be mild, but can be made spicy or sweet and sour.</description><spices>(Optional)</spices><source>Mom</source><rating>Goes with anything</rating><ingredients>2-3 eggs, Scrambled but not cooked yet
2 tomatos, diced
half onion, chopped
3 teaspoons vegetable oil
1 teaspoon salt
(sugar and/or dry red pepper optional)
1 cup of water (depends on how juicy is the kind of tomato you are using)</ingredients><directions>First put oil into the frying pan and heat it up but not boil. Then the tomatos because tomatos takes longer to cook. Put salt ,sugar and/or dry red pepper or other spices into the scranbled eggs while your tomatos are cooking. Once the tomatos become soft and not much water left, push them to the side of the frying pan so the eggs can touch the bottom then put in the eggs. The eggs will be ready in a minate so mix them and it is ready to be served. It gose with anything.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Chocolate Chip Cookies</name><contributor>Daniel Stone</contributor><category>Dessert</category><description>A delicious recipe for homemade chocolate chip cookies</description><spices>None</spices><source>Mom</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>3/4 cup sugar, 3/4 cup packed brown sugar, 1 cup butter, softened, 2 large eggs, beaten,  1 teaspoon vanilla extract,  2 1/4 cups all-purpose flour, 1 teaspoon baking soda, 3/4 teaspoon salt, 2 cups semisweet chocolate chips, if desired, 1 cup chopped pecans</ingredients><directions>Preheat oven to 375 degrees.  Mix sugar, brown sugar, butter, vanilla and eggs in a large bowl by hand.  Stir in flour, baking soda, and salt.  The dough will be very stiff.  Stir in chocolate chips and pecans if desired.  Drop dough by rounded tablespoonfuls 2 inches apart onto ungreased cookie sheet.  Bake 8 to 10 minutes or until light brown.  The centers will be soft.  Let cool completely then remove from cookie sheet.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Quick Tex-Mex Chili</name><contributor>Matt Imtiaz</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Serve this speedy chili over cooked rice or in tacos. Great for all occasions.</description><spices>Chili Power</spices><source>CanadianFamily</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>1 lb extra-lean ground beef (500 g)1 onion, chopped2 cloves garlic, minced1 tbsp chili powder (15 mL)1/2 tsp each dried oregano, paprika and black pepper (2 mL)2 cups mild salsa (500 mL, or one 430-mL jar)1 cup beef stock( 250 mL)1 can (19 oz/540 mL) red kidney beans, drained and rinsed1 can (12 oz/341 mL) whole kernel corn, drained1/4 cup chopped fresh coriander or parsley (50 mL)Salt to taste</ingredients><directions>1.In a large nonstick skillet over mediumhigh heat, combine beef and onion; cook for about 10 minutes, stirring often and breaking up beef with the back of a spoon, until beef is no longer pink. Stir in garlic, chili powder, oregano, paprika and pepper; cook, stirring, for 1-2 minutes.2. Stir in salsa and stock. Bring to a boil.  Reduce heat to medium-low; simmer, covered, for 10 minutes, until thickened.3.Add kidney beans and corn; cook, covered, for 5 minutes. Taste and add salt and more pepper if necessary; stir in coriander. Serve with cooked rice or tacos. Serves 4-6</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Kool-Aid</name><contributor>David Johnson</contributor><category>Beverage</category><description>This is a tasty and thirst-quenching fruit drink that will satisfy your thirsty needs.</description><spices>None</spices><source>Family Recipe</source><rating>VERY SWEET!</rating><ingredients>1 cup sugar
1 packet of Kool-Aid
8 cups of water</ingredients><directions>Put the 8 cups of water into a large drink tupperware. Slowly pour and stir in the Kool-Aid powder, mixing the colouring and flavouring into the water. After the entire drink is the same colour, slowly stir in the cup of sugar until completely dissolved. Pour and enjoy. Refrigerate.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Dumpling</name><contributor>Christine Yu</contributor><category>DimSum</category><description>Dumplings, pinyin: ShuiJao (Water Dumpling) Typically consist of a ground meat and/or vegetable wrapped into a thinly rolled piece of dough, which is then sealed by pressing the edges together or by crimping. Dumplings are one of the major foods eaten during the Chinese New Year. They can be eaten with soy sauce.</description><spices>Sugar,</spices><source>About.com: Chinese Food</source><rating>Sweet</rating><ingredients>Jiaozi dough:
3 cups all-purpose flour
up to 1 1/4 cups cold water
1/4 teaspoon salt
Filling:
1 cup ground pork or beef
1 TB soy sauce
1 teaspoon salt
1 TB Chinese rice wine or dry sherry
1/4 teaspoon freshly ground white pepper, or to taste
3 TB sesame oil
1/2 green onion, finely minced
1 1/2 cups finely shredded Napa cabbage
4 tablespoons shredded bamboo shoots
2 slices fresh ginger, finely minced
1 clove garlic, peeled and finely minced</ingredients><directions>Stir the salt into the flour. Slowly stir in the cold water, adding as much as is necessary to form a smooth dough. Don't add more water than is ncessary. Knead the dough into a smooth ball. Cover the dough and let it rest for at least 30 minutes.
While the dough is resting, prepare the filling ingredients. Add the soy sauce, salt, rice wine and white pepper to the meat, stirring in only one direction. Add the remaining ingredients, stirring in the same direction, and mix well.
To make the dumpling dough: knead the dough until it forms a smooth ball. Divide the dough into 60 pieces. Roll each piece out into a circle about 3-inches in diameter.
Place a small portion (about 1 level tablespoon) of the filling into the middle of each wrapper. Wet the edges of the dumpling with water. Fold the dough over the filling into a half moon shape and pinch the edges to seal. Continue with the remainder of the dumplings.
To cook, bring a large pot of water to a boil. Add half the dumplings, giving them a gentle stir so they don't stick together. Bring the water to a boil, and add 1/2 cup of cold water. Cover and repeat. When the dumplings come to a boil for a third time, they are ready. Drain and remove. If desired, they can be pan-fried at this point.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Easy simple chili</name><contributor>Sean Gilbert</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a simple easy chili to make, very thick.</description><spices>chili seasoning mix packet, or your own special mix, i won't give away mine.</spices><source>small town kitchen recipe</source><rating>MODERATE</rating><ingredients>1/2 cup chopped onion
1 tablespoon vegetable oil
1 1/2 pounds ground beef
1 envolope chili seasoning mix
1 can diced tomatoes, drained
1 can kidney beans, drained
1 tablespoon brown sugar
1/2 diced green pepper</ingredients><directions>Heat oil in a large, heavy skillet. Cook ground beef and onions
over medium heat until it is no longer pink. Stir in chili seasoning
mix, then add remaining ingredients. Bring to a boil. Reduce heat,
cover, and simmer for 10 minutes. Serve with cornbread or crackers.
Serves 6.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Pilaf</name><contributor>Irina Bronipolsky</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a middle eastern main course, consisting of broiled rice</description><spices>Cumin Seeds</spices><source>Middle Eastern recipe</source><rating>Not hot</rating><ingredients>3 cups of whole grain rice
6 cups of water
2 medium sized carrots
Can of chicken broth
1 onion, chopped
half a garlic clover
2 teaspoons of olive oil
1 teaspoon salt</ingredients><directions>In a large pot, combine the 3 cups of rice and 6 cups of water. Add a teaspoon of salt.
Cook until rice becomes partially soft. Prep the can of broth wih half of a garlic clove into the pot.
Add the chopped onions in, and stir. Then cut the two carrots into smaller pieces, and throw them into
the pot - continue to stir. Carefully pour the contents of the pot into another heated pot ( on a low setting).
Cover the pot, and let it simmer.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Terrific Turkey Chilli</name><contributor>Patrick Fung</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Using some fresh and some canned ingredients,
this chili is a snap to throw together and will keep you craving it for days.
If you like beans in your chili, garbanzos right out of the can are great in this.</description><spices>Taco Seasoning,
Ground Coriander,
Dried Oregano,
Chilli Pepper Flakes</spices><source>http://allrecipes.com/</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>3 tablespoons vegetable oil, divided
1 1/2 pounds ground turkey
1 (1 ounce) package taco seasoning mix
1 teaspoon ground coriander
1 teaspoon dried oregano
1 teaspoon chili pepper flakes
2 tablespoons tomato paste
1 (14.5 ounce) can beef broth
1 (7 ounce) can salsa
1 (14.5 ounce) can crushed tomatoes, or coarsely chopped tomatoes packed in puree
1 (7 ounce) can chopped green chile peppers
1 medium onion, finely chopped
1 green bell pepper, diced
3 medium zucchini, halved lengthwise and sliced
1 bunch green onions, chopped
1 cup sour cream
1 cup shredded Cheddar cheese</ingredients><directions>Heat 1 tablespoon of oil in a large stock pot over medium-high heat.
Crumble turkey into the pot, stirring with a wooden spoon to break apart as much as possible.
Season with taco seasoning mix, coriander, oregano, chili flakes, and tomato paste,
and mix until meat is evenly coated with seasonings.
Continue cooking, reducing heat if necessary, until turkey is well browned.
Pour in beef broth, and simmer to reduce liquid slightly, about 5 minutes.
Add salsa, tomatoes, and green chilies, and continue cooking at a moderate simmer for ten minutes.
Adjust the thickness at any time you feel necessary by adding water.
While chili is still cooking, heat one tablespoon of oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat.
Cook onion and green bell pepper, stirring occasionally for 5 minutes, or until onion is translucent
and bell pepper is lightly browned. Add onion and bell pepper to the chili,
and continue cooking at a very low simmer.
In the same skillet, heat the remaining tablespoon of oil over medium-high heat.
Add the zucchini, and cook stirring occasionally, for 5 minutes, or until lightly browned.
Add the zucchini to the chili, reduce heat, and continue cooking 15 minutes more.
Again, adjust the consistency with water as needed.
Ladle chili into serving bowls. Top with sour cream, green onion, and cheddar cheese, and serve.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Russian Borscht</name><contributor>Evgeni Petrenko</contributor><category>Soup</category><description>null</description><spices>Green bell pepper, dried dill weed, dround black pepper</spices><source>Family recipe</source><rating>*****</rating><ingredients>6 cups water
3/4 teblespoon salt
1/2 cup finely chopped carrots
1/4 cup chopped green bell pepper, divided
1/2 stalk celery, chopped
1 medium beet
1/2 cup canned peeled and diced tomatoes
3 potatoes, quartered
1/3 cup butter
1/2 cup chopped onion
1 1/2 cups canned tomatoes
3 cups finely shredded cabbage, divided
1/4 cup heavy cream
3/4 cup diced potatoes
1 tablespoon dried dill weed
1/4 teaspoon ground black pepper to taste salt and freshly ground black pepper to taste</ingredients><directions>Place water, salt, carrots, 1/2 of the bell pepper, celery, beet, tomatoes, and quartered potatoes in a large stock pot over high heat. Bring to a boil.
Melt 1/3 cup butter in a separate skillet over medium heat. Saute onions in butter until tender, approximately 5 minutes. Stir in tomatoes, reduce heat to medium low, and simmer for 15 minutes. Remove 1/2 cup of sauce from skillet, and set aside. Stir half of the cabbage into the skillet with remaining sauce, and continue simmering 5 minutes more, or until tender.
Remove beet from boiling liquid and discard. Remove potatoes with a slotted spoon or tongs, and place in a bowl with remaining 1 tablespoon of butter and the cream. Mash together until smooth.
Return the 1/2 cup of reserved onion-tomato sauce to the stock pot. Stir in diced potatoes, and simmer until just tender but still firm, approximately 5 minutes. Increase heat to a low boil, and stir in remaining cabbage, tomato sauce, and mashed potatoes. Reduce heat and simmer a few minutes more. Stir in remaining bell pepper, season with black pepper, and serve.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Balsamic Veal Escalopes</name><contributor>Patrick Gohard</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a easy to make everyday recipe. I found it on Reader's Digest</description><spices>Fresh snipped chives</spices><source>Reader's Digest</source><rating>Not hot at all</rating><ingredients>1lb(500g) cherry tomatoes
1 tbsp (15ml) olive oil
4 veal escalopes
2oz (60g) butter
2 tbsp (25ml) balsamic vinegar
2 tbsp(25ml) snipped fresh chives</ingredients><directions>Preheat oven to 350F(180C). Toss tomatoes in oil then place in a roasting pan and bake for 12-15minutes
Meanwhile, lay out veal pieces between two sheets of plastic wrap. Using a meat mallet or heavyrolling pin, pound veal to flatten it
Heat butter in frying pan until it starts to foam, add veal for 2 minutes on each side, or until tender. Remove from the pan and set aside in a  warm place
Pour balsamic vinegar into the pan with buttery juices. Stir, then bring to boil. Cook sauve over a high heat for 5minutes, or until sauce has reduced by half.
Return veal to the pan briefly to reheat, then sprinkle with chives before serving with cherry tomatoes</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Spicy Chicken Curry</name><contributor>Charles Elliott</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>A family favourite spicy chicken curry recipe passed down to my mother.</description><spices>Chili pepper</spices><source>Grandma</source><rating>Spicy</rating><ingredients>2 chili peppers
2 onions
3 cloves of garlic
1 tbsp of grated ginger
2 fresh tomatoes (chopped)
Chicken (breasts, thights, legs)
Fresh coriander leaves, chopped (as much as you like)
1 tbsp garam marsala
1 tbsp cumin powder
1 tbsp coriander powder
1 tbsp of tumeric powder
1/2 tsp hot chili powder
Cubed potatoes (optional)
Broccoli flowrets (optional)
1 can of coconut milk (add a second if more needed)</ingredients><directions>In a large pot add 3 tbsp of vegetable oil. Add chili peppers, onions, garlic, ginger and saute until onion is transparent. Add garam marsala, cumin, coriander, tumeric and hot chili powder. Add chopped tomatoes, chicken, and coriander and toss chicken until completely coated. Add potatoes and coconut milk. Stir well and cook covered at medium-low until potatoes and chicken and cooked. At this point you can add broccoli if desired and cook covered for a few minutes longer. NOTE: Do not let coconut milk boil as it will curdle. Makes 6 servings.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Spice-Rubbed Pork Chops</name><contributor>Colin Prime</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Big, meaty chops pair well with full-flavored ingredients. This lime and chili powder marinade is just the ticket. Add more or less of the hot pepper sauce to suit your taste.</description><spices>Hot Pepper Sauce</spices><source>Low-carb Cookbook</source><rating>HOT</rating><ingredients>4 boneless pork lion chops, cut 1/2 inch thick

1/4 cup lime juice


2 tablespoons chili powder

1 tablespoon olive oil

1 and 1/2 teaspoons ground cumin

1 and 1/2 teaspoons ground cinnamon

1/2 teaspoon bottled hot pepper sauce

1/2 teaspoon salt

1 clove garlic, minced</ingredients><directions>Trim fat from chops. Place chops in a plastic bag set in a shallow dish. For the marinade, in a small bowl stir together the lime juice, chili powder, olive oil, cumin, cinnamon, hot pepper sauce, salt, and garlic. Pour over chops; seal bag. Marinate in the refrigerator for 4 to 24 hours, turning bag occasionally. Drain chops, discarding marinade. Preheat broiler. Place chops on the unheated rack of a broiler pan. Broil 3 to 4 inhces from the heat for 6 to 8 minutes or until done (160 degrees Fahrenheit) and juices run clear, turning once halfway through broiling. Makes 4 servings.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Spicy Quesadillas</name><contributor>Sebastian Podlesny</contributor><category>Snack</category><description>This is an easy to make recipe that can be altered according to available ingredients and preferences</description><spices>Jalapenos</spices><source>Home Recipe</source><rating>Spicy</rating><ingredients>4 Thin Pitas
Cheddar or Mozzarella cheese
One Green Pepper
One Red Pepper
One Tomato
One Large Onion
One Jalapeno
Olive Oil
Ham, Chicken, or Sausage</ingredients><directions>Dice up the Green Pepper, Red Pepper, Tomato, and Onion. The meat can be cut into small or large pieces. Grate as much cheese as you would like inside the quesadilla and mix it with the vegetables. Spread the vegetables and cheese over one of the pitas. Add the meat on top of it. Place another top of this. Fry the pita on both sides until the cheese is melted in a pan with olive oil.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Lemon Herb Chicken</name><contributor>Nisrin Abou-Seido</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>This is a simple, quick and delicious dish. All you need are a few spices and, of course, the chicken! The amount of spices are completely up to you. You can add more or less according to your taste. Enjoy!"</description><spices>oregano
black pepper</spices><source>Family recipe</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>2 skinless, boneless chicken breast halves
1 lemon
salt and pepper to taste
1 tablespoon olive oil
1 pinch dried oregano
2 sprigs fresh parsley, for garnish</ingredients><directions>Cut lemon in half, and squeeze juice from 1/2 lemon on chicken. Season with salt to taste. Let sit while you heat oil in a small skillet over medium low heat. When oil is hot, put chicken in skillet. As you saute chicken, add juice from other 1/2 lemon, pepper to taste, and oregano. Saute for 5 to 10 minutes each side, or until juices run clear. Serve with parsley for garnish.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Homestyle Curry Chicken</name><contributor>Tomasz Ogrodzinski</contributor><category>Main Course</category><description>Diced chiken cooked with onions in a thick curry sauce. My family started making this as an imitation of an Indian dish we ate at a restaurant in North Bethesda (suburbs of Washington D.C.). Over time it evolved and became a dish of its own.</description><spices>curry powder
onion powder
garlic powder
thyme leaves (dried)</spices><source>Family recipe based on dish in Indian restaurant.</source><rating>Mild</rating><ingredients>2 chicken breasts, ketchup, all the spices listed in the spices section.</ingredients><directions>Dice chicken breast into pieces approximately 3x3x2cm (this is not very important, just make the pieces sensible). Slice an onion into half circles. Warm a tad of oil up on a pan (medium-high heat). When onions become glossy, add the chicken. Stir occasionally until chicken is completely white and doesn't show through any raw meat. Add some ketchup, curry, and all the other spices. (Use your good judgement. The sauce should be fairly thick, and have a golden orange color.) Cook for 15 more minutes. Serve with rice.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Chocolate Lushus</name><contributor>Andrew Bown</contributor><category>Dessert</category><description>A family dessert recipe with a chocolate crust and a pudding like under layer.</description><spices>N/A</spices><source>Family Recipe</source><rating>Woo!</rating><ingredients>1 cup flour, 1/2 teaspoon salt, 2 teaspoon baking powder, 3/4 cup white suger, 6 tablespoon cocoa powder, 2 tablespoon oil, 1 teaspoon vanilla, 1/2 cup milk, 1/2 cup chopped walnuts, 1 packed cup brown sugar, 2 cup hot water</ingredients><directions>In a medium bowl sift together the flour, salt, baking powder, white suger and 2 tablespoon cocoa powder. Add the oil, vanilla, milk, walnuts and blend well. After well blended poor into a 8"x8"x2" pan. In the same bowl add the brown sugar, hot water and 4 tablespoons of cocoa powder. Mix well and pour over batter. Bake at 350' for 45 min.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Lamb and Okra Stew</name><contributor>Daniel Sont</contributor><category>Main course</category><description>Old Middle Eastern family recipe, one of my favorites. A mildly spiced lamb stew is served over rice pilaf in this homey main dish</description><spices>cumin, fresh mint, dried turmeric, fresh rosemary</spices><source>allrecipies.com</source><rating>average</rating><ingredients>2 tablespoons extra-virgin olive oil
1/4 cup crushed garlic
2 pounds cubed leg of lamb meat
1 teaspoon ground cumin
1 teaspoon chopped fresh mint
1 teaspoon ground dried turmeric
1 teaspoon chopped fresh rosemary
2 (14.5 ounce) cans diced tomatoes, drained
2 tablespoons tomato paste
1 pound baby okra
1 teaspoon lemon juice
1 cup water
1 tablespoon butter
1 cup thin egg noodles
2 cups long grain rice
2 cups chicken broth
2 cups water
1 pinch salt and pepper to taste
1 teaspoon olive oil</ingredients><directions>1. Heat olive oil in a large skillet over medium heat. Add the garlic, and cook until transparent. Add the cubed lamb, and cook until browned on all sides. Season with cumin, mint, turmeric and rosemary. Cook for another 5 minutes. Add the diced tomatoes, tomato paste and okra. Combine the lemon juice and water, and stir into the skillet. Cover, and simmer over low heat for 45 minutes.
2. Meanwhile, melt the butter in a saucepan over medium heat. Add the egg noodles, and saute until toasted. Pour in the chicken broth and water, and bring to a boil. Stir in rice, cover and simmer over low heat until the rice is tender, about 15 minutes. Season with salt and pepper and stir in olive oil before serving. Serve the lamb stew over the rice pilaf.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Meat with potato</name><contributor>Yermek Sakiyev</contributor><category>none</category><description>Generally speaking, it is potatoe cooked in the frying pan. It's half cooked and half fried. :)</description><spices>ragu sauce, pepper</spices><source>none</source><rating>2</rating><ingredients>1 lb cut beef, 1 onion, 10 potatoes, 2 carrots</ingredients><directions>Firstly, we start cooking beef pieces until they are ready, then we put onion and carrot pieces to the pan. Then wait till the onion will get golden color, add some ragu sauce and mix them all. We will get orange stuff. Finally we put potatoes into the pan, add some salt, and mixe everything. Put on the cover and wait about 15 mins for it to be cooked. There is not much to do, but believe me this is my favourite cooking recipe;</directions></recipe><recipe><name>All Dressed Chocolate Chip Cookies</name><contributor>Scott Bennett</contributor><category>Snack</category><description>Traditional chocolate chip cookies with a bit of a twist. Experiment with other flavours of chips!</description><spices>All Dressed Chips</spices><source>Average recipe book with some creativity</source><rating>Weak to Mild</rating><ingredients>1/4 cup sugar
1 cup of semi-sweet chocolate chips
1/2 cup brown sugar, firmly packed
1/2 cup shortening
1 teaspoon vanilla
1 egg, well beaten
1 cup sifted flour
1/2 teaspoon baking soda
1/2 teaspoon salt
1 cup of smashed All Dressed Chips</ingredients><directions>Mix sugars, shortening, and vanilla together.
Add egg and beat mixture.
Sift dry ingredients together and add to mixture.
Stir in 1 cup of semi-sweet chocolate chips.
Mix in 1 cup of smashed All Dressed chips. Drop onto ungreased baking sheet.
Bake at 375F for 8-10 minutes.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Chocolate Lushus</name><contributor>Andrew Bown</contributor><category>Dessert</category><description>A family dessert recipe with a chocolate crust and a pudding like under layer.</description><spices>N/A</spices><source>Family Recipe</source><rating>Woo!</rating><ingredients>1 cup flour, 1/2 teaspoon salt, 2 teaspoon baking powder, 3/4 cup white suger, 6 tablespoon cocoa powder, 2 tablespoon oil, 1 teaspoon vanilla, 1/2 cup milk, 1/2 cup chopped walnuts, 1 packed cup brown sugar, 2 cup hot water</ingredients><directions>In a medium bowl sift together the flour, salt, baking powder, white suger and 2 tablespoon cocoa powder. Add the oil, vanilla, milk, walnuts and blend well. After well blended poor into a 8"x8"x2" pan. In the same bowl add the brown sugar, hot water and 4 tablespoons of cocoa powder. Mix well and pour over batter. Bake at 350' for 45 min.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Tuna Casarole</name><contributor>Daddy</contributor><category>null</category><description>My Father's Best Recipe</description><spices>None</spices><source>null</source><rating>Not Spicy</rating><ingredients>1 Can Cream Of Mushroom Soup
1/2 Cup Milk
1 Can Tuna
1 Cup Peas
1 1/4 Cup Crushed Potato Chips</ingredients><directions>Blend Milk and Soup; Stir in Tuna, Peas and Chips.
Bake in 350-375 degree Fahrenheit oven for 25 minutes
Serves 3 or 4</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Milk Pancakes</name><contributor>Grandma</contributor><category>null</category><description>Basic but delicious milk pancakes</description><spices>None</spices><source>null</source><rating>Not Spicy</rating><ingredients>1 cup flour
1 tsp white sugar
1 tsp baking powder
1/2 tsp salt
1 1/2 cup milk</ingredients><directions>Mix all together and fry in very hot pan</directions></recipe><recipe><name>7 Layer Dinner</name><contributor>Mommy</contributor><category>null</category><description>Large Dinner, feeds 4</description><spices>None</spices><source>null</source><rating>Not Spicy</rating><ingredients>See Directions</ingredients><directions>Into a 9" casserole dish, put 1" of raw potatoes, sliced thin, a layer of sliced onions, a layer of sliced carrots. Sprinkle on 1/4 c. minute rice, 1 tin of peas and juice, a layer of pork sausage.
Pour over all 1 tin tomatoe soup which has been dilluted with 1 tin water.
Bake in moderate oven for about 2 hours.
Bake with lid on for first hour.</directions></recipe><recipe><name>Raisin Spiced Muffins</name><contributor>Grandma</contributor><category>null</category><description>Delicious muffins
Makes 24 small muffins or 14 large ones</description><spices>None</spices><source>null</source><rating>Not Spicy</rating><ingredients>1/4 c. shortening
3/4 c. white sugar
1 beaten egg
1/2 c. of water from the boiled raisins
1 c. raisins
1 1/2 c. flour
1 tsp baking soda
1/2 tsp cloves
1/2 tsp cinnamon
1/2 tsp salt</ingredients><directions>Wash 1 c. raisins + boil them in a cup or so of water until you have about 1/2 cup of water left.
Sift the shortening, white sugar, egg, water and raisins.
Add flour, baking soda, cloves, cinnamon and salt.
Grease muffin tins + brown until delicately brown.
Bake at 350 degree Fahrenheit for 20 min.</directions></recipe></recipes>